♪ ♪
Hey.
YAM YAM:
I said it 100,000 times.
If somebody has it,
it's Carolyn.
CAROLYN: Tribal Council
tonight was amazing.
People...
were shocked and said,
"Whoa, that's really good.
And that... Oh, my gosh."
I played an idol for Carson.
This isa hidden immunity idol.
Any votes cast
for Carson will not count.
CAROLYN: And Danny went home.
- Danny... the tribe has spoken.
- Hmm.
YAM YAM: Love you, Danny.
CAROLYN:
Got to whip an idol out.
Nobody expected that, no one.
Like, "Carolyn did that?"
CAROLYN:
Even though, technically,
I didn't need to play my idol,
I still don't regret playing it.
I assured that me and Carson
and Yam Yam are still together,
and that's what we needed.
That was the most important.
YAM YAM: Girl!
- Yes.
- So the red... I'm the bandit.
[Carson gasps] - CAROLYN:
And so, what happened...
- HEIDI: [laughs] Carolyn.
- LAUREN: Oh, yeah, tell us.
CAROLYN: I found it the
first day we did the search.
So what was that...
Like, day two or three?
So I grabbed it,
I put it in my pants,
and I just ran, and I went
to the shelter, and I, like...
For some reason, my brain said
like, "Just do something crazy."
- So I made a red X, so I got a...
- CARSON: I love that.
YAM YAM: I always knew
that Carolyn is super intelligent.
I always knew that Carolyn is
a greatSurvivor player.
But she let now everybody know
she's good.
CAROLYN: The fake idol?
I thought Yam Yam found it,
so if you didn't find it,
it was Sarah.
- CAROLYN: Yes.
- Yeah.
YAM YAM:
It's like, "Girl, shut up."
Your target keeps getting bigger
and bigger.
All your craziness
is not craziness anymore.
And I'm personally
a little afraid of her.
But none of it makes sense.
It might be, like, cute.
CAROLYN: It doesn't, though.
Like... It did get...
- JAIME: So she thinks that she walked out...
- No, it's not.
Don't think I'm, like, some,
like, good player now because
- I did a stupid... No.
- JAIME: But do you think that...
JAIME: I think Carolyn
is an example of...
don't judge a book by its cover.
She may lead with emotions
and distract with emotions,
but it's very calculated,
and that's how you know
she's a good game player.
[snoring]
CARSON: I wake up this
morning, and Heidi is kind of stirring.
She's checking the light
to make sure
that it's bright enough to see,
and then,
she slowly gets up
and walks around and acts
like she's gonna
go use the bathroom.
No, no, no, no.
She's looking for an idol.
Because Carolyn played an idol,
people assume
there's another idol out there.
I believe
there's an idol out there.
And so, I immediately run over
to Carolyn, and I'm like,
"Carolyn, Heidi's looking.
We've got to go."
Everyone knows
if they find an idol,
it could change
the entire course
of this game.
HEIDI:
I have an idol in my pocket,
and I have not shared that
with anybody.
But even with the idol, I don't
feel completely comfortable.
I'm the last Soka member
alive in this game,
and I think in everyone's mind,
Heidi's probably
the easy vote next.
So, imagine if I had two idols.
I could buy two Tribal Councils
back-to-back,
and then I could position myself
in the final four.
But everyone's looking because
this is a huge opportunity
if anybody can find it
this late in the game.
Got a lizard egg.
No idol.
Oh, Carolyn, you know what?
We saw something at the top
of this tree over here.
No, I'm not... Oh,
and you're telling me about it?
Yeah. I'm not gonna climb up
there and get it.
Are you luring me?
Is there a trap?
LAUREN: I have no idea
what game Carolyn is playing.
Like, I've never seen a player
like Carolyn before.
She's fooling all of us.
- Where?
- At this tree right here.
Carolyn does seem
like she doesn't know
what's going on,
or just, like, she plays
that role, like she's clueless.
But underneath it all,
she got some strategy going on.
CAROLYN: Girl.
Oh, hell... Lauren!
- [laughing]
- Laur... [laughs]
The coc... You want me
to get the coconut?
You could probably
get the coconut.
- You want the coconut?
- Yeah, go get it.
No!
She's so confusing,
but she's so lovable,
and it's just, like..
It's weird, man.
And it's-it's scaring me
a little bit.
It really is. [Laughs]
[Carolyn screams]
LAUREN: I'm down
for it just being s four.
- Yeah.
Who do y'all want to go next?
I think Carolyn.
- For real.
- Mm-hmm.
- LAUREN: She shouldn't have told us the story.
- CARSON: No.
LAUREN: She shouldn't have
told us the story.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, she shouldn't have told us that.
And she's gonna be pissed at me,
- but she's playing a great game.
- JAIME: Yeah.
Y'all, she probably got
something else up her sleeve,
- too.
- Mm-hmm.
I feel like Jaime and Lauren
are buying what I'm saying, but
in reality, I want to stay
with Carolyn and Yam Yam.
I think it's time
for a Ratu member to go now.
But in order
for Ratu to feel secure,
I need Yam Yam and I to pretend
that we are working
with Lauren and Jaime.
We allhave to do that, though.
Y'all are the ones.
She...
Okay, I will make sure...
Considering that Lauren
and Jaime and Yam Yam and I have
worked together
for the last two Tribals,
they feel very comfortable,
and that's great, but
they shouldn't because
one of them's going next.
Come on in!
Survivor44,
what do we have in store?
All right, you ready to get
to today's reward challenge?
- [all voicing assent]
- [cheering]
For today's challenge,
we're gonna randomly divide
into two teams of three.
One player will be strapped
inside a giant ball.
They will guide their two
blindfolded tribe members
as you push the ball
through a long, winding course
to a table maze
where the person,
still inside the ball,
will guide
the still-blindfolded
tribe members
as they race to finish the maze.
♪ ♪
First team
to finish wins reward.
- Want to know what you're playing for?
- ALL: Yes!
The winning three
will be taken to...
ALL: Sanctuary!
Where good things happen.
- Yes.
- PROBST: You will start
- with a relaxing foot massage.
- CAROLYN: Oh, my God.
- [gasps] - Oh.
- PROBST: While you're enjoying
your relaxing foot massage,
you'll have lunch.
- Sandwiches.
- Finally! - [laughter]
PROBST: Plus,
chocolate, cookies, fruit, -Oh!
Juice and iced tea.
- Oh! - YAM YAM: Oh, my God.
- PROBST: Losers...
Another afternoon
back at camp with rice.
- Worth playing for?
- [all voicing assent]
All right, we'll draw for teams.
We'll get started.
- Let's do this!
- HEIDI: Oh, my goodness.
♪ ♪ All right, we
have our two teams.
The caller for Purple is Jaime,
with Heidi and Carolyn pushing.
For Orange, the caller
is gonna be Carson,
with Yam Yam and Lauren pushing.
Big reward on the line.
Survivors ready?
- Get ready.
- You got it.
- Go!
- Go now! Fast, fast.
PROBST: Who's gonna
get through this first
to get the early lead?
It's Orange. Carson upside down,
and they're going
into the structure.
Yam Yam now getting run into
by the Purple ball.
Oh. Just crashed.
PROBST: Purple trying
to get around Orange,
but Orange is blocking.
That's how you do it.
Push more on your side.
Yam Yam...
Keep going.
PROBST: Yam Yam and Lauren now
getting some momentum.
Yup. Keep going. Keep going.
JAIME:
Now get behind it and push.
PROBST:
It's now Purple who's stopped.
- JAIME: Get behind it and push.
- CAROLYN: Up.
- Down.
- PROBST: Orange is really moving now.
- CAROLYN: Up. - CARSON: Okay, listen.
- JAIME: Straight away.
- CARSON: We got a little bit more.
- JAIME: Yup.
- Now comes straight.
- PROBST: Purple still
taking a long time to make
- any progress.
- JAIME: Up.
- PROBST: There you go.
- Ow!
Now straight. Right behind me.
- Keep pushing really fast, really fast.
- Are we on the mat now?
- Yeah, we're going onto the mat.
- LAUREN: Okay.
PROBST:
Orange now onto the main course.
- Lauren, go to... to my right.
- Yup.
- You're doing a good job here.
- PROBST: Orange in the lead.
Carson, Yam Yam and Lauren.
Straight.
Straight, straight, straight.
To the right, to the right.
To the right.
- JAIME: Keep going.
- [Carolyn screams]
- Carolyn, come towards my voice!
- I'm coming.
PROBST: Carolyn's not even
- on the ball right now.
- JAIME: To your left.
Your left, your left, your left.
- Do you see me?
- Your left, your left.
- [Carolyn screams]
- Yes.
Now straight.
You guys look straight.
- Y'all start pushing forward now. Go, go, go.
- LAUREN: Okay. Okay.
PROBST:
Orange extending their lead now.
Now keep going. Now push hard.
Now push hard, yes.
- Oh!
- Yes. We're through.
- We're through. We're through.
- Here comes purple.
Okay, yup.
Yeah, I'm almost there.
Orange is up
on their finish platform now.
They can start
working on that maze.
- Yam Yam, right here. Right here.
- All right, down.
Carson now has to figure out
how to tell Yam Yam
and Lauren how
to get to the table maze.
Yam Yam, stop. You see that?
Pull that...
- Yes, I got it.
- LAUREN: Okay.
Yam Yam has one handle,
Lauren has the other.
Orange is now working that maze.
Carson in charge.
Yup. One more.
Up a little bit more. Okay.
Go around the box, Heidi,
and then get around, and
- pull me, Heidi. Now pull me towards that maze.
- Pull you?
- Yes.
- [Carolyn screams]
Once again,
a picture says a thousand words.
Can we get past this box?
PROBST: Purple stuck again.
JAIME:
Yes, you got it. You got it.
Ow!
Now. Lauren, hold up.
Lauren, hold up. Yes.
- Nice. Okay...
- PROBST: Orange making
- a lot of progress on the maze.
- CAROLYN: Ow!
PROBST: Purple cannot
get up on that platform.
Yeah, push, Carolyn.
Good. Heidi, pull!
- Perfect.
- PROBST: Huge time advantage for Orange,
and they are taking advantage
of it, moving very slowly
- through this maze...
- Now you can
- hold yours up.
- One move at a time.
- All the way up. All the way up.
- There you go, Purple.
- Now Purple's on the finish platform.
- JAIME: Yes.
Walk down right there.
Step, step.
[shrieks] - Now, come
to your left, Carolyn.
Pull down a little bit more. All
right, Yam, Lauren, up, up, up.
- All right.
- JAIME: Okay, feel that.
Carolyn has a handle.
Now Purple's on the maze.
Can they make up the time?
Lauren, up now.
Yes. Now. Okay. Perfect.
There's the move
Orange is looking for.
They are very close. Orange is
now within striking distance.
They don't want to blow it.
- Now, Heidi down and Carolyn down.
- Purple trying to catch.
- Yup. Go.
- PROBST: It might be too little, too late.
- Down more. Go down.
- PROBST: Orange could win it right here.
Um, go down more, really...
- Yes, you got it. You got it.
- And they did it!
- Oh, my God!
- No way.
Yam Yam, Lauren and Carson
win reward.
- Oh, I got take this thing off! I can't see!
- PROBST: An afternoon
- at the sanctuary.
- Oh, my gosh!
Great leadership by Carson.
- Get him out of there.
- [laughing]
- Buddy!
- How do we get him out of here? Oh, no.
Let's pull him straight.
All right, Carson,
Lauren, Yam Yam,
head out, enjoy your afternoon
at the sanctuary.
- Yam Yam, you're gonna eat.
- CAROLYN: You deserve it.
First time that I have a reward.
I only got two bananas from you
from that small basket.
That's the only thing
I've eaten.
Go enjoy. Well earned.
- Straight down here.
- Bye, y'all. - JAIME: Love you.
Love you guys. We'll eat it all.
- Jeff, I'm gonna eat!
- You're gonna eat, Yam Yam.
All right, Jaime, Carolyn,
Heidi, got nothing for you.
- Grab your stuff, head back to camp.
- JAIME: Thank you.
- CAROLYN: Thank you.
- Thank you.
JAIME:
We are outnumbered by Tika.
They are super close, so this is
a huge opportunity
for me to talk to Carolyn
and Heidi
and convince them
to break up Tika.
♪ ♪
Hello.
ALL: Bula! Welcome to sanctuary,
where good things happen.
Oh, my God. Thank you.
YAM YAM: Oh, my God.
My first reward in 22 days.
"Bula! Welcome to sanctuary,
where all good things happen."
I'm like, "Thank God! Give me
a hug! I feel like I'm home!"
- Oh, my God.
- [Carson gasps] - Oh!
YAM YAM: Oh, my God,
with, like, this plate of food
with sandwiches. Like,
these macaroons were, like,
recently made. They're so fresh,
so crisp, so full of air.
[imitates munching]
Mmm, mmm.
I'm so happy for you.
YAM YAM: I have not eaten here,
except freaking coconut,
papayas and snails.
I'm happy I won this reward.
This is the reward
I needed to win.
This is what my husband and I do
when we go on vacation.
We get massage.
- Mmm.
- The first thing we do the first day and the last one.
I can't remember
the last time I got a massage.
Hello.
- Bula.
LAUREN: As a single mom,
I don't have time
to pamper myself
or to go to a spa.
So, like,
I was so thankful just for
those women
taking their time out
to come, like,
give us a massage and just
for us to relax
and be in the moment.
It was just
a beautiful experience.
I keep focusing on the massage
and the waves and then...
LAUREN: Mm-hmm.
Yeah. What are you thinking?
Just, like,
Carolyn playing that idol.
Yeah.
- Her threat level went up.
- Yeah.
- Like, big time.
Carolyn is, like, a huge threat.
- And she's playing a lot harder than everyone notices.
- Yeah.
CARSON: So, like, my ideal
is Carolyn next. It is what it is.
At this point,
my goal is to make Lauren feel
as comfortable as possible
because I want Lauren to think
that I'm working with her 100%
when in reality, I'm not.
- I'm down with it.
- Me too.
YAM YAM: The fact
that Carolyn is a big threat
makes me very nervous.
We've been together the longest
out of anybody in this game.
And I love Carolyn, like,
with all my heart.
But now that we're only six,
you start, like,
thinking of how you can get
to the end,
and my gut tells me
it might be time
to vote Carolyn out.
I'm down.
♪ ♪
- CAROLYN: We're dragging.
- HEIDI: I know.
JAIME: The three losers...
We're coming back to camp, and
I'm thinking,
"There's only six people."
Tika... they're a threat
because they're three strong.
So, we have to break that up.
HEIDI: Only three of us.
This is what
it will feel like at the end.
JAIME: With Carolyn
here, it's perfect timing
to make that happen.
I think the three of us
should be thinking
about one of them.
Who are the biggest threats
left, what would you guys say?
- JAIME: Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, I think...
- CAROLYN: For sure.
- If we want to hand him
a million dollars, then take him
- to the finals, period.
- HEIDI: Exactly. - CAROLYN: Yeah.
I know, Like, I love him.
HEIDI: Yeah.
JAIME: I am focused
on causing rifts in Tika.
That would be a huge feat
on my part to direct this game
in that manner.
I mean, that's literally...
Like, I'm not okay
with him winning, so my vote...
That's where my vote's going.
CAROLYN: Jaime started
talking about Carson,
and "we got to get Carson out."
And I do believe
that Carson is this big threat.
But I can't lose Carson yet.
I may be emotional,
but I'm not, like, dumb.
I still need my numbers.
I don't want
Lauren, Heidi
and Jaime to team up.
I know that Carson can't go to
the end with me, but we need him
for at least one more vote.
Oh, I hate saying that!
That's my baby.
I don't either. I'd rather
be you, Yam Yam and I.
- Me too.
- 'Cause I don't...
- I cannot trust Lauren and Jaime.
- Mm-hmm.
HEIDI: I lost my biggest ally,
Danny, but I'm still here, and
there's a couple of plans
out there.
For me, myself,
I think the final three should
probably be
Yam Yam, Carolyn and I.
But I don't trust anybody
right now.
Luckily, I have something
that could help me,
and that something's
an idol in my pocket.
I-I... That's my worry.
But I'm trying
to think logically,
but I do think that...
- Ah! Welcome!
- CARSON: Did you all
- get some rice in your bellies?
- Not yet.
Look at how beautiful
you all look.
Girl, we smell amazing.
Can you burp in my mouth?
In my nose?
- [Yam Yam burps] - Oh.
- [laughter]
YAM YAM: We walk into
camp, and Carolyn wants
to smell my burps
so she knew how the food smell.
That's out there,
that's a first.
I wanted to smell chocolate!
[burps]
She enjoyed that.
I felt kind of gross
after that, to be honest.
But he smelled good.
His beard, everything.
It's torturous.
Look, Jaime's been pitching you
all afternoon.
- Really?
- And obviously, everybody's like...
And I've just been saying,
"Oh, yeah,
it makes sense. It makes sense."
CARSON:
They're trying to split us up.
- Me, Yam Yam and you.
- Yeah.
- They know that we're the power three right now.
- Yup.
CARSON: So hearing from Carolyn
that my name is out there
is scary, but I know that Lauren
and Jaime are just trying
to split
the Tika Three up, and I'm like,
"It's very obvious
what you're doing."
So, it really comes down
to next vote. I... I...
CARSON: Luckily, right now,
Tikas remain strong,
and somehow,
we were able to masterfully
get to this point where
we are finally in the majority.
And so, now,
we can run this game.
Yes.
Right.
- Yes.
- And her crazy thing?
It is crazy, and I'm crazy, too.
- We're all a little crazy.
- Mm-hmm.
- But it works for her.
- Yes.
I am very surprised
that Yam Yam wants
to vote Carolyn out because
I'm looking at Carson as
my number one threat right now.
However,
I am going with the flow.
He wants to get Carolyn out
and paint the picture
of the target on her back?
Absolutely, yes, let's do it.
As long
as a Tika member goes home.
So you want
to get Carolyn, then?
That works for me.
- Mm-hmm.
- So the same plan as this morning, then?
I knew you guys were in
'cause I know
when you guys are lying to me.
Yeah.
And you know what?
I don't think...
- I haven't lied to you this whole time.
- Mm-hmm.
I really haven't. I never
wrote your name down, either.
I talked to Jaime about
how big of a target Carolyn is.
She definitely agrees with me.
So it might be time
that the Tika Three break up.
It's very hard, but
I need to disconnect from them.
[laughs] I'd be...
When I got here
to Fiji,
I was just excited to play,
to live my dream.
But right now, it's not about
me being happy
that I'm here playing.
It's about me winning now.
I want to win.
If you think you have what
it takes to live in a jungle,
compete in challenges
and vote each other out,
apply to be on Survivor.
Come on in!
That is a beautiful sight.
Six people still in this game.
[laughs]
All right.
Shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- [all voicing assent]
- All right, first things first.
- Yam Yam, got to take it back.
- Oh, Jeff.
It's like taking an arm off.
[laughing]
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
very simple.
You're gonna use two ropes
to balance a ball on a disc.
At regular intervals,
you will move farther back,
making it more difficult.
If at any point
your ball drops...
you're out.
Last person left standing
wins immunity, guaranteed a spot
- in the final five.
- LAUREN: Wow.
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- [cheering]
Losers, Tribal Council,
where somebody will be
- the 13th person voted out, become.
- Thirteen.
The sixth member of our jury.
- Shall we draw for spots?
- Yes. - YAM YAM: Yeah.
Let's do it.
All right, everybody looks good.
And this challenge...
is on.
You'll be in this section...
for five minutes.
Two ropes, one ball, one disc.
Little bit of movement
by Lauren. Nice recovery.
You want tiny movements.
Jaime drops.
Jaime's first out
of this challenge.
No shot at immunity.
- Ugh!
- Carolyn drops
right behind Jaime.
We are down to four.
Still have three minutes left
in this section.
Carson, little bit of movement
and a nice save.
Can he do it again?
No. Carson is out.
We're down to three,
just like that.
Wow.
Fatigue of 23 days is showing.
We're down to Lauren,
Heidi and Yam Yam.
Lauren,
another little adjustment.
When you're dealing
with a ball on a disc,
it is all about touch.
Sometimes,
you need a light touch,
sometimes, more firm.
Yam Yam has no touch at all.
Yam Yam's out,
and we're down to two.
Lauren and Heidi
fighting for immunity.
You walk out of here
with this necklace,
you will make the final five.
You will be safe tonight
at Tribal.
PROBST:
Ten seconds left in this round.
Five, four,
three, two, one.
You're both good.
You can let your ball drop.
- You're moving on. Nice job.
- Good job, Heidi.
- You, too.
- PROBST: All right, let's reset,
and we'll continue on.
♪ ♪
We are reset now
in the second section.
This challenge is back on.
Only two remain:
Lauren and Heidi.
That is how you do it.
Rock steady.
You never know
when it's your name
that's being tossed around.
This is how
you stop that conversation.
By walking back to camp
with that necklace.
You have the jewelry. Find some
other fool. It's not me tonight.
Little bit of movement
by Lauren.
Wow. Nice.
Lauren, another nice save.
Keep staying engaged.
Do not drift.
Heidi with a nice save.
- Ugh!
- Heidi cannot recover.
- It's over. Lauren wins.
- [Lauren yells]
individual immunity.
Safe tonight at Tribal Council.
Cannot be voted out
- of this game. Nice job.
- CARSON: Good job, Lauren.
JAIME: Amazing, Lauren.
Ugh.
Good job, ladies.
Good job. Can we do it again?
[laughing]
Lauren, come on over.
- YAM YAM: Good job, Lauren.
- For the second time
this season,
individual immunity is yours.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
PROBST: As for the rest of you,
Tribal Council tonight,
13th person
voted out, become
the sixth member of our jury.
- You know what?
- What?
- PROBST: It won't be you.
- Yeah.
- Congrats.
All right. Head back to camp.
See you tonight at Tribal.
Thank you.
This is my second immunity win.
I am guaranteed a spot
in the final five,
which is amazing.
So, heading back to camp,
I am thinking
about what my next move is so I
can make it to the final three.
[hammering]
YAM YAM: We have this
long afternoon of deciding
what we're gonna
do tonight at Tribal,
but in my mind,
Carolyn is the biggest threat.
I just have to cement that plan.
But nobody's talking.
Everybody's sitting down
at camp, and nobody's moving.
Nobody wants to stand up
and go to the water well,
nobody wants
to go to the beach to wash up.
Do you forget
we have Tribal Council?
HEIDI: I'm gonna wash
off soon. I feel disgusting.
YAM YAM: We need to talk,
we need to talk about who's
gonna leave tonight.
Every...
I agree. Like, what the hell?
Mm-hmm.
And I believe... I-I mean, that.
HEIDI: If I go strong
with the Tika members...
Yam Yam, Carolyn,
Carson and I...
So four votes against Jaime...
I could possibly save my idol.
But everyone has lied
in this game to me
in some capacity.
So, do I trust what I've been
told or do I trust nobody
and just use my idol
to save myself tonight?
Hell yeah. We have to.
Yeah, so, wait. Okay...
I just told her. I said,
"What do you,
like, do you want to do Jaime?"
So, what's
your best, like, plan?
Or, like, what do you think?
HEIDI: Well, those girls
have written my name,
so I will be very happy
to write Jaime's name.
Okay, so all four of us
on Jaime.
Everyone cool with that?
- YAM YAM: Yes.
- CARSON: Okay.
- Lock it down. Okay.
- HEIDI: Yeah.
We're not worried about an idol?
Jaime doesn't have anything.
CAROLYN:
I can't trust Jaime and Lauren.
We need one of them gone.
Lauren won immunity.
So tonight, we're voting
for Jaime.
- This is real.
- For real.
CAROLYN:
I don't think Jaime has an idol,
but if she does have an idol,
I do think she's
comfortable enough right now
where she wouldn't play it.
JAIME: Is everyone in
agreement that Carolyn
is the absolute threat
right now?
I mean, my worry with her
is that I don't trust
that Carolyn's
gonna bring me to the end.
So I would vote Carolyn.
Let's see what
Yam Yam says right now.
- But that-that's my gut, too.
- Yeah.
JAIME: I don't have an idol
anymore, so
it is nerve-racking depending on.
Yam Yam and Carson
to be okay
with turning against Carolyn.
Carolyn is more dangerous
than Carson.
Yeah.
I'm down.
Right.
She's coming.
Uh-huh.
To Carolyn, this vote
will feel like a betrayal.
She's done it to me before,
I've done it to her,
but we've never done
it against each other.
- LAUREN: You okay?
- What happened?
People are obviously talking.
I don't know
what you guys are saying.
We all doing Heidi?
- Right.
- Yeah.
YAM YAM: This is the most
difficult vote for me tonight,
not only because
I'm drawing my path to the end,
but also because I might
have to betray my biggest ally.
You were, like,
honestly saying, like,
Carolyn, me and you at the end?
- I really was.
- Okay.
I mean, I-I could...
if you want to do something
different, I'm... I've...
- You've always been my number-number one, you know?
- Yeah. Same here.
CARSON: So, do you really
want to get Carolyn out?
I think Carolyn can win.
Okay.
And you don't think we can
get her out at five? Okay.
I don't think
we can take her out at five,
and I think she'll win
the fire-making.
She practiced fire
until she was bleeding.
Think about it.
CARSON: Yam Yam
wants to take out Carolyn.
I'm so surprised.
Are we going to target Carolyn?
I mean, Carolyn
has played a great game.
I've consistently
underestimated her,
and I think everyone else
has underestimated her, too.
Carolyn could win this game.
You have to trust your gut.
I don't know what
your gut is telling you.
My gut...
tells me Jaime,
but I want to do this together.
Okay.
But at the same time,
Carolyn's a loyal player,
and I like loyalty,
especially if it's to me.
We've been together
this whole game,
and so
it's a difficult decision.
Who do I take out at this point?
I'm not sure. It could be Jaime
or it could be Carolyn.
It's so difficult to navigate
this end portion of the game.
HEIDI: Could you take a look
and tell me if you think it's done?
- Yeah.
- HEIDI: Perfect.
♪ ♪
YAM YAM:
It's exciting to play this game.
It's exciting to live my dream.
But right now,
living my dream means...
...cutting the dream
of someone I love.
I got a lot of love for Carolyn,
the way we connected
at Tika the first few days.
I have a big conflict in my head
of getting rid
of Carolyn or Jaime.
The number one reason
to get rid of Jaime
is that throughout this game,
Jaime has cemented
a lot of relationships
and she's a big threat.
So it might be better just
to get rid of Jaime tonight.
But I know
I have a better chance
without Carolyn
at the final three.
I think out of everybody here,
the best game
is being played by Carolyn.
My brain is telling me
I need to take Carolyn out.
My heart
doesn't want me to do it.
So the question
for me tonight is
do I have the courage
to take Carolyn out?
Am I gonna be able...
strong enough to do this?
I don't know. I don't know.
I want this money and I want
this title, but it's hard.
It breaks my heart a little bit.
[breathes sharply]
It's so stupid
because it's a game,
but it's not a game, you know?
♪ ♪
PROBST:
All right, well, let's start
with what
I'm pretty sure is a first.
- It looks like you brought everything from camp.
- [laughs]
Yes. Jeff, we have our rice bag.
- [laughing]
- Machete, hammer, rope.
You brought the paintbrushes.
LAUREN: We got the paint.
We don't know
what to expect, you know,
whether we're
going back to our camp
or whether we're
going somewhere different.
So we just wanted
to be prepared.
JAIME: We're ready.
If we want
to see the rice tomorrow,
Lauren has to bring it
because she's the only person
that's gonna be here for sure.
And then I said, like,
maybe I should keep the rice
- as a hidden immunity idol.
- [laughing]
They won't vote me out
if I have the rice with me.
But she has it.
PROBST:
So, Carson, as Yam Yam said,
Lauren will be the only person
that we know
will be here tomorrow.
I say it over and over,
one immunity win,
on the right day,
can change the entire game.
Yeah. Especially when
there's only six people left,
and there's idols
potentially at play.
Who knows what could happen?
So it's amazing
to have an immunity necklace
around your neck, but that is
not the case for me tonight.
PROBST:
Jaime, Shot in the Dark is over.
Can't use that anymore,
but could be advantages
or idols in the game.
How much time is spent
discussing that?
JAIME: A big portion.
We've anticipated advantages
and prepared for that.
And that's all at play
in tonight's vote.
Jeff, there's not a conversation
that you don't talk about
the possibility
of an idol being played.
It's impossible not to think
of that, and it's very scary
that one person
can decide what happens,
and the vote of
five more people don't matter.
PROBST:
So, Jaime, give me the scales
from excitement to terrified.
You know, I think the scales
went up and down today
with everyone,
because all of our names
were out there today.
But we hear the quote,
"Be the change
you want to see in the world."
Tonight, we can make the moves
we want to see in the game.
It's about
jazzing up our résumés,
so got to do it.
PROBST: Yam Yam, is it
every player for themselves now,
or are there still groups that
are trying to work together?
YAM YAM: It might
appear that there's groups,
but that doesn't mean anything,
because you have
to be inside each head
to know what they're thinking
- the final Tribal Council is gonna look like.
- CAROLYN: Yeah.
I don't have that superpower.
That's a superpower
I would like to have.
It would be amazing
if I could read minds.
I can't, you know?
I don't know what
you're thinking right now.
[laughing]
How about you, Carson?
CARSON:
I feel like, at this point,
we are, in some ways,
working together
and then sometimes
it is a little bit more jumbled.
Sometimes you're
working with a group,
and then the day of Tribal,
they break up, and
that could be the case tonight.
Yam Yam, big words, "break up."
It's a huge word.
And especially at this point
that we're gonna
be coming down to five.
It's a concept we have
to grasp and think about.
It's really emotional
'cause we're not talking
about a stranger right now.
It's 23 days living together
that it's hard
to say, "I know
that's the right decision.
Here. Maybe not here."
If I was on the other side
of the TV on my couch,
I would be
screaming at me and say,
"That's what you have to do!"
But I'm here. I'm not at
the other side of the couch.
The reality is,
it's one of them or me.
And it can't be me,
you know, or Lauren.
[laughing]
PROBST: Carolyn, how about for
you? How much of this is emotional
and how much
of it is pure strategy?
Here's how I think.
I think that
there's nothing wrong
with being an emotional player.
And I think that everybody here
can attest
to the fact that I have
been extremely emotional.
But it doesn't mean
that somebody can't be
strategic who's emotional.
I am both.
But I have promised myself...
I've promised my son...
That I'm not
gonna apologize for crying.
And when certain people
in this game lie to you,
it's a big blow. It hurts.
So I'm not gonna ever deny that.
It doesn't mean
I can't play this game.
Well said.
So tonight's vote, it sounds
like, will be emotional.
[sighs]
I'm scared. Is this, like,
my goodbye speech or something?
I can ask it to somebody else.
Oh, no, no!
I got-got nervous for a minute.
Um, but yes,
there's not many people left.
But this intimate group
and intimate setting,
we are all loving on each other,
and it's real.
So it's absolutely emotional.
PROBST How about you, Yam Yam?
How good do you feel
about the vote tonight?
- How do I feel about it?
- PROBST: Yeah.
♪ ♪
YAM YAM: Here's the thing.
I think the person
that's leaving tonight
is the person
that needs to leave.
For everybody's game.
And that's why
we're voting like that.
All right, it is time to vote.
Heidi, you're up.
♪ ♪
[exhales sharply]
I'll go tally the votes.
[mouths]
If anybody has an advantage or
an idol and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
- All right, I'll read the vo...
- HEIDI: Jeff.
I would like
to make it to five myself.
- So you're playing this for yourself?
- Yes, sir.
This is a hidden immunity idol.
- Ooh.
- PROBST: Any votes cast for Heidi will not count.
I'll read the votes.
First vote: Carolyn.
Jaime.
Carolyn.
Two votes Carolyn,
one vote Jaime.
Guys.
Jaime. We're tied.
Two votes Carolyn,
two votes Jaime.
Jaime. That's three votes Jaime,
two votes Carolyn.
Thirteenth person voted out
of Survivor44: Jaime.
Need to bring me your torch.
Nice move, you guys.
Love you all.
Jaime, the tribe has spoken.
Time for you to go.
Love you guys.
- Bye.
- Good job.
Love you, Jeff.
- Thanks, Jaime.
- [laughs]
Well, your assumptions
were correct.
Tonight,
you will be leaving Tribal,
taken to a new beach,
where you will start over.
Fortunately, you came prepared.
Nice job.
Grab your torches, head out.
Final push begins. Good luck.
Captioning sponsored by CBS.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
YAM YAM: We're so
happy to be in the final five.
This is the last leg
of the game.
PROBST:
Next time, on the season finale
- ofSurvivor...
- [yells]
CARSON: Everyone here
knows that I can beat them.
CAROLYN: I'm ready, and I
want to fight my way to the end.
HEIDI: I don't want second,
third or fourth. I want Sole Survivor.
LAUREN:
This is the difference between
winning
a million dollars or not.
Oh, my gosh. I'm so
grateful to make the top six.
This is a huge accomplishment.
Finding an idol,
that was one of my number one
goals, and I'm so grateful.
I am proud of myself
for overcoming so many fears.
I can do anything at this point.
And I had so much fun playing
my favorite game
in the entire world.
[roars]