♪ ♪
That was, uh...
that was a something.
KARLA:
At Tribal, we were
split into two groups of five,
and it was a double elimination.
At our Tribal Council,
James went home,
and I was
supposed to be out
of the loop of that vote.
OWEN:
I'm sorry I didn't tell you that
- we had this plan.
- NOELLE: Yeah.
- I wasn't sure...
- I mean, no. Sami talked to her
- right before we had left.
- Right.
- Yeah.
Karla had to be in on it.
OWEN: Yeah.
KARLA:
Sami told me,
very last-minute,
what the actual vote was,
and so, I voted the way
everyone wanted to vote.
But I guess I'm just frustrated
because it's the first time
people have planned
to leave me out of a vote.
KARLA: Hey, Cassidy? Okay.
SAMI:
Was it Ryan?
- It was Ryan.
- Yeah.
Wow.
CASSIDY:
Tonight at Tribal,
we sent Ryan packing.
It felt pretty good
for that to finally
come to fruition,
and it was even
made more sweeter by the fact
that he was trying
to blindside me again.
And yet, I got him.
And, um, he's-he's trying
to play the...
JESSE: I feel good not only
coming out of, like, you know,
my Tribal, but the outcome
of the other group's Tribal.
I feel good
about where things are.
Like, I know where all the
advantages are at this point.
Two of the idols
are with me, and
the fact that she was going
around looking for beads--
I know one idol is sitting
in Karla's bag,
even though
she doesn't want to tell me.
We all sort of know it's there.
I don't understand why.
He was in the majority. It's not
like he was on the bottom.
He's trying
to play every single angle.
Every single angle.
JESSE:
After those two Tribals,
I think there's a lot
of distrust between people, and
I'm sort of sitting in this
position again where, like,
me, Cody, and Gabler are sort
of, like, riding in the middle.
I have a really good
relationship with Noelle,
I have a really
good relationship with Owen,
and their sort of alliance that
they're trying to build, and
I also have
this really good relationship
with the other side,
you know, and
Karla and Cass, so, like,
I feel great about where I'm at.
Come on in!
♪ ♪
- Good morning, Jeff.
- PROBST: Good morning.
- Hi, Jeff.
- Good morning.
- Loving the black.
Loving the black.
[laughter]
Thanks, Karla.
Yeah.
All right, shall we get
to today's reward challenge?
[all voicing assent]
For today's challenge,
you're gonna spin
inside a metal frame,
slowly winding a buoy
toward you.
Once it crosses the line,
you're gonna race
through a series of obstacles
to collect a sandbag.
You will then race,
get that sandbag
to the top of a tall tower.
First person
to do so wins reward.
Want to know
what you're playing for?
[all voicing assent]
The winner
will leave here and go
directly to the sanctuary.
You'll enjoy pizza,
- Oh.
- Cheesecake,
- Oh!
- brownies.
- CODY: Oh, gosh.
- Plus beer,
- [gasps]
- Oh! [gasps]
- Hey!
- wine.
In addition, you will
spend the night at the sanctuary
- Ooh.
- and get a proper
night's sleep
- with pillows and blankets.
- Dude.
- Wow.
- God.
All right, we'll draw for spots.
We'll get started. Good luck.
All right, here we go.
For reward.
Survivors ready?
Go!
You're gonna spin yourself
inside that frame.
The faster you spin,
the faster you'll get your buoy
across this line.
And yes, you're getting dizzy
as you do it.
Oh, God.
PROBST:
Everybody's doing a nice job.
The more you wind, you're
pulling that buoy closer to you.
- [grunting]
- Here comes Owen.
There goes Cody.
Here goes Noelle.
You're good, Owen!
You're good, Noelle.
Now you're dizzy.
Now you got to get off.
[grunts]
You're good, Cody.
Karla, you're good.
Sami, you're good.
- [grunts]
- Noelle attacking that.
You're dizzy. It's hard to run.
You have no balance.
You're good, Jesse.
Oh, brah. [laughs]
Keep going, Cassidy.
You're good.
Jesse's struggling.
Can hardly walk.
There goes Cassidy.
Let's go, Gabler. Keep moving.
Now you got to get over that
beam while you're still dizzy.
Gabler, two more spins,
you got it. You're good, Gabler.
Everybody now working
on that balance beam.
Now you're starting
to get your sense back.
Now you've got to balance again
on a small beam
while you untie a sandbag.
It is Owen out first.
Owen drops. Got to go back now.
It's now Cody with his sandbag,
makes easy work of that.
Sami's got a comeback.
You're good, Cody.
Big reward
could change the entire game
for one player.
Noelle, got to go back.
Owen, no. Got to go back.
You've got to finish that beam.
Cassidy, you're good.
There goes Karla.
She has her bag.
You're good.
Noelle continues to work it.
There goes Owen.
There you go.
Here comes Jesse.
Sami working his.
Noelle gonna give it another go.
Sami's good.
PROBST:
You're good, Cassidy.
Cassidy is first through.
Then Karla.
You're good, Jesse.
Gabler's across.
Keep working, Noelle.
First one to land their bag
at the top wins reward.
- Oh.
- PROBST: The harder you work,
the luckier you get.
[groans]
Noelle, you are still
in this challenge.
Noelle has done an amazing job
for 18 days.
Just found a challenge that
has really proven difficult,
but she continues to fight.
[Noelle sniffles]
PROBST:
Cody, on and off.
♪ ♪
- Oh!
- Karla's on and off.
Noelle continuing to work,
work, work, digging.
[sniffling]
Can she get back in this?
Noelle--
an amazing effort by Noelle.
- Noelle now getting inventive.
- [pants]
She's still in it.
Everybody hustling
- on Day 18 of Survivor 43.
- Oh!
- Karla's on, then off again.
- CODY: Nice shot, Karla.
- PROBST:
Karla's been very close.
- [groans]
Noelle still working
that sandbag.
Do I hold the sandbag?
You got the bag.
Got to do the beam now.
Now you got to go back.
She has half of it.
- You got it, Noelle.
- OWEN: Let's go, Noelle.
Now she's just got
to get across the beam.
Cassidy is on. It won't stay.
Sami on and off again.
There goes Karla.
- Aah!
- PROBST: Once again it lands,
- but skips off.
- KARLA: Come on!
PROBST:
Noelle two thirds of the way
across that beam.
- Still fighting.
- KARLA: Come on, Noelle.
CODY:
Get it, girl! Come on, Noelle!
[gasps]
OWEN:
Stay on it, Noelle!
PROBST:
An amazing job by Noelle!
She's back in it.
- Untie those knots, Noelle.
Let's go!
- [overlapping chatter]
And look at that.
Noelle is in it.
Noelle with her first toss.
She could now win this, as well.
Noelle on and off.
Noelle now losing...
You're losing the leg?
PROBST:
Oh! On and off again for Owen.
♪ ♪
There's Sami in the air.
On and off! It won't stick!
The closest so far.
There's Noelle.
Noelle! In one
of the biggest comebacks
- in the history of Survivor...
- OWEN: Let's go, Noelle!
- [Noelle crying]
- Good job, Noelle.
- OWEN: Oh, my God.
PROBST:
...has just won the biggest
reward of the season.
That is what this game
is about right there.
I'm so proud of you.
That was amazing.
- Damn, yeah.
- Oh, my God.
PROBST:
You never, ever stop
on Survivor.
- OWEN: Oh, my God.
- CODY: Congratulations, girl.
- SAMI: Good job, champion.
PROBST:
I have seen a lot of things
in 43 seasons.
- That is up there at the top.
- OWEN: Oh, my God, girl.
- Unbelievable effort.
- My leg is literally off.
- OWEN: You're a warrior.
- CASSIDY: Good job.
You're an absolute monster.
- Oh, my God.
- Got it.
- GABLER: Great job.
- CODY: Yeah.
- OWEN: Go, Noelle.
CODY:
Yahoo!
- [whooping]
- Great job, guys.
All right, Noelle,
come over here.
- CODY: Yes!
- [overlapping chatter]
Keep it on.
PROBST:
Was there ever a moment
when you were on that beam
thinking, "I just
don't think I can do it"?
I was crying the entire time.
I mean, like, that's...
I didn't know I was gonna do it.
I was trying to hop it, but,
like, I go into every
single challenge thinking,
"I don't think I can do it."
But if it was me
with two legs up there,
and I wasn't succeeding,
I would have quit.
And so, everything that
I've learned since my accident--
I mean, it just motivates me.
PROBST:
All right, first of all,
you've just earned
an afternoon and an evening
at the sanctuary.
Tonight, you will also be
enjoying letters from home
- from your loved ones...
- CODY: Nice.
PROBST: ...to remind you
why you were out here.
Pizza, all the things
you want from home,
including love.
There are eight people in this
game, these are big decisions.
Choose one person
to join you at the sanctuary.
- Got to go with Sami.
- PROBST: Sami, come on over.
Thank you. [sniffles]
All right, Noelle, choose
one more person to join you.
NOELLE:
The second that
I came out on this beach,
this guy's talked about family,
and I got to choose Jesse.
- PROBST: Jesse, come on over.
- [applause]
All right, Noelle,
you have one last person.
I got to choose Owen.
- PROBST: Come on over, Owen.
- NOELLE: He hasn't had a meal.
- He hasn't.
- GABLER: I love it. Great job.
Great job. Great job.
Noelle, Sami, Jesse, Owen,
grab your stuff, head out.
Boat's waiting for you.
I love you guys. I'm so sorry.
Two beers for me, huh?
PROBST:
All right, Gabler,
Cody, Karla, Cassidy,
grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
- Got nothing for you.
- Thanks, Jeff.
NOELLE:
I was really doubting myself,
but I didn't want to give up
because I came out here wanting
to prove to myself
and to everybody else
that I can do these challenges,
and I did it.
There is nothing better
than this moment
that I can ever describe.
If you think you have what it
takes to come out here and play
this game, what are you waiting
on? Apply to be on Survivor.
NOELLE: Waking up this morning
at our shelter
compared to now,
like, I'm walking up
to this beautiful sanctuary
where we're gonna be finally
getting a great night's sleep.
It's just indescribable, and
it just shows you that, like,
in a blink of an eye, your life
can change in this game.
Cheers to you, Noelle.
That was incredible.
- Cheers to you guys.
- So badass.
That was
one of the coolest things
I've seen in my entire life.
NOELLE:
This whole day has already
been surreal and already
kind of been a blur, but
these are the types of days
that I'm incredibly grateful
for the experience
that I'm having out here.
OWEN:
This feast
is just what I needed.
But of course, the main event--
the letters from home.
Noelle-- woman of the hour.
They're just an opportunity
to pause and reflect
and just have a minute
to breathe because the speed
of the 26-day game has
been absolutely relentless.
Oh.
Opening the envelope--
it hit me like a freight train.
Getting a letter
from my girlfriend,
from my mom, from my dad.
Just seeing their handwriting,
hearing how they're doing,
hearing that
they're proud of me.
My girlfriend
Sammy believes
I can win an immunity necklace,
and I've done that,
and just, like,
to have the people
that are most important to me
in the whole wide world
be proud of me and be a part
of this experience
with me is just...
[sniffles]
It's-it's tremendous.
And I'm never
gonna forget that.
JESSE: I've been best friends
with my wife
since elementary school, and
the last time we had
to communicate by letters,
it was in such
a different situation.
I was locked up
in juvenile hall, and, like,
we had no idea
what the future held.
And now, we have a house,
we have these two kids,
we have this, like,
amazing life,
and, like,
it's hard to leave that behind.
I've never gone a day
in my adult life
without talking to her.
Any decision I make,
I've made with her.
And so, like, now I'm out here,
and I'm making
all these decisions by myself,
and I'm trying
to find my footing,
and I'm doubting myself.
I don't know
if I can do this.
Right? Like, I don't have,
like, my kids
to go cuddle with at night
when I'm feeling down or sad.
And, like, not having access
to that out here has been,
like, so hard.
And so, having those letters and
being able to see them, like,
cheer me on and a...
...and see them,
like, mention, like,
"You know, when you get home,
please sleep in my bed," right?
Like, it's amazing.
[crying]
It just fills me up.
It gives me that extra boost
to keep going.
- [laughter]
- Who said that? Y-Your brother?
- My dad.
- Your dad. Oh, that's hilarious.
My mom. "I always watch
the weather every day
praying for dry, calm seas
and comfortable temperatures."
OWEN:
I don't know
if I've ever seen my dad write,
"Love you," like,
in his handwriting before.
NOELLE:
Really?
JESSE:
"Dear Daddy, I miss you
and I love you.
I hope you're having an awesome
time. Get that money, baby."
[laughter]
-"Get that money, baby."
- OWEN: "Get that money, baby."
NOELLE:
That's amazing.
- Glad I got to share this
with you guys.
- SAMI: Me too.
- OWEN: Me too.
- I couldn't have picked
a better group of people.
- Yeah.
- OWEN: Yeah.
SAMI: I'm gonna tell you guys
right now.
I've been thinking
about the game
and everything like that.
I'm not breaking off.
- NOELLE: Yeah.
- I'm at the point where
I'm going next for Cassidy.
I want to get out Cassidy next.
- OWEN: Okay.
- Because I'm not flopping back.
NOELLE:
I knew moving forward
that Sami is a flipper.
You know, he has been
playing the middleman
and going back and forth.
So taking him, I feel like
was beneficial for my game
because I could keep him
comfortable so he doesn't keep
scrambling, and maybe this will
reassure him, "Oh, maybe
I do want to work with Noelle."
We can pitch
a three-three vote split
- on Cass and Karla.
- Yeah.
NOELLE:
Owen had the idea
of splitting votes
between Cass and Karla
just in case Karla has an idol.
I want
to start getting the biggest
strategic threats
out of this game.
So I'm just hoping
we can get one of those two,
and we will be golden.
Yeah, I feel like me, you,
- you, Cody, Gabler.
- NOELLE: Gabler.
That's a good five.
I'm just terrified the girls
are already saying my name.
Oh, I want some damn pizza.
- I wanted to win that so bad.
- I know.
Like, that'd be
so much more fun.
Those people at the reward--
they're gonna
go get a nice rest,
they're gonna get a bunch
of food, and they're gonna
have a much more
memorable time than us.
We're gonna
be out here miserable
and tired
and really not talk that much.
I don't know about you, but
when I go out for some cocktails
and some food,
I'm pretty chatty.
Wars, negotiations, sales
are all done
over breaking bread.
I haven't had much time
with the three of you
so it's kind of fun
to get to the opportunity
- to know each other, as well.
- GABLER: That's right.
- CASSIDY: Yeah.
- CODY: So, quick strategy talk.
Are you-are you
still skeptical of Sami?
Yeah, he's-he's
all over the place.
- GABLER: I know.
- CASSIDY: For me, personally,
I haven't built any trust
with Noelle or Owen.
I feel like
Owen is her new Dwight.
- KARLA: Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, that's what I'm thinking.
CASSIDY:
Yeah.
I know it seems like
it was a total loss
for the people who
didn't get the reward, but
to be honest, I'm a big believer
in a lot of the time when things
don't seem to go your way,
like, there is a silver lining
that you can find.
Oh, man,
this game's getting crazy.
It's gonna get crazier.
CASSIDY:
And so I think this is
the perfect time for me
to find out
where Cody head's at
because I do want
to have the numbers on my side
because I think that would be
really beneficial for my game.
I feel like it's time to start
actually, like, looking at
- getting out the big threats
in this game.
- Yeah.
Like, for example,
I think Noelle's a big threat.
I think she...
And she's gaining momentum
the longer she's here.
I feel like she's gonna
cook up some more stuff.
- Yeah.
- She's already made
a big move. Like, do we want
to even give her a chance
to make another big move
- and then, like,
build her résumé?
- No. Yeah.
CASSIDY: It absolutely
is getting harder and harder
to keep everyone in this group
on the same page.
There's so much shifting
in the game right now.
These rewards are big,
and that bonds people,
that bring them together.
So for me,
I'm just trying to make sure
that I can keep my allies
strong, keep us intact,
but I never really fully know
where Gabler's at,
to be honest with you.
And having him as a vote
is gonna be critical for me.
Who do you see yourself, like,
moving forward with on the game?
GABLER:
Well, yeah, we'll have to see
- who's gonna win tomorrow.
- Yeah.
- You know, if we could...
- How do you feel about,
like, Noelle and stuff?
I like her a lot, personally.
Obviously, she's...
I mean, she's like a hero
inside the game for me.
I've thought of that
from the beginning.
I've said that multiple times.
She's a big threat. I don't want
to go to the end next to her.
- And then we'll see who wins.
- CASSIDY: Yeah.
And then we can...
We'll have to make a decision.
- KARLA: Then we can talk.
- Cause then we're gonna have
- to make a decision.
- CASSIDY: But I would like...
- I would like to vote with you.
- Yes.
- Let's do that.
- If you're voting tomorrow.
- Okay.
- I would like to do that, too.
I positioned myself
in a nice spot.
Both sides are wanting me
to vote with them,
and neither side is talking
about voting for me.
So I think that's
a really good place to be.
I've got options,
and options are really big
in this game.
♪ ♪
Come on in.
- Good morning, Survivor 43.
- NOELLE: Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Jeff.
Eight players left.
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- Yes, sir.
- First things first.
Got to take back both necklaces.
- Ooh. You go first.
- You go first.
[laughter]
Thank you, Cody.
- Whoops. Thank you, Karla.
- Thank you.
Once again, individual immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
with one hand,
you're gonna steady
a balancing board
while simultaneously
building a house of cards
with the other hand.
The first player to build
a house of cards high enough
to reach the finish mark...
wins immunity,
guaranteed a spot
in the final seven.
Losers-- Tribal Council
where somebody will be
the eleventh person
voted out of this game
and become the fourth member
of the jury.
All right, we're gonna draw
for spots, we'll get started.
Here we go.
♪ ♪
Put your hand on your handle,
get a feel
of how that board works.
So you're going
to be transferring pieces
with one hand while trying
to keep it level with the other.
All right, Survivors ready?
Go.
This challenge is on.
It's a bit of a race,
but there's a massive
learning curve to this.
You're probably going
to drop your house of cards
at least once
as you start to figure out
where those balance points are
and how much flexibility
you have
with your arm and that rope.
Lots of different strategies
for how to build,
especially your base.
Noelle drops.
That's to be expected.
Karla dropped.
She's got to start again.
You're looking
to build a house of cards
high enough
to reach that red arrow.
A long way to go.
Ain't so easy.
Son of a gun.
15 minutes into this challenge.
[sighs]
It is now Cassidy and Owen
side by side,
Karla down at the end.
All three about the same height.
Everybody else starting over.
Owen loses everything.
Cassidy continues
to make good work of this.
She has found a momentum
and great balance
steadying that board.
Cassidy getting closer.
And Cassidy loses half of it.
That opens the door for Karla.
And Karla drops.
She's back to zero.
Now we've got everybody
starting over again, basically,
and this is wide open.
CODY [sighing]:
Aah. There.
PROBST:
Let it out. Exhale.
Get some new energy.
You got to keep your eyes
on the prize.
Prize is the necklace. The way
you get there-- slow and steady.
- Damn!
- No!
[groans]
You can't get frustrated.
You just have to start again
and keep building.
You start over
in this game all the time.
Damn!
PROBST:
It's the theme of Survivor.
Keep digging.
This is not easy,
but somebody will win.
Awesome.
28 minutes into this challenge.
Right now, just based on height,
it is Cassidy in the lead,
then Karla,
then Sami,
then Owen and Noelle.
Owen drops.
Cassidy getting close
to the top,
but she's been there before.
What has she learned
from past attempts
about building a structure
that's really stable?
Is that enough?
That is not gonna do it.
You're about an inch short.
Sami with another piece.
Karla down on the end,
inching near that finish line.
Karla and Cassidy almost
at the exact same point.
Cassidy has a really
interesting strategy.
She thought through this,
learned a lot.
She's stacking now so she can
just put one piece vertically
and see if that'll do it.
The issue is, can she do this
without faltering?
Karla getting closer.
She's one level away.
Sami's in it,
inching toward that finish mark.
Cassidy has a bit of a lead,
but you can't race.
You still have to be composed.
Noelle not messing around.
Karla close
to breaking that plane.
- [gasps]
- And loses everything!
One tile,
literally one tile away.
And it is now Cassidy,
Noelle and Sami's to win.
Sami trying to catch Cassidy,
but he's got to hope she drops.
Because Cassidy could win this
if she can get one
vertically from here.
That's it! Cassidy wins
- individual immunity.
- NOELLE: Wow.
PROBST:
Safe tonight.
Emotion starts to pour out
after 19 days.
Another new winner
of the necklace.
- What an effort
in that challenge.
- JESSE: Good job.
Great job.
Cassidy, come on over.
- Congrat...
- Oh, my gosh.
[laughter]
I'm shaking so hard.
All right, Cassidy,
you are safe in this game.
You are gonna
make it to the final seven.
That will not be the case
for all of the rest of you.
After 19 very tough days
out here,
somebody's dream
will end tonight.
Eleventh person voted out,
fourth member
of our jury.
It will not be you.
Congrats. Grab your stuff.
Head back to camp.
- See you tonight at Tribal.
- Thank you.
- SAMI: Good job, Cass.
CASSIDY:
To me, today was just proving
to myself that I am capable
of accomplishing
all of my dreams
and my goals in this game.
And now, the last thing that
I want to accomplish is winning.
And I really am starting
to see that I can do it,
and that's such
a fulfilling feeling for me.
CASSIDY: Oh!
Thank you.
- Good job.
- It feels so good.
I, like, dreamt about this
so many times.
NOELLE: Cassidy won
the challenge today, and
it puts a little bit of a hiccup
in our original plan because
we were gonna split the
numbers between her and Karla
just in case
Karla plays an idol.
But now I need
to come up with a new backup
before Karla
can get something going.
- NOELLE: Yeah?
- Yeah. Yeah.
What?
They're looking at me.
NOELLE:
Sami-- you know,
I can't trust the guy,
especially what happened
with last Tribal Council
with everything with James,
him telling Karla
ten minutes
before everything that happened.
But I gained a ton
of trust with Owen.
I have a great relationship and
alliance with Jesse and Cody,
and Gabler's
a straight-up guy, so,
I'm 95% confident
we can still vote out Karla.
- But Cass isn't gonna
trust me or you again.
- CODY: Yup.
- And then she'll have Cass.
- Yup.
Now we're...
Yesterday, I had, like,
a very emotional human moment
reading my letters
from home, and,
like, Noelle is the one
that gave me that moment.
So it makes it hard to think
about potentially
voting her out.
But reading those letters, now
I'm using that to motivate me
to make the best decisions
for me and my family back home.
So,
whatever I might want to do
emotionally out here, you know,
the emotional commitment I have
back home trumps all of that.
CODY:
She's good, dude.
JESSE:
Every time we box her in,
- she finds a way out.
- Yup, she finds a way out.
- She's picking up speed
for sure.
- We can't have it.
JESSE:
I see Noelle as one
of the best players out here.
Every time
I take out her number one,
she comes back
with another number one,
and she comes back stronger.
And we see it
in the challenges, right?
Like, she comes back from,
like, you know,
being at the very end and
winning. Like, so she's, like,
always gonna find a way
to fight through
and make things happen.
- She'll turn on us.
- Oh, yeah.
Very quickly.
I wouldn't be surprised
if she takes out Karla
and then she takes out us.
You're probably right.
Yeah, I mean,
she's got to go tonight.
- Yup.
- Got to be.
JESSE:
But the thing is,
when you blindside somebody,
[laughing]: you have to know
what you're doing here.
Otherwise, it might come back
and blow up on you.
So checklist number one--
you have to have a cover story.
Noelle's on edge
right now. She's a little
bit nervous, I can tell.
And because she's on edge
right now, if you don't give her
a cover story
for every conversation you have,
when she goes and sits on a log
and starts
thinking things through,
she's gonna start wondering why
you had it and what you said.
It was good.
- Oh, you had it? Perfect.
- Yeah.
Now we're straight.
No way
- that she sees it coming.
- JESSE: Yeah.
- It'll be so good.
- Yeah.
So I want you to talk
to Sami and see
if he's 100% on board,
because I feel like
he would tell you.
Okay.
I was already planning
to talk to Sami
because if I'm gonna
take out Noelle,
I need for her
to split the votes,
and I want her
to split the votes on Sami.
He's not seen as trustworthy
by either side,
so I'm just gonna
help that a little bit.
- I don't want Karla
to go just yet.
- Yeah.
But I'm thinking, like...
- But I don't think we could go
to the end of this game
with Noelle.
- Do you think that?
- I don't...
I don't think we could.
JESSE:
So, checklist number two.
You always have to have
the fall guy. [laughs]
OWEN: Going back and forth?
Hmm.
So I think that we need
to split the votes.
NOELLE: Karla.
- JESSE: Sami.
- NOELLE: Sami. Okay.
JESSE:
They're trying to get it
so that the votes are split,
three-three
on Sami and you.
- Oh.
- Because they're scared
- that you have an idol.
- Yeah. Okay.
So then how many votes
do we have for Noelle?
Me, you, Cody and Cass.
I don't...
You think that's she's gonna
flip her vote?
Yeah. If we're talking
the way we're talking right now,
she's gonna assume
that you all are voting with me.
So that's gonna be a four-four.
Unless we can get Gabler.
Checklist number three.
You always have
to have a backup plan.
Are you okay with that?
Yeah, I think so.
- Let me just think
about this for a second.
- Yeah, for sure.
GABLER:
'Cause, you know, I've got
relationships with Owen and Sami
that are gonna
be torched by this,
and we got to think
about the jury at some point.
JESSE:
Gabler is smart, right?
Like, he's thinking things
through, and so, in this game,
you can't just tell them
to vote a certain way.
You have to
make it make sense, right?
And so I was trying
to get Gabler
to sort of envision
his position in the game
after this vote.
I want him to envision,
like, himself
in the power position.
Me and Cody-- we took out
her friend Justine, and then
she got a friend-- Dwight.
Then we took out Dwight,
and then,
- she got a friend-- Owen.
- Got a friend-- Owen.
And then she did that huge move
in front of the jury.
- Yes. Correct.
- So every time we try
and weaken her position,
she comes back.
JESSE: And, I mean, she's
a warrior. That's what she is.
I know she's got to go
before we get too far.
Then we could be back
in the middle
to choose again tomorrow night
- who we want to go...
- So me, you and Cody
would be in
a very powerful position.
I like it.
I'm writing
Noelle down tonight.
Yup.
And that's how
to blindside somebody.
I put everything in place,
I have these cover stories.
You know,
I have this beautiful plan,
and I get to just sit back
and watch it all play out.
- That's amazing.
- Have you heard mine at all?
- Mm-mmm.
- I can't believe it.
I really think we're steering
the ... ship, bro.
- You know what I mean?
- Dude, that's gonna be
... awesome.
[rolling thunder]
- Mm-hmm.
- [rolling thunder]
Okay.
Yeah.
I-I agree.
GABLER:
Jesse made a real quick move.
I understand it.
Noelle's a powerful player,
but I don't like
to be surprised, especially
minutes before Tribal Council.
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, you got to take off, girl.
- I'll see you in there.
- Okay, okay.
Okay. We'll... You got it.
Jesse and Cody--
they're the real
power couple out here.
So, tonight,
I'm trying to think
what's gonna be best for me.
And I've got claws just like
anybody else out here.
♪ ♪
PROBST:
All right. I want to start
with the reward challenge
and one of the best examples
of sheer determination
that I've ever seen.
Noelle, did you have a moment
where you could reflect
on how that
might inspire somebody
who might find themselves
in a similar situation,
where they feel
the odds are against them?
Yeah. You know, I'm gonna
reach that one little kid
that maybe has a disability,
and they're going
through a difficult time,
and they get to see me on
that balance beam, struggling,
and I'm able to overcome it, and
I'm able to win the challenge.
I mean, that's definitely
a huge reason why I'm out here,
is to not only prove it
to myself, but to prove it
to everybody
who believes that they can't.
So, if I could just
reach that one person,
then I'm satisfied,
and I'm happy about it.
Jesse, you benefited
from Noelle's victory
because she brought you along
on the reward.
What was it like
at the sanctuary?
I mean, like, Noelle...
I mean, me and Noelle
have been, like,
you know, out here
since day one together,
and, uh, she's heard me, like,
talk so much about my family,
so much about my kids,
and the only reason
that I was able to read that
letter was because of Noelle.
And then she made me freaking
ugly-cry on national TV.
[laughter]
PROBST:
So, Gabler,
you wake up this morning,
game's back on.
If you're in the operating room,
what part of the surgery
are we at right now?
Well, we lost wire capture,
and we're kind of back
in the aorta
trying to re-recross
the stenotic valve.
- Wow.
- Um, I think,
you know, we're trying
to figure things out.
There's a little bit
of a shakeup going on.
I think I know
what's going down tonight,
but it's a little bit crazy.
There's a lot happening.
Noelle, what do you read
into that?
"I think I know what's
happening, but it's crazy,
- and I'm being vague"?
- NOELLE: I mean,
everyone has their own vision
of how tonight's gonna pan out,
so you got to rely on the
conversations that you've had.
But it's tough,
especially 19 days in.
You think you know someone, but,
hey, you could be totally wrong.
PROBST:
Owen, so, trust,
as always, is once again
what is going
to determine tonight's vote?
Absolutely. I mean,
trust always rises to the top,
and thinking about
who has your back,
who can you move forward with.
I'd like to think
that the plan that
I think is going to happen
is going to happen, but it has
been proven to me and proven
to everyone here that
that's not always the case,
but I feel okay.
- We'll-we'll see what happens.
- PROBST: Jesse,
it's a little bit like
you're negotiating to buy a car,
but you never get to sign
the contract which locks it in.
It's always just like,
"No, we're good,
we're good. You don't need
to sign anything."
JESSE:
Yeah, I mean, trust
is the currency out here,
and you just have
to sort of trust the people
who have the biggest bills,
I guess, right?
And you can't really spend
too much time checking the bills
like you would in,
like, retail or something.
Like, you could hold it
under the black light,
you could write... you know?
Because you're implying
you don't trust them?
- Yeah.
- PROBST: Wow.
So, Cody, there must be
constant lack of certainty
that the last conversation
you had
is the last one
you needed to have.
CODY:
Absolutely. I mean,
the strategy talk changes
throughout the day,
person by person, hour by hour,
and the conversation
that, say, I have,
you know, at hour 12
is maybe not the same one
that I have at hour 14.
And if it is the same,
is the body language the same,
are the eyes starting to wander?
Are the shoulders
starting to change?
To see if they're
getting uncomfortable
in what they're telling you.
Because as that day progresses,
they're talking
to other people as well
and they're hearing all these
stories and they're trying
to decipher which ones
they want to agree with
and they want
to move forward with.
SAMI:
And that's what makes
this game so hard
is, like, I could be
feeling really good
about a conversation,
and you come out of it,
but then, if they're talking
to somebody else for too long,
and you wish they looked at
you like that. Like, "They don't
look at me like that, they don't
talk to me like that."
But at the end of the day,
something was said to somebody
that wasn't true. It was me,
it was somebody else, but we
don't know who it's going to be
- until we go up there and vote.
- PROBST: So, Gabler,
really, it's the duck
up top... [laughs]
underneath. [trills]
GABLER:
Well, what I think is happening,
is most of these killers now
are working with silencers,
- and that's what's going on.
We're...
- PROBST: Who...
- You pointed this way. Who?
- Everybody. Everybody...
Everybody up here.
There's not, like,
a grenade blowing up.
These are very
precision targets.
There's a lot of work
going into them,
and there's gonna be
one fired bullet tonight,
and it's probably
gonna hit the mark
that I think it's gonna hit,
but, uh,
we're gonna find out.
PROBST:
Karla, that was
a very colorful story saying,
"We're assassins waiting for you
to get right where we need you,
and then, boom, you're done."
Yeah, and that's the part
that makes people nervous
is you can't hear them coming,
you can't hear their steps.
You hope that you get to...
maybe you open up one eyelid,
and you're like,
"I'll-I'll take a quick peek,"
and hope that you know who
it is, um, before it's too late.
NOELLE:
And also, you know,
you're thinking
in the back of your head,
"Someone in this group, like,
there's a very, very great
chance that they have an idol."
That's another reason why we're
playing this type of silent
killer assassins game is 'cause
we don't know what's out there,
we don't know who has it.
So, trying to line up
your target, it's scary,
because you could 100% miss.
Jesse, last question.
If Tribal goes the way
you want it to go,
how will it change the game?
It will lay the foundation
for the rest of my game.
And I'm gonna quote my son,
because he wrote me
a letter, and...
Well, he told me
to "Get that money, baby."
- [laughter]
- So it will set me up
to get that money, baby.
Perfect ending.
It is time to vote.
Cassidy, you're up.
♪ ♪
If anybody has an advantage
or an idol,
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Okay, I'll read the votes.
First vote: Karla.
Noelle. One vote Karla,
one vote Noelle.
Sami. One vote, Sami.
Karla. Two votes, Karla.
Oh, my God.
Noelle. We're tied. Two votes,
Karla, two votes, Noelle.
Noelle. That's three votes,
Noelle, two votes, Karla,
one vote, Sami.
Eleventh person voted out,
the fourth member of our jury:
Noelle. That's four.
That's enough.
- You need
to bring me your torch.
- Good job, guys.
NOELLE:
Okay, love you.
Love you guys.
Don't be sorry.
- GABLER: Good job, Noelle.
- NOELLE: Love you.
Give me a hug.
Noelle, the tribe has spoken.
Good luck, everyone.
- Bye.
- Bye, Noelle.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp. Good night.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
I'm hiding in plain sight.
- [Cassidy yells]
- OWEN: We just take off
like bats out of hell immediately.
PROBST:
And there it comes--
another big swell!
Gasping for a breath.
That's how you do it
on Survivor!
I came into this game wanting
to play the hardest,
and that's
what got me voted off.
But they did a good job.
They-they smelled it coming.
I'm absolutely satisfied
with what I've been able
to do and accomplish,
especially physically,
and to be their first
above-knee amputee
to ever play this game
of Survivor.
Hopefully, I can pave a way
for a new generation of people
to start applying.
[roars]