♪ ♪
SAMI:
So at Tribal tonight,
Noelle ended up going home.
Noelle, the tribe has spoken.
SAMI:
I thought I was
kind of in the numbers.
I thought it would be smart
to go after Karla,
but Owen and I were
left out of the vote, and
I could not have been
further off from what happened.
I've dug myself this hole,
and right now,
it's hard to see
how to get out of this.
W-Why...
Noelle...
No.
- We're pretty 100 on that, brah.
- I'll... Yeah, I'll ask Gabler.
SAMI:
I was gonna try to act like
I voted with the majority.
Then I realized
I've already lied enough.
Like, I've done enough
to get myself to this point.
All right,
I wrote Karla's name.
Why'd you write my name down?
Cass, Gabler's with you guys.
I write Karla's-Karla's name.
I wrote Karla's name.
- Can I ask why?
- 100%.
I... I thought it was...
completely on the other side.
Like, I... I was thinking
if you had an idol
and you played the idol
and it was in the majority,
that would be great 'cause then
you could just play the idol
and then Noelle would just
go home anyways.
And you see where it got me.
That's where I'm at.
- Cody and Jesse flipped.
- Yeah.
They told me about it
last-second.
But here's the good news.
- I've got a plan...
- Mm-hmm.
- for me and you...
- Okay.
to get to the final three.
GABLER: I knew Owen would be
very betrayed by tonight's
reversal of the vote, so,
I immediately pulled Owen aside.
He was the first person
I talked to.
No.
- I don't know why,
but it's just...
- No, no, dude,
I'm telling you,
it's not as bad as you think.
It'll be better
tomorrow morning. Trust me.
I'm in a very good position.
I have a relationship
with everybody out here.
And even tonight
when I was part of a blindside,
no one's talking
about me as a target.
I'm hiding in plain sight.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
OWEN:
This is not fun.
[laughing]: This is terrible.
It's, like, getting comical
at this point that I just,
like, keep finding myself
as the closest person
to the person
who's getting blindsided.
And it's depressing realizing
that I've just been outfoxed
for, like,
the nine billionth time.
It's like Charlie Brown trying
to kick the football,
and Lucy's taking it away,
you know,
and he falls
on his back like always.
But except, in this scenario,
it's not just Lucy.
It's Linus
and freaking Pig-Pen
and Peppermint Patty
and the stupid kid
playing the piano.
And it's like every single one
of the Peanut kids
is out to get me,
and it's just like...
Aah.
This sucks.
CODY:
You guys trying
to make some rice this morning?
Think we might give the fire
a go in a little bit, yeah.
- I'll try starting it
in a second.
- Once more.
SAMI:
You know, this is the first vote
I've been left out of
all game.
Nice, Sami.
- [Cody laughs]
- KARLA: Yeah.
SAMI:
But, you know, I...
I've been playing
in the middle
for a very long time,
and if you play with fire,
you're gonna get burned.
And I got burned
pretty bad last night.
The letters from the rewards
of the sanctuary...
Sami.
SAMI: ...it couldn't come
for me at a better time
because today is, like,
my worst day out here.
To reread the words...
My mom told me, you know,
when I'm dealt
with difficult situations,
I keep my head up
and my shoulders back.
And, uh...
yeah, it means a lot
to have that right now.
I feel like my mom doesn't know
how much I listen to her
because I don't
really show it to her.
I was really worried about
coming out here and failing,
and my whole life,
I've been failing to try.
And I know it hurts the people
that-that believe in me
to-to see me fail to try.
I want my little cousins,
I want my brothers,
my sisters, my little
baby brother see me trying
to do things for myself.
And for my mom to be able to see
that her words
helped me push through--
it means a lot to me, and so,
as my mom reminded me,
I'm gonna keep my head up,
I'm gonna put my shoulders back,
and I'm gonna make the best
of the situation that I've got.
Mom, I'm doing this one for you.
I just might,
for once in my life,
say "You told me so."
Doesn't mean
that I'm just gonna, like,
cut all ties with you. Like...
[laughing]: I would hope you
don't just cut all ties with me.
I hope that you are open,
as well, to, like, if...
I don't know. If we're ever
trying to make a move,
you'd be down, that you...
If you... if you guys are down,
I'll help you guys get
to where you guys...
wherever you guys
want to get to.
Who was the first
to mention my name?
The first mention
of your name was Cass.
SAMI:
At this point,
my best move
is stirring up a lot of chaos.
And so, I had to lie
to Karla about Cassidy.
Why not just try
to salvage what little
relationship there might be
with Karla even though
I wrote her name down?
It was a mutual
between her and myself.
We were just like, "Oh, yeah,
Karla's... she's... you know,
she's really good. I think
we just need to get her now."
Yeah.
I'm freaking out
a little bit inside because
Cassidy and I have been together
since day one of this game.
And so,
my dumb self told Cassidy
about my idol.
Well, look,
if you do have an idol
and you're not playing it,
I won't hold that against you,
just so you know.
- You bitch. [laughs]
- [laughs]
KARLA:
So I'm concerned
because Sami told me
Cassidy has said,
"You know, Karla may seem
like a big threat."
I don't know how true or not
it may be,
but it feels very true to me.
I feel like he's on the bottom,
so he's gonna try to,
like, potentially sow
some mistrust between us.
I just want to get ahead of that
in case he is trying
to say ... about me.
No, no, he's not.
I mean, obviously,
I'm in a very vulnerable
position because I...
I mean, so am I.
Well, and I also told you
something that...
- I know.
- I hope just stays between us
- It will. It will.
- because it's... scary.
She knows I have an idol,
and she's seeing my gameplay,
and it's very similar to her.
And so, that kind of
makes me wonder, is
my closest person here, my ally,
really my ally?
- Do you trust me? Okay.
- I do. I do.
I have to act first.
Time is running out.
We have six days left,
and if I don't
go on the offense,
this game is gonna
be decided for me.
I would love to see two girls
in the... in the finale.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
OWEN:
These sunrises are never
gonna get old.
No, brah.
OWEN:
Yeah, those clouds--
they're magical.
Yeah.
- OWEN: Six more days.
- CASSIDY: Yeah.
OWEN:
Crazy.
- CODY: We got company, y'all.
- Where?
[boat engine humming]
KARLA:
Aw, no.
- CODY: Boat mail.
- What the heck?
- [whooping]
- GABLER: We have a visitor?
- KARLA: Yup.
GABLER:
When a boat pulls up,
it's always
something monumental.
The last time a boat pulled up
was about 20 days ago,
and I went on a journey,
and that changed my game.
So, we knew
it was gonna be
something dramatic immediately.
Okay.
[Cassidy gasps]
- Go! Go!
- [Cassidy shrieks]
OWEN: We just take off like
bats out of hell, and it's just
off to the races immediately,
no-no discussion needed.
SAMI: It's crazy 'cause looking
for things in Survivor--
it's like a taboo.
You don't do it.
Now here we are at final seven.
We don't care anymore.
And I'm gonna
need this advantage
in the game
'cause I'm on the bottom,
so I need this.
SAMI: Oh, yeah.
SAMI:
I'm looking for the color.
I'm looking for, like,
an aqua color.
Not seeing it,
and so I'm looking
high and low
for this thing, and I...
I don't know.
It's a lot harder than it looks.
OWEN:
The pace coming out of the gate
is fast and furious.
Everyone is out here looking.
Cody's got a stick,
poking around,
Gabler's going off the path.
Holy moly.
This is like a needle
in a hay field.
CASSIDY:
I would love to find
an advantage, but truthfully,
I haven't had good luck
finding anything in this game.
I've had to, like, get by
by, like, the seat of my pants.
You know, I haven't had
any idols or advantages.
I mean, I've looked.
So I'm worried
that mainly that Sami
will find an advantage.
Excitement's turning
to discouragement.
- Same.
- I've just been everywhere.
You know, we could do a... Uh,
you want to do a "lurp" walk?
- CASSIDY: What's that?
- Long range
reconnaissance patrol.
OWEN:
We start grouping up
for a search.
Gabler teaches us about some
search technique that they used
during the Vietnam War.
Keep lurping.
Looking straight
and left and right
and having a group, like,
kind of like
recon tower situation.
This is how
they did it in Vietnam.
They walked through the jungle
in little teams of four.
Never usually above eye level.
Am I right, guys?
- I don't know.
Do we call it quits?
Do we keep looking?
Yeah.
Kind of want to...
Give me some blue string, Jeff.
Come on, man.
♪ ♪
CODY:
The excitement wears off,
and then you start thinking,
and you look at other people.
"Well, maybe they're not looking
as hard as they first were,
"so maybe they found it
and they're just
digging around
for the hell of it."
But the last thing
I want to do is know
that it was found
after I gave up.
I don't have that in me.
I would be embarrassed
to know that it was found
after I stopped looking.
Dude, we've torn this place
apart, man. That's for sure.
- You think so?
- I think that's
a very strong possibility.
I mean, I don't know.
I've looked all over, man.
I found nothing.
So, I may just... I mean,
it's about time to get...
- I mean, how much energy and...
- Before you get exhausted?
Yeah, it's probably
a very good idea.
I may go back there,
just do my beach swim.
Yeah. For me, it's, like, how
long do I stay here and search?
- I've-I've walked this
whole thing four times.
- Yeah.
I've walked it slow, I've walked
it fast, I've walked it...
CODY:
I'm talking to Gabler.
I catch,
out of the corner of my eye,
something, like, the same color
as the tree trunk.
It's about time to get...
I mean...
CODY:
At this point I'm thinking,
"Oh, boy, uh, what do I do now?"
So I just kind of, like,
put my hand up casually
and waited for him to leave.
[quietly]:
Yeah, baby.
I could just scream
at the top of my lungs.
That's what I really want
to do right now.
I can't help myself. I do
a little shimmy-shake dance.
Like, I'm pretty stoked.
Like, "Oh, bro."
Thank God I had the tenacity
to come back out here.
Ooh. I'm a gambler.
I love this.
Water now starting
to crest above that grate.
[inhaling sharply]
CODY:
We've all seen Survivor.
We've all seen this challenge.
It's scary,
but for me, I'm going,
"I live in Hawaii, I love
the ocean, I'm in all the time."
This is awesome.
This is so awesome.
I am the front-runner on this.
But I also have
to think of my other players.
After living on an island
with people for 21 days,
I should know who is comfortable
in a panic situation.
I had to make
the right decision here because
it's a double shot at immunity,
and I can't blow it.
I'm feeling very good about it.
I got a smile so big,
I can taste the earwax.
Mm!
If you want this, you got
to apply to be on Survivor.
♪ ♪
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- [all voicing assent]
- Yes, sir.
- First things first.
- Cassidy.
- No! All right,
I'm winning it back.
- Got to take it back.
You can win it back.
- [laughs]
Thank you.
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
Today's challenge
is going to test
your ability to remain calm
when everything else
in your body says otherwise.
You're gonna take a spot
under a grated steel barrier.
As the tide rises, your
breathing room will decrease
until ultimately,
there is nowhere left
to breathe.
The person who lasts
the longest wins immunity,
is guaranteed a spot
in the final six.
Losers-- Tribal Council tonight
where somebody will be
voted out of this game.
Their dream of winning Survivor
43 will come to an end.
All right, we're gonna
draw for spots,
we'll get started.
Yeah, Cody.
But Jeff, I found something
in the jungle today.
- No.
- And it's a present for you.
- For sure.
- Thank you. I will take that.
So this morning, you all knew
there was an advantage hidden.
Cody found it. This is the
Choose Your Champion Advantage.
What it means is
Cody had the secret opportunity
to select one of you
to win this challenge,
which means, if he doesn't win,
but the person he bet on--
if they win-- he is also safe.
This is his secret to keep,
which means
you won't know until Tribal
because we will not
reveal this until
after the votes have been cast
but before they are read.
Huge advantage with
seven people left in the game.
All right, now we're gonna
draw for spots.
Then we'll get started.
Here we go. Who are you gonna
be sitting next to in the water?
All right, here we go.
Everybody get under your grate.
[inhaling through noses]
And this challenge
is on.
This is a classic
Survivor challenge.
This is unique
every time we run it.
Every day
in the ocean is different.
You might start with
a higher tide or a lower tide.
Everybody looking good.
Still have plenty
of breathing room at this point.
Owen, how you feeling right now?
OWEN: It's unbelievable.
I'm happy to be here.
You always want to try this one.
- Yeah.
- [laughing]
PROBST:
That's easy to say
until a swell comes.
[inhales sharply]
PROBST:
I can see from looks on faces,
you're already uncomfortable.
Claustrophobia is
probably the first thing.
The tide hasn't risen that much,
but you get little swells
like that.
Moment by moment,
that tide is rising.
Make no mistake about it.
Your breathing room
is decreasing.
And Gabler can't take it anymore.
Gabler is the first person out.
We are down to six.
If Cody bet on Gabler,
that bet is over.
But only Cody knows
who he bet on.
[coughing]
Obviously, a big advantage
in this challenge is
how comfortable are you
in the water in general?
Not everybody grows up surfing.
Another swell.
- [Sami groans]
- Sami, out of nowhere
takes a swell,
can't take anymore.
And we are down to five.
Those are the moments
that get you.
The swell is too much.
It lasts too long.
PROBST: You're underwater longer
than you feel comfortable,
and you just pop out.
And there it comes
just like that.
Another swell.
Some of these swells are fast,
some of them
really take their time.
Wow.
Another big, slow swell.
This is impressive.
PROBST:
That was a long time underwater.
Jesse's out,
and we're down to four.
Karla, Owen, Cody and Cassidy.
GABLER:
Great job, buddy.
We're getting down to it now.
That water is rising.
Immunity on the line.
This is old school Survivor.
Back when we inflicted
a little more pain.
Nice to revisit
some of our old haunts.
♪ ♪
You are at one hour
in this challenge.
It's exhausting
to be doing this right now.
Everybody wants it to be over.
You got to keep digging.
♪ ♪
Tide continues to rise.
This isn't just one swell.
This is constant.
That steel grate
is being pushed around.
Here comes another swell.
Absolutely submerged.
PROBST:
This is the most difficult
stage so far.
A far cry from when we started.
Still underwater.
We could
lose somebody here soon.
Cody has let go,
but he's still under.
That's the panic.
Everybody's underwater. Unbelievable.
- Cody's back in it...
- [gasping]
- ...gasping for a breath.
- GABLER: Golly.
PROBST:
That's how you do it
on Survivor!
Cody lets go again.
He's still underwater.
He's still good.
- Cody can't do it. He's out!
- [Cody groans]
We're down to three.
Now the question for Cody is,
what name did he secretly
write down?
Was it Karla, Owen or Cassidy?
If so,
he's still got another shot.
Cody, you freezing?
I'm frozen, man.
It's cold in there.
You have been in that water
for 90 minutes.
Your body's tight,
limbs are cramped.
You're absolutely freezing.
The only thing keeping you
in this challenge is you.
Let's go! Go!
[muffled shouting]
PROBST:
This is why you signed up.
This is what you wanted, and you
got it, and you're killing it!
Childhood dreams coming
to life right here.
- One hour, 52 minutes.
- CODY: Come on! Come on!
- You got it!
- Here comes another big swell...
- Go! Go!
- Let's go!
PROBST:
...submerging everybody.
GABLER:
Come on, guys!
[muffled shouting]
PROBST: Boy.
Wow.
PROBST:
That is the longest yet.
- GABLER: There you go, Karla!
- CODY: Come on, guys! Let's go!
This is incredible.
That is a long time
without a breath.
[overlapping shouting]
- [muffled shouting]
- GABLER: Go, Karla!
- PROBST: And Cassidy is out.
- GABLER: Aah!
PROBST:
An unbelievable performance
by Cassidy.
- Come on, y'all! Let's go!
- It's not gonna be enough.
- GABLER: You got it, Cass!
- Cassidy, you lasted two hours,
- and we are down to two.
- SAMI: Two hours.
- Two hours.
- It is a showdown
- between Karla and Owen.
- Come on, guys!
PROBST:
We have seen some great efforts
in challenges this season.
This may be
at the top of the list.
- Come on, y'all! [whoops]
- Good job!
PROBST:
The ocean came in
with a job to do,
but Karla and Owen
have pushed back.
- [Cassidy laughs]
- GABLER: Wow.
PROBST:
Two hours, 20 minutes.
Geez Louise, brah.
PROBST:
This thing goes long enough,
that water
will reach its peak
and start to drop.
We've never had players
outlast the rising tide
- and swells of the ocean.
- GABLER: Boy!
But they're heading there
right now.
SAMI:
Good job!
Coming up
on two hours, 45 minutes.
You're almost there!
Keep it up, you two! Keep it up!
PROBST:
We have been out here so long
that the tide
that was once rising
is now dropping.
And without the tide,
this is just a steel grate.
[inhaling sharply]
I'm still here.
I have more gray hair.
Owen, how are you feeling
right now?
[Cody laughs]
- It's happening, isn't it?
- CODY: Yup.
- GABLER: It is.
The fact that you are
both talking again
- and that the water
is dropping...
- Wow.
We're making
an unprecedented decision
to end this challenge.
Both of you will win
individual immunity.
This challenge is over.
- You can both breathe.
- Yes! [whooping]
That's it. You have done it.
- [indistinct shouting]
- 43 seasons, 22 years.
We've done well over
a thousand challenges.
We have never had players
outlast the challenge.
The tide came in.
- You were underwater
for long periods of time.
- [Karla laughs]
Players dropped, but you didn't,
and the tide left.
Congratulations. Swim over.
- PROBST: Karla, come here.
- GABLER: Why'd you put me
- in the same row with him?
- [Karla shrieks]
- Oh, your body is freezing.
- Yeah. I am.
GABLER: Hey, behind your ears
there's some gills.
- Karla.
- Yeah.
- Hug for sure.
- Karla!
You made history
in winning this.
This has never happened.
You both outlasted
the challenge.
You both deserve immunity.
You're safe tonight, cannot
be voted out of this game.
- Congratulations. Take a seat.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Oh, my God!
- Owen, come on over.
You, too.
- You have made it to six.
- [laughs]
- Owen is safe tonight.
- OWEN: Oh, my gosh.
- Have a seat.
Try to start warming up.
- Thank you so much.
- Nice job, brother.
- [Karla laughs]
All right, Karla, Owen,
you have made it to six.
Cody still has a
Choose Your Champion Advantage,
which will be revealed tonight
after you vote,
but before the votes are read.
And then you have a whole bunch
of scrambling back at camp.
All right, swim out.
See you tonight at Tribal.
- Oh!
- Oh, Jeff!
- Love you all.
SAMI:
Final seven.
Two people are immune.
And on top of all that,
if my gut's telling me
that Cody picked the right way,
which I do think he did,
there's three out
of seven players immune.
It's terrifying because I'm one
of the four that's not immune.
Now I think
that the target's on my back.
And this is the last time I can
play the Shot in the Dark,
so if I have to play it, I will
play it at a game-time decision.
♪ ♪
[indistinct,
overlapping chatter]
- How about that?
- That was so hard.
- I know.
- OWEN: That was insane.
- KARLA: That was.
OWEN:
But, you know, dude,
like, truly
just, like, out-of-body.
- KARLA: It was like
I became one with the water.
- Yeah.
- OWEN: Literally at a point...
- KARLA: You knew exactly when...
CASSIDY:
This was a really
hard moment for me.
- SAMI: It was incredible.
- OWEN: That was nuts.
CASSIDY:
I don't know
why this one got me.
I think it's just because
I put so much effort in
and I still came up short.
But why?
Ended up being two people
winning immunity today
and then, potentially,
Cody being safe as well.
So that takes basically
three people off of the table
for tonight and leaves the other
four pretty vulnerable.
Keep your chin up.
CASSIDY: Jesse's vulnerable,
Gabler's vulnerable,
Sami's vulnerable,
and then I'm vulnerable.
So, this is terrifying.
What are you thinking
for tonight?
I think maybe Sami, yeah?
I feel like we could all
get on board with that.
CASSIDY:
I'm worried for myself
because people,
I think, are starting
to see me and Karla
as, like,
a pretty tight duo, which is
always dangerous in this game.
And so, I don't know.
I think people
might try to get me out
just to knock Karla down a peg
right now because she's safe.
But I'm hoping that,
at least, tonight,
they see Sami
as a bigger threat than me.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, no. I-I agree,
too. We've talked about this.
It's the easiest.
This is the final seven.
I think
it's a make-or-break number.
So, I could do Sami today.
But I'm kind of
beating myself up
about telling Cassidy
about my, uh, idol.
She could start telling anyone
she wants, right?
"Karla has an idol," and that
will blow up my entire game.
KARLA:
So my game plan right now,
as really bad
as-as this sounds...
is to get my number-one ally
out of the game.
Let's do, uh... Cass?
- Really? Is this...
is this real?
- Uh, yeah.
- Is this serious?
- Yeah.
- Cass.
- Okay.
SAMI:
I hear Cass' name
from Karla,
which is music to my ears.
This is what I wanted, but
Karla and Cass have voted
together the entire time.
The way that you were
with me yesterday--
I appreciated that, that's good.
Cool.
SAMI:
And so, I'm gonna
tread water lightly.
I still think
there's a very good chance
the Shot in the Dark
comes out of the bag
and goes into play
with me tonight.
- It's Cass, bro.
- Interesting.
SAMI:
But for now,
to hear Cass' name,
it-it has a nice
little ring to it.
- My guess is Cass.
- Okay.
That's who I want to go.
Go Cass.
- Karla's got to be next.
- Yeah.
If you look at the alliances
right now, you've got, you know,
Cass and-and Karla are tight.
If you were gonna do
anything, you'd go Cassidy now,
- Karla tomorrow.
- Yeah.
A lot of people are starting
to lean towards, you know, just
taking out Cassidy because Cass
and Karla are this tight pair.
And maybe
I need to just go with the flow.
- What are you thinking?
- Okay.
JESSE: But at this point,
Karla wants
to get rid of Cassidy.
So you're on board with Cass?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
JESSE:
The fact that Karla is on board
sort of set off,
like, a little bit
of, like, alarm bells in my head
because it just means that
Karla doesn't see Cassidy as,
like, a key piece in her game.
I mean, I'm also
okay with Sami, but...
No.
JESSE: Then she's starting
to build new bridges
with Sami, and Sami is a threat
for, you know, other reasons.
Sami's, like,
this amazing fire magician.
- You want me to start fire?
- Yeah.
JESSE:
Nobody wants to go up
against Sami on fire,
and nobody trusts him.
He's kind of flip-floppy,
wishy-washy, so, like,
maybe now's the time
to take out Sami.
Cody's pushing for Cass, I think
Gabler's on board, and...
- To vote Cass?
- To vote Cass.
OWEN: Wow.
OWEN: Yeah.
Ooh. To help drive a wedge?
Then they're going at
each other's throats next time.
- Yeah?
- And then we can count on Cass
to vote Karla next time.
Hell, yeah.
JESSE:
Sami-- I don't want him
to slip through.
OWEN:
No, I 100% agree with you.
- It's been annoying.
- But this is where it changes.
Yeah.
So I'm okay
with taking out Sami tonight,
but Jesse--
he flipped on Dwight,
he flipped on Noelle.
He's stabbed me
in the back before.
And as much as I like the guy,
I don't know if I can trust him.
- Good.
- I'm gonna talk to Cody
and try and get him to see...
- And I'll talk to Gabler,
try to do the same.
- Yeah.
OWEN:
Voting correctly tonight
is crucial to my game,
but if I think
it's gonna be that simple,
I could be played
for a fool once again.
JESSE:
What if
instead of voting Cass--
because, honestly,
she's not a huge threat--
what if we vote Sami out?
And we don't fill Karla in
so she's the only one
that votes Cass.
So that when they come back,
they're at odds.
CODY: When Jesse pitched the
idea of, let's vote out Sami
so we can put Karla
on her own little island
and make her look
on the wrong side of the vote,
it makes me think.
You know, like, something...
And that's where we-- me
and Jesse-- get along so well,
is we think
of other options, right?
Because sometimes the clear-cut
one is not always the best one.
Yeah? Ooh.
Lucky for me, Owen won
the immunity challenge,
which means I'm now immune.
But in my mind,
it's time for Cassidy to go.
Like, I think we need
to split up Cassidy and Karla.
- I don't trust him.
I feel like... Really?
CODY:
I get it. He's a fire threat,
but he's also a challenge loser.
He's the first one out
all the time.
Cassie's won immunity.
She's almost...
She put up a good fight today.
CODY:
Jesse and I have been
steering the Survivor bus,
I think, since the merge,
but in this case,
we are not seeing eye to eye.
So, we have to get
on the same page.
We started this game together.
We're freaking finishing
this game together.
And making the right choice
tonight will get us
one step closer to the end.
♪ ♪
All right, so let's start
by talking about
today's historic challenge.
Karla and Owen,
we've never had anybody
outlast an entire high tide.
As a result, Karla and Owen
are both safe tonight.
And we still have a question
with Cody,
who found the
Choose Your Champion Advantage.
If he bet on either Owen
or Karla, then Cody
is safe tonight as well.
So there's a lot going on.
And this afternoon,
I was thinking about you all
after spending three hours
watching that tide
rise and fall.
The thing about tides
is they're never the same.
They ebb and they flow.
They're different every day.
The only thing
you can count on is
there is a low tide
and there is a high tide.
And if you draw that analogy
to Survivor,
the only thing
that matters every day is
you got to survive
the high tide of Survivor.
PROBST:
So let's get into it, Gabler.
What happened
when you get back to camp?
Because this was unexpected.
GABLER:
Oh, it was big. You know,
when there's seven people left,
it's always kind of
a magical time
in Survivor history.
Things happen.
The fact that you have one, two,
potentially three people
out of the seven
that are immune--
that was a lot of chaos
back at camp.
PROBST:
And how does that work, Karla?
What are the rules
of this group when it comes
- to having a conversation?
- KARLA: We are so polite. Like,
"Would you like
to dance with me, sir?"
"Sure." You know, and then,
"Let's dance now."
So you never know
where that tide
is going and how high or low
it's going
'cause everyone's open
for business.
Owen, it's got to be terrifying
with no firm footing.
Talk about a tide.
You're just...
This is it, all day, every day
out here with you all.
Yeah. It's absolute madness,
and it's ironic,
'cause at the last Tribal,
I said,
"I feel okay, Jeff.
I feel fine."
And then, of course, the plan
that I thought was
going to happen did not happen.
So, just seeing everyone
talk and turn
and twist and swap partners,
and it's-it's a lot going on.
PROBST:
Sami, what's going on?
You-you were gesturing
back there.
Yeah, man. It's really hard
'cause after the last vote,
I feel very so much
on the bottom.
And so it's hard because
you don't get second chances
this late into the game.
All I can do is put myself out
there as a free agent, right?
And everybody else is deciding
whether I am the guy who's
at the end of his career,
who you don't
really want
to give a chance anymore,
or the guy
who's at the end of the career
who you give
the one-year contract
because that guy can still
produce for you a little bit,
and get you to the next vote.
Jesse,
that's a pretty good pitch
because that's Sami saying,
"Look, I can catch the ball
a couple more times
if you need me."
- That can be valuable at seven.
- Yeah, and I think
that's why you have to
constantly be open for business.
That's why
you have these conversations.
That's why you have to consider
everybody as, like,
you know,
a member of your team,
and a possible
useful member of your team.
PROBST:
Cassidy, the one thing
you can count on
with every other player is
what they are thinking about
is this:
how do I get to the end?
- Yeah.
- So when somebody comes
to approach you with an idea,
- it's to help them
get to the end.
- Yeah.
And the question is
will it help you get to the end?
Yeah. I mean, especially as
we're getting closer and closer
to this endgame, right,
and-and you have to analyze
every person, their strengths,
their weaknesses,
their moves, you know,
their threat level in the game.
Do I feel like I could trust you
for a vote if I needed you?
You're trying to see into, like,
the crystal ball of the future
when it's-it's really foggy
right now.
PROBST:
And, Sami, now you have
the ticking clock on idols,
if they're in the game,
other advantages.
Tonight's the last night
you can use Shot in the Dark.
How much does that
ratchet up the tension?
It ratchets up a lot.
You know, advantages and idols--
you know, these've been the talk
of the town around the season,
but yet we still have yet
to see one played.
It becomes paramount
for you deciding,
do I want a souvenir
to take home or do
I want to play the game all the
way till I can play the game?
You know what I mean?
Especially in terms of, like,
having an advantage or having
an idol, and so, I'm gonna
go up there, I'm gonna play
my Shot in the Dark tonight.
You know, at the end of the day,
if the people who said
they were with me today
are actually with me,
we should be fine.
But if not,
we'll see what happens.
PROBST:
So, Karla, here's where
those conversations
where you asked each other
to dance come into play,
because what
I just heard him say was,
"Don't count on my vote.
"And if everything
is as it's supposed to be,
my vote won't matter anyway."
KARLA: Yeah. Uh, well...
It's, um...
[sighs]
It... I don't know,
it's unfortunate, I think.
You know, I've never
heard someone just say,
"I'm gonna
play my Shot in the Dark."
C-Can you explain to me
how it's unfortunate, though?
Like, what's unfortunate
about it?
The fact that, you know,
people have told you to trust,
and then you're just saying,
"Well, screw my vote."
SAMI:
If what I was told today
is what's going on,
then it doesn't matter.
PROBST:
So, Gabler,
when you hear Sami say,
"I'm playing
my Shot in the Dark,"
assuming he's telling the truth,
does it change anything
about your pulse
or is that just Survivor?
No. I'm gonna
continue on with the way
I believe it's gonna be
when I came in here.
I'm sticking with the plan.
PROBST:
How about you, Jesse?
JESSE:
No, I think this
kind of gets back
to something that we said, like,
last Tribal, where trust
is currency out here.
If you spend too much time
checking, like, if your trust,
like, the bill that somebody
gave you is counterfeit,
then you go back to camp,
and, you know,
nobody can trust you still.
But you got to take risks
in this game.
You got to.
'Cause if I sit back idly
and get lied to
the way I lied to other people,
that's not the way
I want to go out.
All right, it is time to vote.
- Cassidy, you're up.
- [chuckles]
♪ ♪
All right,
before we get to the votes,
let's answer the question of the
Choose Your Champion Advantage.
Who did Cody bet on
to win today's challenge?
If it was Owen or Karla,
then Cody will be safe as well.
Any votes cast against him
will not count.
Cody bet on... Owen.
- [applause]
- [laughs]
- PROBST: Predicted it correctly.
- Wow.
PROBST:
Any votes for Cody
will not count.
All right. If anybody
has an advantage or an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Owen and Karla weren't the only
ones in deep water today, Jeff.
- [laughter]
- I played the Shot in the Dark.
PROBST:
Want to bring it up?
Sure.
Thank you.
All right, so Sami
played his Shot in the Dark,
which means there is
not a vote in here from him.
Sami, if this says you are safe,
any votes against you
will not count.
If it says "not safe,"
then any votes
cast against you will count.
Let's see your fate.
♪ ♪
Sami, you are...
...not safe.
Any votes cast against you
will still count.
All right, I'll read the votes.
First vote, Sami.
Sami. Two votes Sami.
Sami.
That's three votes Sami.
12th person voted out and the
fifth member of our jury, Sami.
That's four. That's enough.
You need to bring me your torch.
- Good luck, buddy. Good luck.
- Hey. A lot of fun.
It was lot of fun, man.
GABLER:
Eat some food for us, buddy.
SAMI:
You guys can
come to Vegas any time.
Just not on Sundays
'cause I got church.
[laughter]
CODY:
I'll be there, brah.
I'll be there.
Sami, the tribe has spoken.
Thank you, brother.
Time for you to go.
Lot of fun, peeps.
- See you, bud.
- SAMI: Have a good one.
[whoops]
[laughter]
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
Good night.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
KARLA:
It's fascinating
how quickly people
will turn on their own alliance.
Karla, I'm coming for you.
"Genius" is the word
for this plan.
OWEN:
This is so unbelievable.
JESSE: If I got to be
more brutal, I will.
GABLER:
The gloves are off now.
It's a death match
to get to the end.
The dominoes started to topple
after the last vote.
I started to lose control
of my fate in the game.
So I played my Shot in the Dark
'cause I felt like
I'd rather go out
swinging for the fences.
And sometimes
those moves don't work out,
but I'm happy
with the way I played.
A million dollars
for a 19-year-old kid
probably wouldn't have gone
to the best of things anyways.
I'm starting
to like Teslas a lot,
and my mom doesn't
really like electric cars,
so I think this works out
better for us both.
[roars]