Hey, real quick, I just--
I want to say two things.
Just, first of all,
I'm sorry for getting
a little worked up and anxious,
but just definitively knowing
my name was coming up, like,
- it definitely was
fear-inducing.
- Sure. Of course.
Tonight was wild.
Morriah went home.
But when I saw my name come up,
I wanted to poop my pants.
Looking down the barrel
of potentially going home,
it was absolutely terrifying.
More importantly,
I just want to say thank you,
not just for keeping me
but just for-for being who
I thought you were, you know?
I'm just so relieved that
my trust in the people
that are here,
in Gabler and Jeanine
and Elie and Sami, like,
that was not unfounded.
I hope this vote solidifies
trust, you know?
Like, we all did
what we said we would do.
That was like a trust exercise
we just went through.
Well, it was. I mean, heck,
I trusted you guys
not even to play my idol, so...
- Yeah.
- I mean...
- I know.
Our tribe has been
slow to get into the game
because up until now we've been
very much focused
on the relationships
and getting to know one another,
so there's a lot of stuff
we still have to do,
but if we can take care of
our bodies a little bit better,
I think we'll be
that much better in challenges,
and hopefully that doesn't put
us back in, in Tribal Council.
You know, tomorrow I think
it's real important
for us to find some food.
I'm thinking of worms.
We can fry 'em up and
that will be our Survivor bacon.
I've been on fumes here
the last couple days.
Oh, boy.
Is there anything going there?
There are some embers in here.
We just got to find 'em.
Right there.
That was the roughest night
I've ever had in my entire life.
Back at home,
when it starts raining,
I could go
to the convenience store
and wait for my mom
to pick me up
or I could run inside
or I could throw
my windshield wipers on.
We can't do that out here.
And I don't know if anybody
has ever tried to do anything
while they're just completely
drenched and everything.
But sleeping?
That's not-- it's not happening
while you're wet.
We might have to come up
with a different roof situation.
Yeah.
- That is getting done today.
- Yeah.
We were not prepared
for that storm last night.
That was a beating.
It was scary
'cause that storm came in
so loud, so fast.
The wind went from, like, this
to probably,
you know, 40-mile-an-hour wind.
What a night.
- I've never had a night
like that, ever.
- Seriously.
That was pretty brutal.
This adventure is
everything I can take
and maybe a little bit more.
I've never pushed
my physical boundaries this far
in my entire life.
And I played football,
ran track, was a boxer.
I do a lot of big hiking
with heavy packs on my back
in mountains, in high altitude,
but, you know, I've got food,
I've got water.
I can stop and do whatever.
This is like-- there's just--
you never know
and you're never dry.
So this game
is blowing my mind right now.
Those gulps of water,
which I know are good for me,
I just feel
like puking right now.
Oh, man.
I am worried about Gabler.
He's a big guy
and he's running out of steam,
and I worry
that he's not gonna be able
to sustain himself out here.
- Uh-oh.
Very. I'm extremely nauseous.
So I'm not 100% sure if he is
the best piece of the puzzle
for this tribe moving forward
'cause he's a strong man, but
it doesn't do us any good
if he's lying on the ground.
I'm 20 to 30 years older
than some of my teammates,
but I don't want them
to look at me
and think that I'm dead weight.
It's walking a fine line
because, I mean,
I had to lay down
this morning for,
you know, a couple hours
while everybody was getting
the fire going,
and I know every minute
I'm laying down, resting,
and I'm getting stronger,
I'm getting weaker in the game.
Long enough?
- It's okay.
- Great.
The longer I have to loaf,
if you will, to manage my body,
the more of a liability
I become.
Yeah, yeah, I'll just yell
if somebody's coming.
Advantages are all-important
in this game.
This is the new era
of Survivor, and there's a lot
of new dangerous twists.
It's a 26-day season.
You got to play aggressive
from the jump,
so having that advantage
would be huge.
Yeah.
Okay, yeah.
Our tribe
is doing all right now,
which feels great.
I think that we work well together.
I think we have
a good sort of sense of unity
and a good sense of teamwork,
but at the same time it seems
like the tribal lines
are getting clearer.
Noelle and Justine cliqued up,
like, almost immediately,
and me, Cody, and Nneka
are tight,
and Dwight-- he's on his own,
basically, so I'm trying
to really build
that bond with him
and make sure
that we're a tight pair
because I think we could be
good partners going forward.
Back home,
like, all my decisions
have been made in a partnership,
right, like...
Oh, Lord.
I wanted to come in here
and find somebody I trust
immediately,
and Jesse's that person.
He's someone that I could
rock with the entire game,
but at the same time I feel
like I've made good social bonds
with everybody on my tribe,
and I've been able to do that
ever since I was a kid.
When I was in school,
whenever there was, like,
some events nearby with
influential political figures,
I'd reach out and say, like,
"Hey, I'm a junior journalist.
Can I interview you?"
Those included
Madeleine Albright,
Dr. Condoleezza Rice,
Colin Powell.
I'd just go up to them, start
talking, start asking questions,
and I didn't really have
that fear in me,
and even to this day I don't
fear walking up to people
and just talking to them,
so in the game of Survivor,
I'm talking to everybody,
no fear,
having a good conversation.
That allows me to build
these really great bonds
with these people,
except for possibly Cody.
Yeah.
I really like Cody,
but, like,
we never talk game at all.
- For real?
- No, like,
we'll just, like,
talk about life, whatever,
but it's never game-related.
- So...
- Yeah.
- But got to do it.
Dwight doesn't
really trust Cody.
Yeah, he doesn't talk strategy,
but I'm okay with that.
:
Cody's just Cody.
He's just kind of off
on his own.
I want to jump off that
'cause it looks really fun
and it feels like home.
Like, we always go jump
off bridges, jump off rocks.
Pretty inviting.
That's beautiful.
I want to climb up there
'cause I bet
nobody's ever done it before.
And it gets kind of boring
at camp
just sitting around,
eating coconuts.
Cody's fun, man, honestly.
At first
you're thinking, like,
oh, this guy's crazy
'cause he's just, like,
spouting out these wild ideas
and stuff, but then,
like, I realized
he just likes to have fun.
What do you think of my hat?
I'm gonna wear it
loud and proud.
Cody's just living, dude.
Like, it says it on his ass--
he's living.
You want to enjoy your time
while you're out here.
You know, like...
- You know what I mean?
- Yes, sir.
... yeah.
- Livin'.
- Livin'. L-I-V-I-N.
So, like, I'm not
that worried about Cody.
Honestly, like, I'm able
to connect with, like,
almost everybody on the tribe
except for Justine.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
Oh.
Oh, my God, there's a spider
right there, too.
Oh, my God, I just
keep walking into them.
Aah!
I literally see spiders
crawling all around.
I don't know, maybe it's like
the four days of hunger,
but I'm starting to get annoyed.
Wait, Cody, do you mind
putting it over one?
'Cause that makes this side
of the bed a lot smaller.
Or, like, drag it over
a little bit?
Okay.
The thing about
Justine is, like,
I don't know how much we jibe.
She lives, like, a city
over from where I grew up,
but I think she's just
a different kind of person.
My nails are so disgusting.
But at this point we don't
have to make a decision.
Also, Dwight risked and lost
his vote on the journey, so...
at the end of the day,
he doesn't really have a say.
I would like to sort of be
on the same page as him,
but right now I'm sort of
in the driver's seat,
which is awesome.
So... bring your foot back.
You're gonna pull it out
and then back in.
Back, forward, same foot.
We dominated
our first immunity challenge,
and that is
such a good feeling because
overall the Coco tribe
is still pretty united,
but when you start peeling back
those layers,
you can kind of see
where the divides occur.
Did you guys finish
all your sets?
- Yes.
- Five on each side?
There's a three-person
girls alliance,
which is me, Lindsay,
Cassidy, and we're bringing in
James to be our fourth.
Yeah. Come on.
That leaves Geo and Ryan.
They believe
that I'm in a solid three
with them.
You're trying to expand
this part when you breathe in.
But what is making me
a little bit more cautious is,
Ryan is very close to Geo.
- Okay, I...
- You get... you get it?
- Yeah.
-  Yes.
- Look at you.
- There's a bunch of these trees.
- Yeah.
There's another one right there.
Okay.
Ah, no, you got it.
You really were right.
So, if you really don't...
Okay, let's try that.
- Let's find out.
- We should open this?
Look at you go.
- Mm-hmm.
- And...
Watching the show from TV,
you're, like,
Everything looks so much easier,
like, anybody can do it,
and it's not.
Just one almond in there?
But I've gone through
so many struggles in life.
I had to overcome
so many things.
I've kind of always knew
that I was gay
from a very young age.
I knew that I was different.
When I turned 18,
I decided to come out
to my parents, and
their... I guess their dreams
kind of, like,
came down crashing
because I wasn't the person
that they wanted me to be.
That was kind of hard for me
because I always had that
in the back of my head
that if I ever tell my family
that I am not straight,
that they would not
love me anymore
or they would not want
to be with me anymore.
My parents didn't agree
with me being gay.
They ended up pretty much
telling me that
if I'm not gonna
change the way I am,
then I will have to go somewhere
else or leave the house.
- Oh, this one's pretty good.
- Yeah.
Because of that,
I was kind of forced
to going through
a homeless stage.
As a lot of people know,
the LGBT community has
a very high rate of suicide
and depression, and I did
consider not continuing my life,
but I had to learn
how to look at the positive.
So I told myself,
"This is your chance
to make it happen in life.
to keep going
"and don't let anything
or anyone stop you
from whatever
you want to accomplish."
And that's exactly how
I'm gonna play this game.
I'm gonna tell you right now.
I am not gonna let anything
or anyone get in my way.
Oh.
Me and Geo feel like
we've known each other
since before Survivor.
I accept him. I feel like he's
able to be himself around me.
- Oh.
- Okay, cool.
They're in here.
And that's something I feel
he really looks for in life--
to be himself and not
to have to hide anything.
Yes, we do.
- We-we have a rhythm.
- Yeah. Yeah.
So I do think there is
a good push-and-pull
that we have.
- Consider myself a new brother.
- That works for me.
I think if we can take control
and really pay attention,
we can go pretty far.
I think we'll be a good duo.
My hands are so wet.
I can't even get this on.
Meeting Noelle was really cool.
I-I wanted to meet her seeing
that she had, obviously, one leg
'cause there's a huge story
behind that,
and I love to hear those things.
In high school,
my best friend lost his leg.
At first I was like, "Oh.
That's the end of the world,"
and then, it progressed to...
You know,
he's up in heaven with us now,
and he's watching over me
right now
here on the game
of Survivor, but
that really changed
the way I live my life.
You're, like,
living a dream life, Cody.
Was there a moment
that spread that,
or, like,
have you always been that way?
Uh, I've been pretty, like,
crazy my whole life.
But, like, for me,
part of, like, my drive is,
I had a high school friend
die of cancer.
And then, like,
a year later, he passed.
I grew up
in a small town in Iowa.
A thousand people in my town,
28 kids in my graduating class.
With that small of a school,
we're all pretty tight.
And I realized when Devon died
that life was very fragile.
I really had
to watch him struggle.
And I think that's-that's why it
affected me as much as it did.
At that age,
to have to watch how vicious
life can be to someone
that doesn't deserve it--
that made it really,
really tough.
But it put things
into perspective, and
without that experience,
I wouldn't be...
I wouldn't be here today.
I wouldn't...
I wouldn't reside in Hawaii.
I wouldn't have taken
some of the risks
that I have taken in my life.
So I'm gonna play Survivor
as hard and as fast as I can,
just like I do in my life.
I ain't letting a day
go by out here
without really living.
There's not a day
I'm gonna let go
that I can't go to bed
and be like,
"I had a good time today."
My friends back home describe
me sometimes as a, uh...
a lovable curmudgeon,
and I'm trying
to keep the curmudgeon
under wraps.
I've tried to be
a bit more measured, and I think
all my friends at home
are gonna
be very proud of how
much I've held it together
to this point.
Aah!
Someone had to do it
'cause these fools don't like
drinking water that much.
But I'm fine. I'm fine.
I don't need... Yes, you do.
I feel like the next vote
is gonna be a really tough one.
I feel like you and me need
to be thinking about, like,
who would be a safe bet
for a vote.
- You know?
- Yes, for sure.
Going to Tribal kicked things
into gear,
and really forced us
to now be in game mode.
So I've been talking strategy
with Elie.
Obviously, we've been close
from the start.
And we have our pick
of whether we want to bring in
Owen or Sami as our third.
Who do you feel close with
outside of this?
I think, at first, Owen,
but maybe more recently,
Sami, only because
Owen's gonna be a lot
to manage, like,
once we get to the merge.
I feel a little bit like
Sami and Owen are my children.
Sami is my firstborn, and
he came out really independent,
and, you know, strong-willed.
He can kind of take charge
and doesn't need
a lot of tending to.
And Owen is, like,
my baby boy, my second born.
Even though he's older, he needs
a lot more attention, and so,
he's the more
high-maintenance child
in this situation.
If you need to take a break,
you can take a break.
Okay? So the frustration
- makes it harder, right?
Okay. Yeah.
I know.
I'm so confused about it.
Are they doing something
that we're just not seeing?
This foot seems worse
than the other one.
Mine are equally pruning
and gross right now.
You guys know
who Patrick Mahomes is?
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
- I'm Patrick Mahomes.
Dude, you're rocking
his haircut. Yeah.
You look like him, yeah.
You kind of look
like him, man. Geez.
But I think that it's opened the
door for the two of us to be,
like, strategic incognito.
I wonder
if they're talking about us.
You got to take it
into consideration.
- They do seem pretty close.
- Hmm.
But here's the dealio.
It doesn't matter.
- One, two, three.
- Yeah.
- It's true.
The guys need
to look out for each other
in the event
that this thing goes south
and those girls stick together.
Because those girls
will vote together
to the very end of this game.
And I think that the best way
for me to go right now
is with Gabler and Owen.
If they try
to pull something funny
and pull aside any one of us...
Then we know what to do.
I genuinely hope
- it doesn't come to that.
- I hope it doesn't, too.
- But the game's on now.
- The game is on.
- Yeah.
We got to look out
for each other.
I got you boys always.
I'm not the kind of person
that enjoys the whole guys
or girls alliance, or...
I don't-I don't think
that alliances should be based
off of that,
but I think me, Gabler
and Owen are being
completely underestimated
by the women altogether.
So, we have to be able to look
out for each other 'cause
we have the numbers,
and we will be stupid
to lose to them.
Come on in.
Vesi, Coco,
getting your first look
at the new Baka tribe.
Morriah voted out
at the first Tribal Council.
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- Let's go.
First things first.
Got to take back the idols.
- It's coming back.
- With Coco.
- Just win it back.
- That's the plan.
Thank you.
All right, once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna dive into the
ocean and swim to a tall cage.
You then have
to get up and over the cage
to release a very heavy snake.
You then have to get that snake
out of the cage,
drag it to a table
where you will release
number tiles.
You'll use those tiles
to solve a combination lock.
Then two players will race
to solve a massive
Survivor puzzle.
First two tribes to finish win
immunity, safe from the vote.
You're also playing for reward.
Want to know
what you're playing for?
- Yes, sir, Jeff.
- Yes, Jeff.
- First tribe to finish.
- Oh, my God.
A complete Survivor fishing kit.
Second tribe to finish--
it's smaller,
but it'll get the job done.
Hey, it still works.
Last tribe to finish,
otherwise known as the losers--
Tribal Council tonight
where somebody will be
the second person
voted out of this game.
And as a penalty for losing,
I will take your flint. Baka,
you're playing today
to get yours back.
All right, we have sit-outs.
Vesi, who's gonna be
the sit-out?
Get us this fishing gear.
- I am.
- Noelle's gonna
sit this one out.
Coco, who's it gonna be?
I'm sitting out.
Karla's gonna sit up.
All right.
Sit-outs take spot on the bench.
Everybody else,
give you a minute strategize
and we will get going.
All right, here we go.
For immunity
and reward,
Survivors ready?
- Go!
- Go, Vesi!
- Let's go, Coco!
Everybody's swimming quickly.
You got to get all five players
to that first edge of the gate
before you can
start heading over.
Coco, you're good.
Baka, you're good.
- Vesi, you're good.
- Let's go, James!
Let's go, Ryan! Good job!
You cannot go through the cage.
You've got to go up and over.
Here we go, Vesi!
Now you got
to untie that snake and start
working it over
the other side of the cage.
You can ask people
on either side of that gate
to push or pull that snake
once you have it untied.
Cody now starting
to lift for Vesi.
That is 400 pounds
of Survivor snake.
Let's go!
You are trying
to maneuver all the way
- to the top
through to the other side.
- One, two, three.
- Go, Coco!
Vesi doing a nice job
working together.
Coco trying
to get that snake up.
You can see
how heavy the snake is.
- You can't let go
once you get it up top.
-
It is Baka now in the lead.
- Vesi...
- Way to go, Vesi!
- making progress.
- Lift up.
Lindsay hanging from the snake.
Ryan, one pull at a time,
is pulling that snake
over the edge.
- Good job!
Cody trying
to just wrestle it down.
Baka has their snake.
Now you got to
get everybody over.
There goes Ryan,
very close to the end.
Let's go!
There's Gabler.
You're good, Baka.
- Coco has their snake.
- All right.
Cody is literally hanging on
to the snake
like he's riding it.
Go!
You're good, Coco.
Start heading in.
It is Baka in the lead,
followed by Coco.
- Good job!
- Vesi very close.
- One big pull.
There you go, Vesi!
Okay, here we go!
Get over, Jesse.
You're good.
Start heading in.
Let's go, Coco!
You got this. Come on.
It's very close--
Baka and Coco.
Vesi coming behind.
Now you've got
to go under a barrier
which will also be tough 'cause
you're dragging the snake down.
You're still in this, Vesi.
Let's go. Dig now!
One.
Baka into the next stage.
Coco right on their tail. Sometimes
it comes down to seconds,
which is why
you're digging all the time.
One, two, three, go.
- One, two.
You got to get that snake
all the way
to the end of your table.
It is Baka, Coco and then Vesi.
Vesi slowly gaining
on both tribes.
- Right there.
- Come on, push!
There you go! Start untying.
You're looking
for the six tiles.
Three of them have numbers.
That's how you do it, Coco.
Keep pulling.
One more big pull.
Start untying.
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Baka has their number tile.
It's gonna be Owen and Sami.
- Once we're free, we're good.
- Lindsay, free...
- What's wrong?
- Vesi, you got
to keep digging.
What happened?
Vesi completely came to a stop.
Baka solves their combination.
They're good.
You got Jeanine and Elie
for Baka. No, no.
Give 'em that. Not you. Go.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Got to get that open.
There's a piece inside
you need for that puzzle.
Coco has their number tiles.
Geo and Ryan
opening that combination.
There we go! There we go!
There you go! Start untying!
There's a piece
by Jeanine and Elie.
Coco solves their combination.
They can start
working on the puzzle.
You got Lindsay
and Cassidy for Coco.
You're right there, Coco!
Yup. Let's go! Let's go!
Okay.
Jeanine and Elie for Baka.
Vesi has their number tiles.
- Let's go, Vesi!
- No. That's gonna be up...
There. Yeah, yeah. Just...
There it is.
Another piece by Elie.
Vesi solves their combination.
They can start working
- on the puzzle.
- Great job, Elie.
Now gonna be Nneka
and Dwight on the puzzle.
- Right now, Vesi!
- Right now,
it is Coco and Baka
- side by side.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah.
Then Vesi trying
to get back in this.
There you go, Nneka.
Two tribes will be safe.
Two tribes will stay intact.
One will go to Tribal
and lose a tribe member.
- Nice.
- Vesi, you're in this.
There are comebacks
in Survivor all the time.
- Ryan?
- Right there. Good job.
You need to get
that bottom part.
- Okay, we need one like that?
- Hell, yes.
- Good job.
Vesi once again dead still.
It's becoming a theme
in this challenge.
They get some momentum,
then they stop, talk, rest.
You guys, we can't give up.
Come on.
I'm not.
I'm not, I'm just thinking.
You can't rest
on Survivor, ever.
You sleep
when you get back home.
And I don't mean your camp.
I mean back home.
Coco is closing the gap on Baka.
We got a challenge right now.
- There you go. Good.
- We're good.
It is Vesi in dead last,
looking at the Tribal Council
right now.
- Flip it over, Nneka,
and look at that. Yeah.
- They are stuck.
- Can't find the pieces
they need.
- Yeah.
Nneka, stay down, stay down.
- No! Turn!
- They don't even know
if they have the right piece.
- It's right there!
- It is Baka and Coco
side by side, piece by piece.
Vesi still moving
in slow motion.
Elie shoving her arm
through one of the openings
to get it in there.
Wow. We are really close.
Baka down to their last piece.
Careful, guys. Careful.
Jeanine and Elie.
Redemption for Jeanine.
They've got it!
Baka wins immunity.
Safe tonight
from Tribal Council.
Big fishing gear as well, and
they earned their flint back.
This one's over. You can put it
to deep freeze.
Vesi's out of it.
The last piece by Lindsay...
- That's got to be it.
- for the win.
Whoa.
And they got it.
Coco wins immunity,
safe from Tribal Council,
sending Vesi to Tribal Council
where the second person will be
voted out of Survivor 43.
That was the piece. That was the
small one that goes right there.
Damn.
All right, hard fought.
- Ah.
- Baka.
- Coco.
Yeah, my baby.
Baka, no Tribal Council tonight,
nobody going home.
Large fishing gear will be
waiting for you
back at your camp.
Well done.
- In addition,
you earned back your flint.
No, I can't catch [bleep].
Coco, Nicely done. No Tribal
Council tonight for you.
Nobody going home.
Smaller fishing gear
will be waiting
- for you back at camp.
- We'll take it.
- Thanks, Jeff! Let's go.
Baka, grab your stuff, head out.
Enjoy the night off.
- JEANINE and ELIE: Thanks, Jeff.
- Well earned.
Thank you, Jeff.
Cody, how many steps
before you're into your camp,
strategy kicks in,
and people start
splitting off to talk?
- 20.
- So quickly?
I think so. I mean,
the parade's over, man.
It's hunt
or be hunted at this point.
Everybody's got
to go to Tribal, and,
unfortunately, one member of our
family is gonna have to go.
Nowhere to hide in a dangerous
game, and there's
very little room to hide when
there's only six tribe members.
Tribal Council tonight, Vesi.
Somebody will be the second
person voted out of this game.
And as a penalty for losing,
I got to take your flint.
Sorry for you.
You'll have a chance to win it
back in the next challenge.
Grab your stuff, head out.
See you tonight
at Tribal Council.
It sucked
watching from the sidelines.
I'm a competitor.
I came out here not wanting
to sit out any challenges,
but now it turns out
that Nneka's not great
at jumping off things.
She's not great at puzzles.
I'm so sick of it.
I just want
to have a strong, united group.
So if we're gonna keep the
tribe strong, Nneka's got to go.
Gave it all we got.
Leaving that piece,
none of us caught it.
We all sat there
and watched the whole thing,
and none of us caught it.
So I don't know.
We can learn from our losses,
but, uh, tonight's gonna
be tragic. This sucks.
Today's challenge was a beast,
and we got our butts kicked.
Now we're gonna Tribal,
someone's going home,
and you're gonna have to
cut somebody
from your own ohana.
And it's heartbreaking.
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
Me and Nneka, we're very close.
I love Nneka's energy.
She's got a positive attitude,
and we have a strong alliance.
Unfortunately, she really
struggled in the challenge.
So for some people,
it could be Nneka
on the chopping block,
because keeping the tribe strong
is important.
But I'm not
gonna let that happen.
Every time I looked down,
she was just in the water,
- sitting there.
- She was in the water,
and, like...
I'm pissed, because I would
have kept this leg on.
And I, like,
I would have been able to lift.
And also, when Cody said
that was all of our faults
that the puzzle piece
was in the bag.
- She grabbed the bag.
- Especially, yeah.
- That's your responsibility.
- Yeah.
Nneka has been
great around camp,
but judging
by this challenge, um,
I just feel like every time
I was looking at her,
she's wasn't really
pulling her weight.
- I don't know.
- Yeah, we need
to talk to the boys.
Yeah. We need
to talk to everybody.
Nneka does contribute
a lot around camp,
but we just need to think
what's gonna get us
further in this game.
And voting out Nneka
is probably the best way
to keep the tribe strong.
- Oh.
- We know what that means.
All right. Well...
After the challenge,
it was a very different vibe.
I mean, we've had a good kumbaya
thing going in the tribe,
but today, people talk to you,
they're not making eye contact.
And I'm not surprised,
because I did not do well
in the challenge.
So there is a chance
that it could be me tonight.
Talking about
the stupid challenge
and the other tribes probably
eating freaking fish tonight.
However, Cody and I
are super close,
and Jesse and I have
been getting along really well.
So hopefully the relationships
I've built in this game
are something I can count on.
Oh, my God.
It feels amazing to win.
Not only did we win immunity,
but it was a reward challenge,
so we won fishing gear.
Oh, my God! There's two.
Which is so crucial,
because the entire tribe
has not been eating
anything but coconuts.
So to be able to get a different
source of protein is invaluable.
- I'm so proud of us.
- I'm-I'm so proud of us.
- You guys...
I was actually in shock.
And then it hit me,
and I was like,
"Aah!"
I feel really proud of myself.
It makes me a little tearful,
like...
I did that,
and that was something that
came from my brain, and...
I underestimate that a lot.
Growing up,
I had ADHD and I had dyslexia.
And so before I was diagnosed,
teachers just assumed that
I was lazy and didn't care.
I would get one of those timed
quizzes sit in front of me,
and I would freeze up so bad,
I just couldn't think.
I would only answer,
like, two or three questions.
And, you know, we have to swap
and grade each other's papers.
And the person next to me
always knew how bad I had done.
And that kind of talk
gets around quickly.
So I grew up being told
I was dumb--
by my teachers, by the people
who are supposed to help you.
Basically everybody but my mom
and dad told me that I was
not going anywhere
and that I couldn't do
the things that I wanted to do.
And so, it takes
an experience like this
to really shed that.
A doctoral degree couldn't even
shed me of this feeling
that I'm not smart enough.
But today,
I looked at that puzzle,
and I was like,
"Dang, girl, you're bright."
Have you guys worked
with that gear before?
- The-the spear and the...
- A spear?
- No.
- Oh, I have an idea.
Do you want to tie
a really long rope around it?
We don't need that.
I'm gonna be holding on to it.
If we're just walking out there,
I can hold on to it.
- We're just gonna be
holding on to this...
- Also, it's...
- You're gonna hold on to...
No, for when you release it.
- So that's...
- when you release it.
- That you can catch it...
- without having to,
without having to cut it short.
- We can shoot it into the sand.
Shoot it into the sand.
All right,
do whatever you want to do.
Gabler has some
spearfishing experience,
which I very much appreciate.
All right, bud, let's go see
what we can get into.
However, he has not
ever used a Hawaiian sling.
There it is. One short one.
Like that.
This guy
you swing around like this.
You guys are ready
for your fish.
It's a big, blue frickin' ocean
out there.
When I think of
soaring off into oblivion
and completely misses the fish,
we might be out a spear.
Wow.
Good news is
next Tribal we have to go to
we don't have to
deal with that idol.
- I'm just, I...
- I think that it's invalid now.
- Oh, yeah. I think so. Yeah.
- But we're just trying,
but we're trying to verify that.
A big topic of discussion
has been whether or not
Gabler's idol expires after
the first two Tribal Councils
in the game or after Gabler's
first two Tribal Councils.
We want to look at the clue
again without being weird
and being like,
"Can we read your clue?"
It said the next
two Tribal Councils...
But are you sure?
I am sure that's what it said.
We were hoping
that after tonight,
even though we're not
going to Tribal Council,
that the immunity idol
that he had would expire.
Okay.
I always thought it was so wack
when people went through
each other's bags on Survivor.
I thought it was just
lying, cheating,
you know, unfair.
But it's so different coming
here, understanding that
those are necessary deeds.
- Hey, Owen.
- Yes, sir.
Do we have any coconut left?
There's a tiny bit on there.
Okay, cool.
Hopefully this is
the last of this I eat.
I don't like it, man.
I thought I'd like coconut more.
In my daily life, I don't lie,
I don't cheat.
I really am an honest person.
But everything changes
when you're in this game,
because anything you can do
to give yourself an advantage
is fair game.
Oh, it was in that shell thing.
- It was in the shell?
- That's where
the idol itself was.
I'm, like,
95% confident
it's no good anymore.
I found it.
Okay.
- Obviously, it's still good.
- After that, it loses all power.
- So he still has to stay around
for the next one.
- Okay.
- Okay. Yeah.
- It's good we read it.
I have confirmed my worst fear
that Gabler's idol
is still in play.
So that complicates things,
because if he plays his idol--
which I think
we have to assume he will--
and he throws my name out,
I'm gone.
Our game plan right now
is to get Nneka out.
We know that
Dwight doesn't have a vote,
so obviously
Jesse is a key person here,
because if Jesse is with us
and Nneka plays
her Shot in the Dark,
we can split our votes on Cody.
I've always gotten
really good vibes from Jesse.
I feel like he's being
genuine with us,
but there is that little
inkling in the back of your head
of, like, how do I know
100% that you're actually
on our side, and we're
not the ones getting played?
While Nneka might be a challenge
liability going forward,
I think Justine
is a bigger threat to my game.
She seems smart,
She seems calculating,
and like Cody said, "You can
never trust a salesperson."
But also, the other day,
she just openly told me
that she's really good at lying.
We need to come up
with a decoy to tell 'em.
I'll talk to Nneka.
I'll do some acting.
- I have a good, like,
lying face.
I can keep a straight face.
I mean, she's scary.
So I've always got,
like, this stereotype of...
Yeah.
Justine's a threat.
Like, she seems sort of lethal.
So I think voting out Justine
right now is the right move,
but I really want to get on
the same page with Dwight.
- Me and you,
I-I feel like we're tight.
- Yeah.
Think we're solid like that.
And I think, like, we're in
the middle of these two pairs.
- Yeah.
- And we have to figure out
which way is best.
No, no, no, no...
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
So...
...is Justine
is a little bit scary to me.
- I'm not gonna lie to you.
She's a little bit scary.
- Yeah.
Like, earlier,
she was telling me, she's like,
she's like,
"I'm really good at lying."
And I was like, "What?
Why would you say that to me?"
And that's what scares me.
So...
- I-I...
- Cody is, honestly,
he's like, "Oh, Dwight is, like,
solid. He's great."
So I run the idea
of voting Justine off to Dwight,
and he wasn't too receptive.
I could just get the vibes
that he didn't want to do that.
He still wanted to sort of
work with the girls,
which is kind of troubling
to me, because, you know,
then he has
these other options, right?
But the thing is,
he doesn't have a vote.
So is there any way for you...
- Spiders.
Yeah...
- How are you guys?
- We're good.
- Yeah.
- I mean...
Nneka thinks it's her.
- Uh-huh.
- I mean,
that's who I'm voting.
But how do we know
that you're not playing us?
You're the swing vote here.
I just want to know.
You're good. You're good.
- I swear.
- We've been
walking all day...
Yeah.
The fact that she came up to me
and was like, "I don't know
if I trust you, pretty much."
Like, that for me,
I got to take that out.
I can't have that.
I really can't.
I would like to sort of
be on the same page as Dwight,
but if push comes to shove,
I'm gonna do what's best for me.
The plan is Nneka?
- Yeah. Do you guys agree?
- Yeah.
Jesse really wants
to vote out Justine,
but that's not what I want.
I feel like,
with Justine and Noelle here,
I have a lot more options
going forward.
I have no vote.
I really have no say in this,
but we have
to keep the tribe strong.
So, unfortunately,
Nneka needs to go.
Justine is worried
that it's between you and her.
So she has an inkling that
we're going after her as well.
- J-U-S-T-I-N-E?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- Hey, man,
spelling wasn't my best.
My standardized score in, like,
vocabulary and English
- was quite low.
We got it all settled.
We're all good.
We're just ready to go
to Tribal and vote out Justine.
And I decide to take
a little bit of a walk,
'cause Survivor. Why not?
Got nothing else to do.
Plus, it'd be nice
to have an idol.
My eyes are peeled.
I think I'm good
at that kind of stuff.
Always have been.
I used to go hunting
for night crawlers at night.
So we'd go fishing.
Mushroom hunting in the spring.
Easter egg hunting as a kid.
I was a legend at it.
Just bird doo-doo.
But this looks easier on TV.
That's for sure.
I haven't looked for an idol
because I believe that
that is a kiss of death.
But we're
going to Tribal Council,
and that changes everything.
I'm walking around forever,
and I'm finding nothing.
And I'm about to say
"to hell with it."
And then I walk up to this,
like, stump,
and bingo. I got it.
And I was like, "Holy moly."
I was so stoked.
I saw season 41 and 42,
but the L-I-V-I-N that was
tattooed on me is in my blood,
so, like, the "beware" part,
like, it didn't even exist.
Like, I just said, "Open it."
Tonight was a slam dunk,
we were ready to rock,
and now
this leaves both me and Dwight
without a vote.
So, Justine and Noelle
are voting for Nneka.
And Nneka and Jesse
will be voting for Justine.
Tie. Fantastic.
... just got crazy.
Opening up the Beware Advantage
was a huge mistake,
because if I don't get
a specific bead
off of each person's bag,
I don't have a vote.
And we'd guarantee
gonna a tie.
I need to go get my stuff
that was drying.
I'm gonna hang mine up.
And getting these beads from
my tribemates is going to be
damn near impossible,
because they're all superfans,
and these things
are like gold to them.
Like, the whole
Survivor experience--
the bags, the water bottles--
are like gold.
And there's minutes
left on the clock.
So I got to talk to Jesse.
And I lost...
How am I gonna
convince anybody?
- I can get yours.
- Yeah, you can get mine.
For sure. Yeah, yeah, no...
But then Dwight's,
like, all about it.
I shouldn't have grabbed it.
It was so stupid.
We were set just perfect.
Cody found the Beware Advantage
and he just opened it,
right before Tribal.
I don't know if he hasn't seen,
like, season 41 or season 42
or something, but,
like, you know
you're gonna lose your vote
unless you do something.
It's absolute panic.
You got people losing
their votes, people who didn't
have their votes to begin with.
It's just chaos right now.
Guys think I should
wear my hat tonight?
- Absolutely.
- Right?
Like, really ... rip it.
- It'd be a legend move.
- Yeah.
Palm frond hat.
It'll pop, you know?
That'll be beautiful on here,
you know?
I want to connect it.
Sweet.
- I'll put it right there.
Maybe, like, weave it
into the palm fronds.
Can I have yours off your bag
to wrap it around?
Sure. I'm not gonna
do anything with it.
You can take my beads
off of my bag.
Yeah, you can take mine off.
Immediately, Justine--
who doesn't know she's on the
chopping block-- was like,
"Yeah, you can have mine, too."
I'm like, "Whoa.
This is actually working."
- Hey, Dwight?
- What's up?
You want to put your beads
in this?
Dwight, you should give Cody
the beads from your bag.
From my bag?
He's trying to string it
all around.
All around?
I don't know. I mean...
Oh, come on.
All right.
I thought that Dwight was
gonna be very difficult,
but he took it
right off his bag.
Aw, that's awesome.
Of course.
Mm-hmm?
'Cause. I think they're cool.
Pretty.
I made a bracelet.
Noelle-- there's no way she's
parting with any of this stuff.
So I'm freaking.
I feel like an actual castaway
on Survivor
with my Survivor beads.
There are so many moving pieces.
The sun's setting.
Tribal's upon us.
I mean,
this new game of Survivor--
it's just
absolute freaking chaos.
Yeah.
I mean, there's so many
different possibilities
for this Tribal, so we
got to be ready for anything,
because it's gonna be crazy.
Behind you are some torches.
Everybody grab a torch.
Dip it in and get fire.
This is part of the ritual
of Tribal Council,
because in this game,
as you know,
fire represents your life.
And when your fire is gone,
so are you. And as much as
I hate for any of you to leave,
that's the stakes.
Did you feel that, Cody,
when you got back to camp--
that realization that it's on?
"One of us
is going home tonight."
Oh, automatic. Guarantee.
I mean, two days ago, we won
our first immunity challenge,
and we had dropped
into the wave of our lifetime.
And we rode it up until today.
And unfortunately, someone
is going to wipe out tonight
and have a end
to their Survivor story.
Cody, got to ask:
did you weave these palm fronds,
- this hat?
- Yeah.
Learned it from the uncles
that sell 'em to tourists
- on, uh, the island of Oahu.
- For real?
- Absolutely.
- Huh.
So, figuring that today
could be my last day,
I wanted to rock it and, uh,
give the people what they want,
show 'em this beautiful hat.
And with the help
of my tribe, we, uh...
you know, made it real nice and
fancy and put some beads on it.
It's pretty impressive.
- Oh, yeah.
- It's like
a full-on visor.
And I actually am
very down for a hat.
Like, today I was squinting
in the sun. I wish I had a hat.
So, Cody, what will it take for
you to make a hat for Justine?
I mean,
it's gonna have to take
for her to stay for another day,
and, uh, unfortunately,
I don't have that sole power
to do so. It-it's a tribe thing.
And, um, whoever goes home,
I'll be happy to get you a hat.
- I can promise you that.
Wow.
Just a simple comment
about a hat.
And then Cody has to say,
"Great.
If you survive,
I'll make you one."
Yeah, I mean, I personally know
that tonight
could be my last night.
- Based on what?
- Well,
Noelle and I
hit it off immediately,
so that puts us two together.
Dwight and Jesse are kind of in,
you know, no-man's-land.
We don't really know
where they stand at this point.
And then it really seems
like Nneka and Cody
have been hitting it off
as well. So it kind of
breaks our six up into two,
two and two.
- Hmm.
- But I think
that the strongest two
that we know are together
are Nneka and Cody.
And on top of that, I'm the only
person that hasn't really
talked game or strategy
with Cody.
So I think that puts
an extra target on my back.
Okay, so, Dwight,
this is what I just heard
Justine say.
Her and Noelle are paired.
She thinks Cody and Nneka
seem to be hitting it off,
but you two-- they don't
know if you're together
or you're both lost
or you haven't figured out
- what you're doing.
Is that what you just heard?
- Yeah, I'm not sure.
Are we together now?
- You want to make this official?
- Absolutely.
Thank you so much, sir.
- We're together now. Um...
- So wait, is that real?
Are there three pairs?
Um, the strategy talks,
up until this afternoon,
have been very limited.
It also has kind of been
difficult for me,
because I think
it's common knowledge here,
I got on the boat day two,
and I lost my vote
in a decision.
So it's kind of been difficult
for me to have strategy talk
if I don't actually have
a concrete say
in this Tribal Council.
How does everybody know
you don't have a vote?
I came back and I was
very honest with my tribe,
told them what kind of
decision I made, lost my vote.
And I got to live
with the consequences of that.
Jesse, I'm sure you
think this at times,
when you watch the show.
I hear it all the time.
"Probst, why does everybody
tell everybody everything?"
And I try to explain
that it's about currency,
and trust is really
the only currency you have.
Is that what it is for you,
as well?
Yeah, I think that's the case.
I mean, back at home, like,
when, you know, I'm trying
to sort of, like, build
relationships with people--
which aren't very many.
Again, it's just me,
my wife and kids.
But, like, in social settings,
I will, you know, go one-on-one
and, like, share my background
with people.
I will tell people, you know,
that I did get jumped
into a gang as a teenager.
It's about sort of building
trust and, like, opening
that door, and I think when
you're authentic with people,
they're authentic back.
Nneka, when you watch Survivor,
do you ever scratch your head
at why players share all their
advantages or disadvantages?
Jeff, have you hung out
with Nigerians at all?
We are, like, ultra-passionate.
You need to see us watch
Survivor at home sometimes.
Like, we will be
on the coffee table,
screaming at the TV.
"No, I should've done this.
No, I shouldn't have done this.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah."
Like, "You know what?
I'm gonna go on Survivor.
I'll show you all."
So, Nneka, Dwight brought up,
"Hey, I went out.
I lost my vote."
Did that open the gates
for everybody to have
a discussion about whether
or not there's other advantages
or idols that
might be in the game?
Um, no, I think that,
on the one hand, yes,
maybe there's an idol
for this season.
But if we look at
the last couple of seasons,
like the Beware Advantage,
you want to think, like,
"Okay, if I find this,
will it really help me right now
"or is it something that
will get your hands tied
in whatever way?"
And that's just a tough part,
because you just never know
if there even is an advantage
or an idol
on our island, because,
unless everybody's lying to me,
nobody's sharing.
So they're either
playing a really great game
or nobody actually
has found anything.
So, Cody, what kind of impact
does that
have, knowing one
of only six players
says they won't
be voting tonight?
It's enormous. I mean,
not having a vote
can break up an alliance.
You know, Dwight doing that.
Well, they only got one vote,
you know?
It makes an easy target.
But hopefully for him
or Jesse or whoever else here,
it's not gonna be
the-the dagger in the back
that really
causes them to go home.
And that's
a tough decision because
not one person has done
anything wrong on this tribe.
Nobody deserves
to be going home tonight.
But then, on the other hand, we
need to keep the tribe strong.
We need to be winning
these next immunity challenges,
because I don't want
to be sitting here again.
Jesse, that really gets at
the heart of where the game is
for each player,
and that is,
"I care about tribe strength.
I don't want
to lose another challenge."
Or, "I just need to make sure
my alliance is strong
and as long as I'm here,
I'm good with that."
Yeah, I mean, I think that
it's a big dilemma.
I can't say, like,
which one is more important.
I think that's
a really hard thing to decide.
But we do develop
these relationships.
We have these emotions
that are involved,
but at the end of the day,
we do have to sort of
set them aside
and-and play the game.
All right, it is time to vote.
Justine, you're up.
I'll go tally the votes.
If anybody has
an advantage or an idol
and they want to play it,
now would be
the time to do so.
All right, I'll read the votes.
First vote: Justine.
Nneka.
Cody.
That's one vote Cody,
one vote Justine,
one vote Nneka.
Justine.
Two votes Justine,
one vote Nneka,
one vote Cody,
one vote left.
Right before Tribal
was easily the most craziest
emotional ride
I've ever been on.
It was terrifying.
But thanks to Nneka and Jesse,
I got the beads
just in the nick of time
to take off to Tribal Council.
Second person
voted out of Survivor 43:
Justine.
Need to bring me your torch.
Justine, the tribe has spoken.
Time for you to go.
- Love you, girl.
- Love you, guys.
Love you.
- Bye, Justine.
- Bye.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
Good night.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
-♪ Happy birthday to you.♪
- We're building
a community here.
Till we
slit each other's throats.
The island marriage
is a bit strained.
He's sleeping on the couch.
I'll sign the divorce papers.
It's okay.
My ally was snooping around.
She's next.
I got completely hoodwinked
by Jesse, which sucks.
Jesse was very visibly
playing both sides,
but I feel sad
about leaving this family.
I'm still rooting for Vesi.
My dream was to be on Survivor,
and I'm gonna
take it for what it is.
I had an amazing time out here.
I'm so lucky to be on this show,
so I'm walking away
with a smile on my face.