Honestly, I appreciate
every single one of you.
I know she meant a lot to--
I mean, she meant
a lot to all of us.
- We believe in you. So...
- Thank you.
I love you guys.
- Let's do it.
- Love you guys.
Nneka and I had a very good
alliance, and I voted for her.
So coming back from Tribal
was like
my girlfriend dumped me,
and the pizza guy that I ordered
pizza from didn't show up,
and my roommate drank
all the beer in the fridge.
It was just brutal.
We have no flint,
no food, no fire,
and we've lost
two challenges in a row.
We are in dead last,
and it is crunch time.
We need to kick some butt
and, uh, get back on track.
Come on, guys. This is Survivor.
Like, this is showtime.
Let's go.
I don't know.
I don't want it.
Oh. Thanks, dude.
This is Gabler.
This is Mike Gabler personified,
out here on Survivor.
I love the guy,
and at this point,
we're working together, collaborating,
but sometimes he's not aware.
Oh, yeah, such a nice blanket.
Survivor is more than a game.
You're living with these people,
so it becomes really tricky when
you get under each other's skin
a little bit
or you touch nerves.
Was the palm frond
at all helpful?
No. You woke me up.
- I was asleep.
- Oh, sorry.
We don't want to have to
walk on eggshells
all the time, but we can't
be shocked when all of a sudden
we crack somebody's egg.
- Do you need little sticks?
That's gonna...
- We need a few more.
Put some more burl up in there,
it'll catch. Yeah.
Gabler's starting
to rub me the wrong way.
He's becoming a detriment
to potentially our game,
but honestly,
to our camp life as well.
These are way too big
to catch just off of that.
- Two seconds will burn that.
- Oh, yeah, for sure.
Well, the problem is
all the fire's blowing this way.
It's not coming up.
What does that have to do
with the size of the sticks?
There's some
small sticks in there.
- All right.
No, it totally worked.
- But we need more. More.
- Hey, Elie. Okay, I know.
- I'm sorry, I'm frustrated...
- Well, you're not helping.
- And your way didn't work,
and so maybe
we try little sticks.
Okay. Then go get more.
- You do it. That's right.
Just go ahead and do it.
- I am literally doing it.
Elie's a very
strong personality.
I'm a very strong personality.
The two of us clash.
On top of that,
I don't trust her at all,
because she already rummaged
through my bag to read my idol.
If we get too far with her,
we will all regret it.
Come on in.
Howdy, Jeff.
Well, good morning, Coco.
Jeff.
Let me just quickly
take attendance.
Okay, there's Lindsay.
Cassidy's here. Geo.
- Good morning, Baka.
- Good morning.
- How are you, Jeff?
Coco and Baka,
getting your first look
at the new Vesi tribe.
Nneka voted out
at the last Tribal Council.
All right, shall we get
to today's reward challenge?
Yeah!
For today's challenge,
one player from each tribe
is gonna use sandbags
to knock blocks off a ledge.
That same player will then
walk on two of the blocks
to get to the finish,
where the three remaining
tribe members must each land
one sandbag
on one of the hanging discs.
First tribe to finish
wins reward.
- Want to know
what you're playing for?
- Yeah.
Today, it's a winner take all.
First tribe to finish
will have ten fresh fish
- delivered to your camp.
- Sweet.
In addition, the winning tribe
earns the right
to go to one of
the other two tribe camps
and steal one item.
Oh, yeah.
Oh.
All right, Coco,
you have two extra members.
Sitting two people out.
- I'm out, Jeff.
- James is out.
Lindsay's out.
Baka, you have one extra person.
- I can sit out.
- Elie's
gonna sit out for Baka.
Everybody else,
give you a minute to strategize.
We'll get started.
Here we go.
Sit-outs, you're
heading over to the bench.
All right, here we go.
For reward.
Survivors ready?
- Go!
- Come on, Ryan.
Ryan.
It is Ryan, Sami and Cody.
You got to
knock all the blocks off.
That's the first phase.
Nice hit by Sami.
- Aah!
- Come on, come on, come on.
Go ahead.
Cody firing his sandbag.
Yeah. Yeah! Yeah!
Wow! Cody takes
half his stack off
- with one toss.
- Yeah! Let's go!
Vesi somehow now
with some fire in them.
- Let's go!
- After two back-to-back
immunity losses,
Cody is blistering
this course right now.
- Yeah!
- Looking like an MLB pitcher.
- There you go.
- Ryan with another toss.
Here goes Sami.
They're about to fall off.
- Yeah! One more!
- Sami on fire.
Cody, you're good.
Come forward.
Vesi in the lead.
They have not been
in this position very often.
Now, you can only use your feet,
and you got to move across
this hot lava.
That's it. All right.
You got a feel for it.
- Got to start again.
- You got a feel for it...
- Yes!
- Sami knocks his last block off.
Pick your two. Pick your two. Mediums.
It is now Cody and Sami.
You can only use your feet.
Cody really going for it.
Extending those blocks. Far out.
Go, Ryan! You got this!
Ryan with two more blocks.
Let's go, Coco!
- Cody is halfway there.
- Great job.
Sami right on his tail.
Nice job by Cody
getting past that log.
Yes! Let's go, Cody!
Very surprising
to see red ahead of anyone.
Could this be
a turning point for Vesi?
I'm gonna take my time.
- You're good.
- Great job. Take your time.
Cody very close to the finish.
You're good. Let's go!
Vesi through the first phase,
in the lead.
Let's go, guys. Let's go.
Let's go.
Sami trying
to keep Baka in this,
and Ryan
in dead last for Coco.
Slowly inching
that last block off.
And it drops.
Coco, you're good.
Go, Coco!
Jesse sticks it for Vesi.
Vesi has their first.
Sami's across.
Ryan working on those blocks.
- This is
a winner-take-all challenge.
- Let's go, Ryan.
Let's go!
Yeah!
Noelle does it. Wow.
Vesi is on fire.
Dwight for the win...
On and off.
Baka trying to get in it.
- Jeanine just misses.
- All right, you got it.
Dwight on and off.
These get
increasingly more difficult
because they get smaller.
So your target is tiny now
for Dwight.
Let's go!
Ryan has his two blocks.
You're good, Coco.
- Let's go!
- Coco is now gonna be in it.
Come on.
Oh. On and off for Dwight.
Geo comes in for Coco.
He has the first.
Coco's now in it.
Jeanine, she sticks it.
Baka with one,
Coco with one, Vesi with two.
All right, good job.
Dwight now feeling the pressure
of trying to win it right here.
And he does it!
Vesi wins reward!
Ten fish
and the opportunity
to steal one item
- from another tribe's camp.
- Yes! Yes!
Wow.
All right, Vesi.
You look
like a different tribe today.
Did you feel that, Noelle?
Absolutely, Jeff. You know,
we woke up this morning,
we were like, "Guns blazing.
We're tired of losing.
We want to eat."
We literally haven't eaten
anything other than coconut.
That's gonna change.
Ten fresh fish
delivered to your camp.
In addition,
you have earned the right
to go to either Baka or Coco
and take
any reward they've won--
their fishing gear
or their tool kit.
You could also take a pot.
You could take their machete.
The only thing off-limits
is a flint.
The question is, which tribe
are you gonna visit?
And what are you gonna take?
And we're gonna leave that
as a surprise for them.
Coco, Baka,
got nothing for you.
Grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
Go long.
All right, Vesi, what goes
through your mind on day eight?
You haven't had flint
in a long time.
You can't take their flint.
Do you have fire at your camp?
We do not, so, you know,
we're thinking,
you know, we're getting
all these ten beautiful fishes,
but how are we gonna eat 'em?
Are we allowed to trade reward?
Absolutely. You can always trade
- for a previous reward
and give up your fish.
- Yeah.
You still keep the camp raid.
That is a separate part.
- I think we should
do the tool kit...
- We could eat the fish raw.
I'm not eating ... fish raw, Cody.
- You don't eat sushi?
- No.
So lay it out, Noelle.
What are you gonna do?
So we are going
to trade our reward
and get the basket of fruit
and the tool kit.
All right. You'll have
the afternoon to figure out
which tribe you're visiting
and which tribe member
is going to make the visit--
- another big decision.
- Yeah.
All right, Vesi,
grab your stuff, head out.
Enjoy your afternoon. Congratulations.
Thanks, Jeff.
- Nice job, you guys. Yes.
- Gotta feel good to win.
We dominated the crap
out of that challenge.
Winning the camp raid,
I mean, it is huge.
We have all the power
in our hands.
You don't want
to piss too many people off,
but then I have to think,
you know, I'm playing
the game of Survivor.
It's a cutthroat freaking game.
We did it.
Oh.
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna start crying.
This is the best feeling
in this world.
That was so fun.
We've been
on a bit of a losing streak,
so it's extremely important
to turn things around.
And even though we won today,
there's no guarantees tomorrow.
And so, like, we win
this camp raid, and, like,
we do have to think about what's
gonna strengthen us the most
and what's gonna
weaken the other tribe.
Does anybody want to go?
- Yeah. Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
As far as, you know, making sure
they're not pissed off.
Yeah.
Cody's
an extremely likable guy.
He's probably gonna go over
there and make them all laugh,
but at the same time,
this is a strategic game.
Yeah, I'm not
going in there, like,
stomping out their fire
and kicking over their fort.
"Aah!"
- Oh, God.
- Sending Cody is truly
just a wild card move.
We don't know what he's
gonna do, what he's gonna say.
That's very scary.
All right,
who are we going after?
What if we go to the yellow
tribe and take the fishing line,
two spearguns, two goggles.
Like, a full fishing set.
If we're trying
to strengthen our tribe,
that's gonna strengthen
our tribe the most.
Honestly, I think they'd
be stupid to not come here.
We have the most stuff.
- Yeah.
- But they got
to look at the numbers, too.
Coco's strong. They're-they're
still their original six.
I think they're
smart enough to go for Baka.
I really hope they are.
Baka has bigger fishing gear,
bigger tool kit.
So I don't think we have
to worry about it anyway...
I don't think
Vesi's gonna come after Coco
because right now
they're hurting.
They haven't been eating.
And Baka has the big
fishing gear-- bigger than ours.
But at the same time,
this is
a very scary moment for us,
because it's the first time
that we lose,
actually.
We've never lost before.
If we're gonna piss off anybody,
I feel like we should
just piss off Coco.
Because they have six people.
It's five and six,
so it's not like
they have a huge advantage.
If we go to Coco, would you
want to take the fishing gear?
- Machete would be...
- Fishing gear.
I mean, can you imagine
without a machete?
- Fishing gear.
- You can't cut c-coconuts.
- You can't start a fire.
- I know,
but if we win tomorrow,
we get our flint back,
we go fishing. That's fuel.
If this was old Jesse,
growing up as a teenager,
like, in L.A., you know,
tattoo on my face,
I'd probably
go for the jugular,
be with Cody
and take the machete.
- Show no mercy.
- Listen...
But I live on a cul-de-sac now.
I, you know, I got to be
diplomatic with my neighbors.
And so, myself,
Noelle and Dwight are
against hitting the other tribes
as hard as possible.
And I don't think
anybody would do that to us.
You know?
Can we start the flint
with the saw?
Well, you know,
maybe the back of it.
Try it with
the front of the saw.
It's not great.
What I'm most worried about
is them taking
our pot and our machete, okay?
If they really want
to play games, do that,
then it's just war.
We're at war, man.
The idea of wiping a tribe out
with the take of a machete.
You got to think long-term,
not short-term.
This tribe's missing some grit.
For me, it's not
about what we're getting,
it's what we're inflicting,
because we have a tribe of four,
and they're
a tribe of six and five.
We are outnumbered.
We're tired, we're beat up.
I don't agree with this. I think
we're being soft as hell.
The only way
that we can close that gap
is to kick 'em
in the shins, man.
Really hit 'em hard.
God.
Sending a child off to school,
and I don't know
how he's gonna behave.
Yeah!
- Oh, my God.
- No way.
- No. No, no, no.
- No.
For real?
- Do you see that?
- I might go over there
and take their machete,
'cause I might be looking around
and be like, "To hell with it.
"You know what? I'm making
an executive decision here.
Taking out
their Achilles' heel."
- No, y'all.
- Oh, no.
No, y'all.
So they're coming for us?
- Yup.
- They really came for us.
Put my shoes back on.
- I had just gotten comfortable.
- Oh, my God.
- Hey.
- What's up, man?
- We don't
have anything. I'm sorry.
You're gonna have to go back.
We were hoping they would
go after Baka
because they're, like,
winning all the big rewards.
- Cody. My pleasure.
- Nice to meet you, Cody.
Nice to meet you.
So when they come to our camp,
I'm just thinking, like,
we still have
six people in this game,
they're down to four.
So they really want to give us,
like, a hard blow, I guess,
just because
we have the numbers right now.
This is pretty sweet.
Thanks. Take a look.
Yeah, you're
more than welcome...
Yeah, I actually came over here
to kick down the post,
to kick it over.
That's what he was stealing,
the structure of our home.
Oh, yeah, very nice.
Nice work.
- Sure.
- So how are
y'all eating your fish?
Are y'all doing,
like, sashimi, or...?
Ah, very funny.
What are you here for?
I, okay, so,
I came over to steal...
I came over
to steal your machete.
- And...
- What good does
an extra machete do for you?
- It's-it's-it's a savage take.
I agree with you 100%.
- Okay.
But you also understand the
message that it's sending to us,
and what we're prepared
to do in retaliation.
Right now, I just don't
want to lose the machete.
It's one of our
most useful tools.
So anything that we can do
to make Cody happy
- makes sense.
- I'm not the strategist
of the group. I'm the,
I'm, like, the messenger here.
So if you came back with, like,
some food, would that,
would-would that be enough?
Yeah.
I've done sales for 13 years,
and you don't
come into a negotiation
asking for what you want.
That's Sales 101.
So I told them I wanted their
machete. They didn't like that.
They started mumbling.
None of 'em knew what to do.
They were kind of like, "Well,
what else would you like?"
It was music to my ears.
At that point,
you know,
I was in the driver's seat.
So you're saying,
in lieu of the machete,
you'll give me some food?
- Yeah.
- A lot.
- What?
- At least.
- Yes.
- What?
- Yeah, we got limes.
Limes are great.
Let me see
your refrigerator, man.
- Look at this.
- Tastes like mashed potatoes.
Boil it up, it's good.
Listen,
I mean, it's a good offer,
and I really appreciate it,
but the thing is,
we don't have fire right now.
So it does us no good tonight.
We need something that will
give us a longer life cycle.
- Yeah.
What if we take, would you
give us the fishing gear
and a little bit of that?
What do you guys think?
It's a group decision.
- Is that a deal?
- I'm down for that.
- Yeah.
And some limes. Can I get
a couple limes? 'Cause, man...
- Yeah. All right, yeah.
- Please.
Let me guess,
you got tequila back there, too?
Now that would be something.
I turned on the charisma 110%,
and Coco went
right into my trap.
Man, thank you guys so much.
Yeah. Thank you
for not taking our machete.
It's a win-win.
I got more
than what I went for,
and Coco ended up extra happy,
because they were thinking
they were getting
their machete taken.
Yeah. You're gonna love it.
This is the winning root. Huh?
Mahalo.
I don't trust Cody at all.
He's like,
"Mahalo. Hawaii. I live
on the island of Hawaii."
And I'm like,
"Bro, you're from Idaho.
Like, calm down."
Aloha, y'all.
Coco definitely
did not play it cool.
We gave away our fishing gear
and too much food,
which strengthens the enemy.
I know.
We're so bad at negotiating.
I think Cody played us.
Yahoo!
Come on in.
All right.
- Shall we get to
today's immunity challenge?
- Yeah.
First things first,
got to take back the idols.
I know, Owen.
You don't want to give it up.
I do not.
King Coco.
Blessings, Jeff.
Once again, immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna race to knock
off a series of heavy sandbags.
You're looking
for a ring of keys.
You'll then use those keys
to unlock a net
and drag four large puzzle
pieces underneath the net.
You'll then arrange
those pieces in a square.
Once you have the square
finished, you're gonna take
the same pieces,
go up a cargo net
to another platform and
rearrange them into a triangle.
First two tribes
to finish win immunity.
Safe from the vote.
Losers, Tribal Council,
where somebody
will be the fourth person
voted out of Survivor 43.
Let's get to sit-outs.
Coco, you have two.
Cassidy and Geo are gonna
sit this out for Coco.
Baka, who's it gonna be?
Jeanine gonna sit out for Baka.
Sit-outs on the bench. Everybody
else, give you a minute
to strategize.
We'll get started.
All right, here we go.
For immunity.
Survivors ready?
- Go!
- Let's go, Coco!
You've got to go over
and get all the sandbags off.
And you're looking
for one ring with keys on it.
Go, Coco!
Boy, everybody is tearing it up!
Let's go, Baka!
On day nine of Survivor 43.
- Right there. Grab it,
grab it, grab it.
- Baka! Go, Baka!
Every second is going
to count in this challenge.
- Yeah.
- You're good. Go, Vesi.
- It is Ryan unlocking for Coco.
- Let's go, guys!
Let's go, Ryan!
Got Cody unlocking for Vesi.
You're good.
Let's go, Elie.
Elie unlocking for Baka.
You're good, Baka.
- Yeah, okay, go.
- Let's go, Baka!
- Go. Go.
- It is Vesi in the lead.
- You got it.
- Ryan still struggling
to get the net unlocked.
- There we go.
- You got it. Go, Coco.
Let's go, guys! Hell yeah!
- Go.
- You got this, Baka.
It's gonna be Cody
through with the first piece.
- Here comes Baka.
- Come on, baby.
Sami's got one. Owen's got one.
Come on, Baka! Go!
- Lindsay's got one for Coco.
- Good job, Lindsay!
There goes Karla digging.
Ryan just holding that net up,
but he's not
grabbing a puzzle piece.
You got to get
all four of 'em back here.
Everybody working.
Lindsay takes a fall.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Baka, you're good.
- Start untying.
- Let's go!
- Now you've
got to untie your bag.
- Let's go!
Vesi has all four puzzle pieces.
Start untying.
Yeah! Good job, Coco!
Coco, you're good.
You can untie.
- You got this, Baka!
- Go, guys!
Everybody got through
that first leg very quickly.
Now you've got to get the
puzzle pieces out of their bags.
Then two players
will form a square.
Got to get 'em all out
before you can start solving.
Dwight is moving about
as slow as you can move
and still actually be moving.
Thank you, Jeffrey.
Baka can start solving.
You got it, you got it,
you got it.
Coco, you're good.
Start solving.
Go, Coco!
Vesi has their fourth.
You're good.
This challenge is on.
Towards Owen, towards Owen,
towards Owen.
You're solving on that platform.
You're making a square.
Yep. Just like that.
And then put, um, rotate it.
You're experimenting right now
to see what works.
Up straight. There you go.
- How's that looking there?
- No.
- Shoot, I'm sorry.
There you go. That's it.
That's it. That's it.
Trial and error.
Just keep digging.
You got it, Baka.
Once you have it,
let me know.
- Jeff.
Baka thinks they have it,
and they do.
- That's a square.
- Can we kick it?
Move up the cargo net.
Hell yeah, Baka!
Baka quickly knocked it down
so nobody could even look.
Now you've got to get very heavy
puzzle pieces up this cargo net.
You earn it every single day
out here on Survivor.
Yes.
It is Coco and Vesi right now,
trying to get the square.
- Put that there!
- Go!
Sami heading up for Baka.
Gabler with the first piece.
You got bodies underneath.
If you drop a piece,
they are heavy.
Send it here,
then knock it over.
- That's the way you do it, Baka.
- Jeff, Jeff, Jeff, Jeff!
Vesi thinks they have it,
and they do. That's good.
- Head up.
- Get on up there.
- You got this, Baka!
Get those pieces up there!
Go ahead, Jesse.
Keep going, Jesse.
Vesi now heading up.
Oh.
Coco in dead last again.
That piece, that piece
goes down on the ground.
They had it to where
it lined up like this.
- Elie, give me your hand.
- Thank you.
- Wait, wait, ow!
- Oh, sorry. Sorry.
Baka, you're good. Start.
All you, Baka!
Help Dwight. Help Dwight.
- I'm fine.
- All right.
- Vesi has their four.
You're good.
- Nice, Dwight.
We're looking for two to finish
by building a triangle.
Flip that.
It is Jesse and Dwight...
One more time.
...Sami and Owen.
Immunity on the line.
Day nine, Survivor 43.
Coco's still working on their
first puzzle-- the square.
- Don't give up, Coco!
Jeff, we got it.
- Jeff! Jeff!
- You got it! Go, Coco!
Right on! Good job, Coco!
- Coco trying to stay in this.
- Go, Coco!
Coco, once again, has put
themselves back in competition.
Watch out.
There it is, all four pieces.
Now get up.
James, Ryan,
everybody's in it.
- Coco, once again,
not giving up.
- Here.
Good.
This one's bottom left, quickly.
- Quickly.
- No. No, that's not it.
It can't be it. It can't be it.
Do not get sassy.
I want you
to take that next piece.
Coco is making fast work
of this, if they can solve it.
- Ryan, keep that up there.
Ryan, slide that in.
- Ryan, Ryan...
Like so many Survivor puzzles,
once you see it,
it'll be so clear.
But until you see it,
it's very difficult.
Vesi has it.
Vesi wins immunity.
Vesi has won
their first immunity challenge.
No Tribal Council.
It is now Baka and Coco
fighting to stay alive.
Right there.
- No, no, no.
- Long piece, long piece...
Can Baka pull it out
and send Coco to Tribal Council?
Elie, Elie, Elie.
Have him switch that over here.
The longest side on the ground.
- That's the right... Flip it.
- Flip.
- Yes?
Push that in. It'll go.
- Yeah.
- There you go.
Vesi is very clearly
helping Baka,
trying to tell them
where their pieces go.
- Why?
- They're helping them?
- Yup. Yes.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
- Come on, Baka!
- That's it.
- Spin yours.
Try it. We're gonna lose. Go.
- Keep going. Keep going...
- Owen gonna
try a different piece.
- Yeah.
- Do they have it?
- There we go.
- Jeff! Jeff!
They do! Baka has it!
Baka pulls it out!
Baka safe, sending Coco
to Tribal Council
for the first time this season.
- Nice!
- Wow, what an effort.
A very clear division,
with Vesi helping Baka.
Vesi, congratulations.
First time you've had this.
Here's your flint.
Well-earned.
First time in a while we will
not see each other at Tribal.
Baka, hard-fought,
very close at the end.
Baka's safe.
Baka, Vesi, grab your stuff,
head out, enjoy the night off.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thanks, Jeff.
Cassidy,
what do you make of the fact
that Vesi wasn't even hiding
that they were helping Baka?
I mean, there isn't any rules
in the game of Survivor.
There's definitely dirty play
that goes on, as we saw here.
They're uniting together
as the losers.
Um, we haven't lost yet,
and so they're trying
to just knock us down
- off of our pedestal.
- All right, Coco,
Tribal Council tonight.
Somebody from your tribe
will be the fourth person
voted out of this game.
And as a penalty for losing,
I'm gonna take your flint.
Sorry for you.
All right, Coco,
grab your stuff, head out.
See you tonight
at Tribal Council.
Losing sucks.
The other two tribes
were working together,
so once we hit the merge,
I've got people that I...
that I want to get revenge on.
But my biggest fear
is coming true.
We are going to Tribal Council.
And in a tribe of six,
there's no place to hide.
They had to help each other.
But y'all did amazing.
I'm really proud of y'all.
- Yep.
- This sucks, y'all.
I just want to eat
one more time together
before we start strategizing.
We do have to.
Okay.
Now that we lost,
our tribe has
to experience something new
and something unpleasant.
This is the first night
we have to scramble,
and right now,
the two people I trust the most,
it's gonna have to be
James and Geo.
Geo is my number one.
Somebody has to go home,
and I got to keep the people
I trust as close as I can.
Probably gonna be a whole bunch
of names being thrown...
I'm not gonna lie. I'm kind
of excited about Tribal Council.
And my master plan
is to take out Cassidy tonight.
We're gonna vote for Cassidy.
- Whatever I have to do
to stay in the game, right?
- Yeah.
I don't know.
I feel like I'm just
calling the shots right now.
I feel like
I can't trust Cassidy
as much as everybody else.
And I can
feel it in my bones
when I talk to her. I can feel
that she's probably gonna
turn around and backstab me.
Wait. You know,
wait, wait, wait, don't...
Okay, I was gonna
show you something.
When I cut 'em up, I cut 'em up
exactly in the center,
- where e-everything
looks almost exactly the same.
- Okay.
And that's why...
No, no, no.
You continue doing it.
It's like, "Why don't
you just cut it then,
if it's, like, so important?"
- We can do it
your way this time,
- No, no.
- and if it works, then...
- It's not like it's my way.
Geo's definitely, like,
grating on my nerves, for sure.
He's gotten a little big
for his britches, in my opinion.
He's being sassy to everybody,
and I think
- that's because... Yes.
- Is he?
- Yeah.
- He's been... I've seen him
be sassy to multiple people...
Yeah.
I want to get Geo out,
and I don't think that
he would blink an eye
if he had to turn on me.
I want to go Geo.
Perfect. I'm down.
Geo is playing
a "I call the shots" game.
No. There's no way
Cassidy's going home.
Tonight, we're voting for Geo.
It's the easiest vote.
Do you know if
my name has ever come up?
No.
Nobody's saying
anything right now.
The plan right now
is for us to vote Geo,
and something's
just not adding up.
I say that
because this is Survivor,
and it's never
as easy as it seems.
It's making me, especially,
pretty paranoid.
I don't know why.
You know, maybe it's the fact
that everybody's continuously
running around this island,
trying to strategize.
I don't understand
why we have to keep going off
if the plan's already in place.
...feel like we can
start talking strategy.
You know, they're
talking right now.
After we eat this,
strategy season is open.
My gut is telling me,
"Of course they would
target me."
I-I feel like
I'm somebody that
needs to be targeted.
Ryan won't even
strategize with me.
Fine. Don't talk to me.
If I'm being honest,
I'm a huge threat--
physically, socially,
um, and strategically.
How are you feeling? Like,
what's going through your head
- right now, Lindsay?
- I'm super paranoid
that it's gonna be me tonight.
No.
Oh, my gosh.
What-what can I do
to reassure you that it's not?
I just want to know who's lying.
I don't trust anybody right now.
This is Survivor, and
it'd be silly for me to do so.
But that paranoia is
too difficult to work with.
I completely understand
and agree with that.
Dude, are you...
you'd be down to flip?
If she's this paranoid?
She's paranoid as hell.
I'm gonna talk to her
to calm her down.
- Yeah, but Karla's
acting funny. I mean...
- Karla's not acting funny.
We both, me and Karla
are on the same page.
We're trying
to get you to realize...
Madness.
You tell people they're safe,
and for some reason that's just
not good enough for them.
Are y'all in an alliance?
And that's the thing.
- I don't feel like it,
at this point.
- No, no, look. Think about it.
- I think Karla's
lying to me, too.
- No, no, no. She's not.
Look at me.
You are not the target tonight.
What you can't do
is sketch out the people
that are voting with you.
I'm trying to make it
so Lindsay
doesn't go home,
but when you start
blowing up the game with people
trying to protect you
on the first freaking vote...
- ...I can't convince you.
- All right, then-then that's it.
- I'm gonna trust you.
- Thank you.
And the thing about it is,
it wasn't Lindsay
maybe two hours ago.
And you didn't trust me,
and you may just go home.
All right, I just need to go...
- Let's go to the well
really fast.
- All right.
You and I are the swing votes.
- You know this, right? Okay.
- Yeah, 'cause right now
it's Geo.
Geo or Lindsay.
I know.
So we're set to go after Geo,
but Lindsay's starting
to show signs of paranoia.
It's literally not you.
I don't know what's going
through her head, but it's like
telling your drunk friend
that they can't drink anymore,
that they're not allowed to go
into the bar, and they're like,
"I can, I can," and you're like,
"Stop drinking."
And it's just, like,
they don't listen.
She may have just
shot herself in the foot.
Right now, chaos just erupted...
Yes.
- She's literally
ruining the game right now.
- I know.
She's ruining her own game
by doing this.
But at the same time,
Geo right now is power-hungry
and thinking that he can
kind of, like, boss me around.
That ego is getting in the way.
- Geo.
- Cool beans.
I'm putting
all my trust in you guys.
- Sounds like a plan.
- All right.
I love you guys.
Geo is the easiest vote
right now.
We have the numbers,
but I knew coming intoSurvivor
that it was
gonna be really complicated.
And it's game on.
Hello, Jeff.
Wow.
This may be
the most raucous entrance
to a first Tribal.
Group of torches back there.
Grab one, dip it in, get fire.
This is part of the ritual
of Tribal Council,
because, as you know, in this
game, fire represents your life.
When your fire is gone,
so are you.
Sadly, that will be the case
for one of you tonight.
All right,
so I need a little catch-up,
because this is
our first time together.
So, Ryan,
what grade would you give
the tribe
for these first nine days,
based on camp life, and shelter,
and fire and all that stuff?
I'd give us about an 8.5.
We don't bicker very often,
though it does happen,
like a family.
- But we've eaten every night,
most of the time, so...
- Wow.
Well, Geo and Ryan,
they're the papaya boys.
And they run around.
They do their thing around camp
to keep us fed.
Yeah, when I care for people,
I want to provide for them.
I've gotten to spear fish. I've
gotten papaya for everybody.
I climbed a coconut tree,
and I got a coconut, Jeff.
- And I...
- Let's stop there for a minute,
because when's
the last time you did that?
I've never
climbed a coconut tree, Jeff.
Never.
So I think we got to
take these moments in,
because, of course,
Survivor is a game.
We all know that, but I'm always
the one sort of preaching
that it's the adventure
that you make it, as well.
Yeah, Jeff, I have to say, I
really took your words to heart.
So, Lindsay,
what have you learned
from nine days of hard work,
trying to get along?
Because I feel like
Coco has gotten
as much juice out
of every papaya
that you can, so to speak.
We have, and we know
what works right now for us.
We know what it takes to win.
And then today happened.
So, um, today was definitely
a wake-up call for us.
Immediately, everyone started
breaking out into groups.
Some people spoke
a little bit more than others.
Some people didn't speak at all.
Um, I'm curious to see
if those people
will reveal themselves
and maybe explain why
they didn't feel like
they needed to have
a conversation with me tonight.
I actually
didn't get that energy
of, "I need to talk to you.
Like, I want
to strategize with you."
How do you receive that?
I think the people that wanted
to have conversations
with me today
made it a priority.
Okay, so that's a rejection.
Geo, does that concern you
or does that make you happy
when there's a little stress
between two other tribe members
at Tribal?
As long as the vote
is not on me, I am happy.
But I've been nervous
all afternoon.
I kind of feel like, you know,
when you're a child
and you get in trouble
with your parents,
and they take the TV away
from me? It's like
you're the parent and the TV
is the flint.
Okay. I'm the parent.
I'm the fun killer,
and now you all have to
come in here
and get a lecture from me.
Why am I always the parent?
I don't know,
but that's how I feel right now,
and I've been nervous all night.
And if you're not nervous
on Tribal Council,
then something's wrong with you.
Karla,
what did you notice happening
when you all got back to camp
after the challenge?
Naturally, there was a scramble,
and you're kind of
fact-checking.
You kind of have
to do full circle
to ensure
that every single person
that you said
you're solid with is solid.
If not, then you have to figure
out where did that go wrong, or,
if you're solid, you're solid.
Lindsay, fact-checking in
a conversation is a great part
- of playing Survivor.
- Right.
Were you doing that today?
Uh, probably a little too much.
I was definitely
getting paranoid,
and everyone
definitely noticed that.
But then I realized. "Wait.
"If you keep revisiting
these conversations,
- Mm-hmm.
-"it's gonna create paranoia
"within the people
that you just solidified
your-your votes with."
So, Geo, given that you felt
your own version of paranoia--
that the parents were mad
and they're gonna
take the remote
and all that stuff--
when you sense
Lindsay spiraling a little bit,
do you go in to try to help?
I just want to make sure
I keep my people calm.
You know, the people
that I spoke to, calm,
so that way,
they won't freak out.
But sometimes the waters
might look calm on the surface,
but underneath, like, there's
stuff happening, you know?
And it's-it's... it's gonna
get messy no matter what.
Well, I know somebody's going to
be hurt at the end of the day.
- It's part of the game.
- James, what were you trying
to accomplish this afternoon?
Well, I was chilling at camp
for a lot of the time.
That's my calm demeanor,
and that's how
I assure the people
that you're working with
that you're going to do what
you said you're going to do.
That's an interesting approach.
"I'm just gonna chill.
That's how I'm gonna
show you trust."
But that's the part of this game
that's so complicated,
which is,
"Of course I'm gonna front
-"like I trust everybody,
but inside,
- Yeah.
my heart is like,
'What if I'm the one?'"
Yeah. I mean, yeah,
that's a real
emotional battle
that you have to face
because things can change every
day, every second in this game.
And the only way that you can
really demonstrate trust
is by voting.
So, Karla, how close
to the sun setting were you all
still talking about the vote?
It didn't stop.
- I mean, it-it...
- We didn't get to finish.
We didn't get to finish.
Yeah. Like,
- if we had more time...
- Agreed.
- We didn't get to finish.
- ...we wouldn't
stop talking, yeah.
- Really?
Really?
So what is that indicative of?
There's still
a lot of questions in the air.
And that is the paranoia.
All right, with that, it is
time to vote.
Lindsay, you're up.
If anybody has an advantage
or an idol,
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Okay, I'll read the votes.
First vote: Cassidy.
Geo.
One vote Cassidy, one vote Geo.
Lindsay.
That's one vote Cassidy,
one vote Geo,
one vote Lindsay.
Lindsay. That's two votes
Lindsay, one vote Cassidy,
one vote Geo.
Fourth person voted out
of Survivor 43: Lindsay.
That's three. That's enough.
Need to bring me your torch.
Lindsay, the tribe has spoken.
Time for you to go.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
Good night.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
You are not on our side.
They think
they have the numbers,
but revenge is a dish
best served cold.
I came here
to dream big and go for it.
It's a million-dollar game.
Oh.
I could mess some things up.
Boom. Over.
We are screwed.
Now the game
has changed dramatically.
I thought my alliance
was gonna stick with me,
and they turned on me.
I did play my ass off,
but it came at a cost.
I only know one way--
to go as hard as I can.
I've waited 22 years
to play this game,
and I wasn't going
to do it half-assed.
:
I'm really proud of myself.
But it was everything
that I wanted it to be.
Not as long,
but I'm really happy.