Guess what we got.
- We have tree mail.
- Ooh.
- Yeah.
-♪ Da, da, da, da.♪
Whoa.
Oh, yeah!
- What? Read it.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Yes!
- What?!
- Yo!
I'm gonna wait. It's Survivor.
While it's exciting,
"Yes, oh, my God,
the merge is coming,"
it's Survivor, right?
And for the last two seasons,
we've seen that
the merge doesn't come easy.
There's a huge papaya
that I grabbed.
'Cause if we came in
with fruit and stuff,
they're gonna be like,
"Oh, my God.
- We like these people,
don't we?"
- Yeah.
For me, honestly,
this is some perfect timing.
After yesterday's
Tribal Council, you know,
I felt left out.
And now I feel like I just
went from the top to bottom.
So I'm not necessarily
tied down with Coco anymore.
I'm a free agent now.
I can say,
"Hey, I'm on the outs,
and I'm ready to vote
for who you need taken out."
So it's perfect time,
in my opinion.
Well, we made it to the merge.
Wow, guys.
Let's go, team, 'cause you know
that clock has started already.
The first phase of
the game, when it's all about
the tribes and stuff,
and you're in your little
six-person tribe, to me,
that's like gladiator school.
Like, you know, just,
you're just learning the ropes.
You're starting to learn how to
make the moves
and things like that.
And I'm, like, excited,
but I'm nervous, so, like, I got
this mix of feelings going on.
But this is where you
got to really prove yourself.
This is where,
you know, it really gets going.
Yeah! Hello!
- BYOB! Where's the party at?!
- Huh?
The game is starting.
I am so excited. I've
looked forward to this moment
since I was a little girl.
I wanted to be able to say
I made it to the merge.
James. I'm Elie.
It's nice to meet you, James.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Oh, my God.
We have been
competing against these tribes
and looking at them as our foes,
and now, all of a sudden,
everybody gets on the beach,
and we're like, "Hey!
"Nice to meet you.
I've been waiting to meet you.
I can't wait to meet you."
And I'm going,
"Man, you all are lying."
It's like Normandy here,
and it's about to hit the fan.
So great to meet you, dude.
I get it,
I mean, it makes sense,
but I find the whole thing
kind of comical.
But, hey, if you can't beat 'em,
you might as well join 'em.
I don't know
what to think, because
I don't have a buff yet.
So it's not a traditional merge.
We don't have a merge feast.
So we know
something big is coming.
It's great to be here.
I'm just scared
to death at what's coming next.
Yeah, no, it is huge.
- I was like...
- I wish I had the chyron
on the bottom third of my screen
right now
that could tell me
who's got an idol,
who's got an extra vote,
who's got an advantage,
'cause in this new era
of Survivor,
there are so many trinkets
running around
in Jeff's bag of tricks.
Okay.
The known menu of advantages
we have right now,
starting with Baka.
Gabler has an idol
that is good
for one more Tribal Council.
Jeanine has
the hidden immunity idol
that she got
from the Beware Advantage,
but Jeanine can also not vote
at this first Tribal Council.
Going over to Vesi,
I know Jesse
does not have a vote,
and I know Noelle
has the Steal a Vote
from our journey together.
And then with Coco,
someone could have their idol.
That I don't know.
So as far as I know,
I'm aware of two idols
and two no votes
and a Steal a Vote.
So five different things
we're trying to keep track of
right now,
on top of 12 other people.
So it's-it's a lot.
It's a big deal, you know,
even though
it's not really a merge.
- Yeah.
- I'm so hyped.
You'll love Cody.
Like, you literally, like...
- He-he's... he's amazing.
- What you see out of him is,
like, what you get.
Noelle mentions Cody has
a bead from everybody's bag.
And my ears perk up.
Cody's got the idol
from the Vesi camp.
So, Cody has the other idol.
Because Noelle was
talking about Cody had
- all the beads on all her bags.
- All the beads...
- But we know.
- We know.
And she-I don't think she knows.
- I don't think she knows either.
- So...
- Yeah, yeah. Okay, yeah.
- Right?
- And that's, like,
a supermajority.
- Yeah.
- We at least know
where Vesi's idol is.
- Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Mm-hmm.
I feel like
I was made for Survivor.
I've kind of figured out
how to hack things
and, I don't know,
I just feel like this
is my environment.
And the social element
of the game,
I knew I was gonna be good at,
but I'm way better
than I even thought.
And honestly,
that's exactly where you
want to be at the merge.
Come on in.
All right.
Shall we get into it?
- Yes, sir.
- All right,
first things first.
I'll take back the tribal idols.
Thank you.
No need for these anymore.
Oh, my God.
Because we're no longer
in the tribe stage of the game.
Yesterday, you received
a note with tree mail
telling you to drop your buffs.
You also don't have
your merge buffs yet,
because you have not
made the merge.
You're at the threshold where
you're trying to transition
from one stage of the game
to the next.
Here's what you're gonna
have to do to earn that buff.
For today's challenge,
we're gonna be divided
into two teams of six.
On my go,
you're gonna race to remove
a heavy pile of debris
to reveal a sled.
You'll then drag that sled
to a series of stations,
collecting large wooden crates
along the way.
When you have all six crates,
you'll use them
to build a staircase.
Retrieve a ring of keys.
You must then work together
to get up a very steep ramp...
...to the finish where you will
solve a Survivor word puzzle.
First team to finish,
all six players
safe tonight at Tribal Council.
You earn that merge buff
and, in addition, a merge meal.
- Whoo.
- It's yours, no twist,
no player gonna take it away.
Oh!
Losers, not the same story--
no buff, no food, no immunity.
Your threshold
will continue at Tribal Council,
where you will now
have to survive the vote
in order to make the merge.
And to be clear,
tonight at Tribal,
everybody goes.
Everybody's voting tonight.
Sound good?
- Sounds good.
- Yes, sir.
All right, we're gonna
divide into two teams of six.
One final twist.
There's one extra person.
If you draw the gray rock,
you will not compete,
but you will choose
one team to align with
and ride or die with them.
You will win with them,
or you will lose,
but you will not
have any say in your fate.
- Make sense?
- Yes, sir.
- Shall we draw?
- Let's do it.
- Yes, sir.
All right, let's do it.
Grab a rock
and keep it a secret.
Oh, God.
Sometimes the game comes down
to these moments of chance.
You're just
drawing a colored rock.
All right, everybody,
turn your palms up...
...and reveal.
All right, everybody,
turn your palms up and reveal.
Oh. No way.
If you have a red rock,
go to the red mat.
If you have blue,
go to the blue.
Noelle, you have gray.
You're in the middle,
in between the two.
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Oh, Noelle.
All right,
let's look at the Blue team.
We have Gabler, Jesse, Ryan,
Jeanine, Dwight and Karla.
Let's go to Red.
We have Cassidy, James,
Elie, Sami, Owen and Cody.
I got to say, from here,
it looks pretty even.
Yeah, my decision
sucks right now, Jeff.
All right, Noelle,
if you choose the team
that wins, you are safe.
If you choose
the team that loses,
you go to Tribal tonight vulnerable,
and it could be you going home.
It's tough, because
it's so freaking even.
I'm gonna go with...
I'm gonna go with Blue.
All right, Noelle,
you're gonna sit right here.
You can see
everything from here.
Everybody else, I'm gonna
give you a minute to strategize,
and we will get it on.
Here we go.
Making the merge, right here.
For immunity, safety tonight
at Tribal Council,
earning the merge
and a merge meal.
Survivors ready?
Go!
First, you've got to get all
20 sandbags onto your platform.
That is stage one
of this challenge.
Here we go, Blue!
20 sandbags.
Red working
very quickly together.
Coconuts being tossed all over,
big heavy ropes,
but the sandbags
are what matter.
You got to get all of 'em.
- Let's keep moving!
- All right, now this side.
This side.
Blue very close.
Red very close.
- The last bag, is that it?
- That's it.
- You're good!
- Jeff.
- Pull it, pull it, pull it.
- Blue, you're good!
One, two, three.
We're dead even right now.
- Just here. Just to the nose.
- Here?
Now you got to get your sled
to that first station.
Let's go, guys.
Here we go, Blue.
Load those crates on your sled
and move on to the next station.
You got to cross a threshold--
- the theme of this challenge.
- Let's go, guys.
From one stage to the next.
Here comes Blue.
And here comes Red.
Let's go, Blue!
This way.
Nice. Nice.
- Blue in the lead.
- Nice job, Jesse.
They've got
three crates on the bottom,
- same as Red.
- Pass me the crates.
Here we go, guys.
- You got it?
- Yep.
Now they're gonna
get a little wobbly.
Oh, watch out.
Careful, careful.
- You got it?
- Go ahead.
- Now it's Blue.
- Oh, it's caught. It's caught.
- What's it caught on?
- On what?
- Blue is stuck,
and here comes Red.
This way, this way.
Well, we've got our first
lead change here.
It's now Red in the lead.
Blue's gonna have to wait.
- We could have a collision.
- Hurry. One, two, three.
You got to push.
One, two, three.
- One, two, three.
Stop.
Red doing a great job to keep
the crates on their sled.
You're good.
Now start building a staircase.
You now have six crates
that you're gonna use
to build a puzzle staircase.
- Y'all got it?
- We got it, we got it...
You're good.
Now you
got to get the crates off.
Okay, that's gonna go on top.
We know that.
Where's the O-R in Survivor?
- Where's the O-R?
- Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Karla got smashed
by one of the crates.
Where's the O-R?
- Oh, there's the "R."
- Okay.
Karla with an injured hand.
- You all right, Karla?
- You okay?
- All right.
- Karla bleeding.
You know you're on Survivor
when you got blood.
Red making progress
on that crate.
- We're good.
- You've got it. Go up.
Come on, come on...
Owen gonna go up
to untie the ring of keys.
It is now Blue
trying to stay in it.
Red's still in the lead.
Still a lot of challenge left.
Boy, Red is not messing around.
They don't want anybody
to see their puzzle.
- Now you got to get up the ramp. James...
- Okay, hold on.
- That was impressive.
James scaled the entire wall.
- Attaboy, James.
- Wait.
- Owen gonna give it a try.
Owen did it as well.
That is not easy to do.
That is the biggest ramp
in Survivor history.
- All right. Ryan, get up there.
Ryan, get up there.
- Blue, you're good.
Ryan gonna head up.
Blue trying to close the gap.
Merge buffs on the line.
Immunity and Tribal Council
and a merge meal.
You're good, you're good.
Step on...
Elie now up for Red.
Cassidy standing
on the back of Cody.
- James has her.
- I got her. I got her.
- Probably a good idea.
- Here goes Blue.
- They've got their ring.
- Good job, Blue.
Here we go. Here we go.
Here goes Cody.
The last for Red.
Can he do it?
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
- That is how you do it
on Survivor.
Let's go, baby!
Let's go. Let's go.
- Big lead for Red.
- Key, key, key.
Here goes Blue now
with a different story.
- Gabler using his back.
- Come here.
Ryan goes up on his own.
Here we go. Next, next, next.
Elie has the key. Crate open.
- Let's go, baby.
- Last puzzle piece.
You are good. Start working.
It's gonna be Owen and Elie.
Grab with both hands.
Push him up.
Jesse trying to get up.
Gabler just pushes Jesse up.
- Same thing. Same thing.
Gabler and I will push you up.
- Ready?
Karla now gonna
have to go up for Blue.
She's gonna need a hand.
There's Ryan.
Karla has had a hard
time in this challenge.
- No, no, no. Go, go, go.
- She's
had her hand smashed.
- She just slid down the wall.
- All right, I'm coming.
Red has been in the lead
from the beginning, really.
Noelle put all her faith
on Blue.
Six people wearing Blue.
Jeanine is up.
Get over that wall.
Jeanine's good.
Here comes Karla.
Come on, Karla!
She's getting a hand.
Look at that.
- Ryan upside down...
- Grab my feet. Grab my feet.
like Spider-Man.
Hold on. Let me grab your...
Will it work?
Yes, Karla.
- You got it!
- Give me your hand.
- Karla digging, digging.
- Get up here...
Grab her hand, Dwight!
I got it, I got it, I got it.
I'm going. Okay.
- You're up, Karla.
- Yes, yes, yes.
- I got it.
- Go ahead. I got it, I got it...
It is now
Blue trying to catch up.
- Karla bleeding, in pain.
- Yeah, yeah.
Here we go, everyone. Great job!
There you go.
Now get that piece free.
Now you can
start working on it, Jeanine.
- Okay.
- It's Dwight and Jeanine
for Blue.
It is Elie and Owen for Red.
And a mass of letters.
You are trying to solve
the Survivor word phrase.
Get rid of that,
and put this one up there first.
Red has had more time
to study the puzzle.
First.
Okay.
You think it's three lines?
- Yeah, I do. I do.
- Okay, cool.
Dwight gonna make a move now.
They've got an idea.
No, hey, this-this one
goes right on the bottom.
- It's gonna say "S."
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
James with a lot of thoughts
about where
these letters should go.
- Yeah.
- Another piece by Blue.
Do they think
they have something?
- There you are.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Red now with another piece.
Elie and Owen think
they have something going.
Shut up. Shut up.
Both teams are now whispering.
Both teams think
they know what it is.
They just got to
figure out how to do it.
Another piece for Owen and Elie,
and another piece
- for Dwight and Jeanine.
- Right there.
- No, that's too high...
- Both teams appear
to have the very same thought
- in mind for the phrase.
Now who will solve it first?
- Hurry, hurry, hurry.
No, no, this one goes...
This one. It's this one...
Panic now.
Jeanine racing to get a piece.
Owen trying
to hold a piece up.
They need a different piece.
Which one is it?
- Owen, Owen, all right...
- Immunity on the line.
Guaranteed spot in the final 12.
- Dwight with another piece.
- Help her, help her...
Here goes Jeanine and Dwight
with another piece for Blue.
Blue trying to close the gap.
E, E, E, E, E.
Both teams know they have it.
They've just got to get
their puzzle put together.
It is Blue now
with the momentum.
- That one, that one, that one.
- This one, this one, this one.
Blue is now in the lead.
You got it.
Don't worry about it.
Elie trying to shove a piece in.
- Hey, Elie, no.
- That's not it. That's...
Blue with another piece.
They're down to two pieces.
This would be
a big comeback for Blue.
Say it! Say it!
"Earning your spot
at every stage."
That's what you just did.
You earned
your spot in the merge.
Nobody from this six going home.
Noelle is safe.
- We're not going home.
- Noelle picked
the right group
and she is safe tonight as well.
Thanks for believing in us.
Come here. Come join us.
Share those happy tears.
Wow.
Sorry, bro.
...
Thank you guys so much.
All right.
Six buffs in here,
and one for you.
Oh, my God, they're so pretty.
My daughter's gonna love this.
Jesse, Dwight, Jeanine, Ryan,
Karla, Gabler and Noelle,
safe tonight
at Tribal Council, cannot
be voted out of this game.
In addition, you'll return
to camp and enjoy a merge meal.
You six will not have any food,
you don't have a buff,
but what you do have
is a lot of uncertainty.
Which one of you is
going to be voted out tonight?
Grab your stuff, head out.
See you tonight at
Tribal Council, where somebody
will be the sixth person
voted out of Survivor 43.
The winner's got immunity
at tonight's Tribal Council.
They are set.
The rest of the six of us,
somebody's dream
of being a part of the merge
is going to end one night short.
The craziness, the madness
has not even started yet.
It's about to get
really wild around here.
I mean, whatever tonight,
- we ran that thing hard.
- We sure did.
All righty, y'all. Let's
have a little losers' lunch.
Oh, so, I'll get the fire
going, and...
No, no, no, no, no, don't.
- We were all in it together.
- No, we were all,
we were all there.
I know, I just,
I couldn't focus, and I'm sorry.
We were licking
our wounds a little bit.
I volunteered
to be on the puzzle,
and so I feel responsible.
Let's push through it.
Let's make the most
of what we can.
- Get some little sticks.
- Right now,
we're kind of in "mergatory."
Half of us
have not made the merge.
You know, the six of us
are in limbo right now.
We're fighting
to stay in the game.
So it's me,
it's Elie, it's Cody,
it's Sami,
it's Owen and it's James.
And one of us is going home.
- One, two, three.
- Team Red.
So, like, there's nowhere
to hide right now.
Cody, can I just
talk to you for one sec?
I'll tell you what,
James is sketching me out.
- Yeah.
- The fact that James was like,
-"Cody, let me talk to you,"
like that.
- I know.
So I want to talk
with Cody at some point,
-'cause I would like
for him to be the name.
- Mm-hmm.
Like, I think that we... Yeah.
- Like, we tell Coco
that it's gonna be Cody.
- Cody.
As fast as we can.
I've been getting the best vibes
from people on the Vesi tribe.
They seem
to want to work with us,
really for
the past few challenges.
Elie. Elie.
Have him switch that over here.
Vesi is very clearly
helping Baka.
So I think
they would be comfortable
with a Coco going home first,
where we do a split
on Cassidy and James.
And so, I'm gonna tell them
that I'm open to a Cody vote,
but the real plan
is to vote out one of them.
I'm just gonna have
to lie about it to their face.
- Yes.
- Okay.
- And I'm with James.
So I don't want to throw
anybody's name out there,
- but I'm just saying, like...
- Get Cody?
Yeah. I mean, I don't know.
What do you think?
- I'm okay with that. Yeah. Yeah.
- That's...
I'm totally okay with that.
There's a lot riding
on tonight for me, and I'm
- definitely nervous.
- I've made
a better connection with James
- than I have with Cody.
- Yeah.
- So far.
- Me and Elie
talked about voting together.
And I feel like us girls
could kind of get together
and maybe do something.
Unfortunately,
that means it's Cody tonight.
I think that we're down
to team up with Coco,
-'cause that's an easy majority.
- So you just tell me
the name so I know where to go.
I mean, we don't have
to beat around the bush.
- I would like to work with Coco.
- Okay.
And so that means
you and Cassidy are safe.
I don't
want to vote out a Baka,
and that means
Owen and Sami are safe.
- Okay.
- Not gonna vote for myself.
- Yeah...
- Okay.
- Uh, yeah.
- You don't have
to say anything else.
I pulled Elie aside
to see where she wanted to go.
She didn't want
to give me a name,
and then she reluctantly
gave me Cody's name.
I want to keep her very
confident, but I'm not with her.
She doesn't
tell me anything, and
I don't trust her.
- Oh, my God.
Ah, how do you start?
I haven't eaten for
13 days.
I haven't eaten a real meal,
so I'm gonna enjoy this.
The hell is this?
And I don't even
know what I'm putting
in my mouth at this point.
I don't even know
what the tastes are.
I'm just trying to stuff it
as much as possible.
So sorry.
Manners out the door.
I'm so sorry, Nana.
I'm so sorry, my mom.
My mom loves dragon fruit.
Does anyone want a beer?
- Would that be crazy?
- Yeah, I'll have a beer.
- Who wants a beer?
- I'd like a beer.
- Here, darling.
- Thank you.
We're having a great time
because we're safe.
That means that we don't have to
come back to camp and scramble.
-
- But at the same time,
there's, like,
this tension of like,
"All right, let's talk."
- Oh, my God. Uh...
- Oh.
So, tonight.
Yeah, let's, like... What's...
- What's the scoop?
- What's the plan?
We could be the final seven.
That's the thing.
We have the numbers.
We got this spot
by winning today.
Ryan starts
talking about how it makes sense
that the seven of us are strong,
and I'm not
interested in his pitch.
It's just a little ridiculous,
the fact that we're just gonna
become an alliance because
you boosted me up a ladder.
I have my own
alliance at this point.
So we need
to find somebody that,
you know, would help us
get further in the game.
Yeah. I mean, I do have
a good relationship with Cody.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
- I'd like to keep Cody.
- I'd love to keep Cody.
I'd like to keep Owen and Sami.
I'd like to keep Elie.
It was pretty evident that
everyone wanted
everyone to stay,
with the exception of Gabler.
Elie went through my bag
on day three.
So that's something for me
that I remember.
I was just like,
"Uh," and then
I took a sip of my beer,
because this
is one of those moments
where you're just like,
"Oh," you know?
It is very evident
that Baka is fractured.
Gabler. Oh, my God.
In that moment,
my jaw drops, because I am just
flabbergasted that he would
just throw her under the bus
like that. And it's wild to me
what comes out
of that man's mouth, especially
in front of me, who...
He knows it's gonna
get back to her.
It's gonna be pretty tough
for all of us to vote unanimous.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
Everybody was fractured,
they need something to go for.
And by throwing out
Elie's name, I was trying to...
throw out Elie's name.
The trust has been broken with
me and Elie since day three.
So right now,
I'm targeting enemies
that I know are enemies
that are plotting against me.
And if I can
do that with people,
then we build a little bit
more trust together, because
if we're gonna vote Elie out,
it's today.
I want to look like
I'm decisive and trustworthy.
I think it's
really important for me
to not just talk to talk
but walk the walk.
And I'm walking
that walk tonight.
Oh, God.
- No. No.
- No.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
It sounds like Coco
is putting me on the block.
I am the only Vesi member that's
not immune at Tribal Council.
So it's easy for them
to just be like,
"Well, let's
just pick off Cody."
Fortunately,
Baka wants to work with Vesi
to take out James.
And if that's the case,
then I don't need
to play my idol tonight.
- Yeah.
- Why me?
I know, you didn't.
It seems
that at the merge feast,
Gabler told everybody there
that on day three,
I searched his bag,
and he essentially serves me up
on a silver platter of somebody
that he would like to vote out.
I have heard that
you're telling people
I searched your bag
on day three,
and I have literally
never searched your bag.
I have no idea
where you got that information.
Owen and Sami said they saw you.
They told me that you looked
through my bag with Jeanine.
Well, it's not true.
Why would you
throw me under the bus?
You've been throwing me
under the bus, too.
I have not.
That's the thing, Gabler.
- I'm not playing like that.
- Somebody went through my bag.
- I still felt...
- Was it Jeanine? Who was it?
- Somebody did it.
- I'm not gonna do that.
I'm not like that.
It's important
for you to do that.
- I'm not like that.
- Okay.
- Then I-I got to assume
that you guys were together.
- So...
Of course.
Jeanine is my best friend.
Does Jeanine
have a hidden immunity idol?
- Did she find something?
- Yeah.
Yeah, but nobody told me, right?
Why would I tell you
someone else's business?
I'm not gonna
tell your business...
Am I your ally
or am I not your ally?
I feel you have turned on me.
All right, well, it's not true.
We wanted to stay Baka strong.
- I have not faltered.
- Then you should have
shared information with me
when you could have, and brought
me in and kept me in the loop.
- So...
- Well, I have
to go talk to other people
- I know. I know.
- because you have now put me
on the chopping block, and
I have to deal with that, so...
- I don't know that it was me.
- It was you.
We talked in circles,
and there was no budging.
He's not believing me at all.
So Owen and Sami
really screwed me over.
You told Gabler that I
searched his bag, and I did not.
And then he told
everybody at the feast
that I was searching his bag.
He got my name.
He said from you and from Owen.
- What? You-you...
- He told my name to everybody
- at the merge feast
to vote for me.
- Yeah.
What the hell?
Gabler blew everything up.
Now Elie is suspicious of me.
And she has enough skill
in this game to turn it
right back around on me.
So we got
to make her feel comfortable.
The two of you told Gabler
that I searched his bag.
- I, first of all,
I did not search his bag.
- I didn't tell him.
- Does Gabler want to vote for
you? Or is he just trying...
- Yeah. Yeah.
Gabler threw Elie
under the bus.
And now she is panicking
that she is gonna get voted for
by basically everyone
for being a snake.
I don't know
what he's talking about.
I think he's just scared of you.
I don't know what it is.
Then I-I need you to help me
clear my name then.
- Yes...
- Like, if y'all are legit.
- We got it.
- I trust you both, and...
Who do you want to vote for?
- Okay.
- I want to get out there
and talk to people,
because I feel like
the longer it festers,
- I'm just not...
- No, let's get out there.
- not trying to have, like...
- Okay, and whatever you do,
whatever you hear,
keep coming back to us, please.
James would be a really
easy target to get rid of,
but Elie is so much more
of a threat to have around here.
So I think
Elie has to go tonight.
So, you and Elie are sisters,
- and I get that, but...
- Yeah.
...somebody went through my bag.
I know it.
I also know that you guys found
the hidden immunity idol
out here.
- Actually, is it okay if we,
maybe, just talk?
- Yeah, yeah...
- Is that okay?
- I don't mind. I won't
disclose any information now.
- We'll see you in a minute.
- Thank you so much.
Coming back to camp,
all hell broke loose.
Gabler goes off his rocker
and keeps
throwing Elie under the bus
and starts telling
everyone that I have an idol.
I honestly don't know
how this information
got out at this point.
I don't even care
to deal with it right now.
All I care about
is that people feel good
within the Baka five
enough to just vote together.
I think for this vote, guys,
we got to stay Baka strong.
- I agree. Please.
- We have to.
We have to.
We'd be so, so, so, so dumb
to implode right now.
Yes. Yes, yes, yes, yeah.
The problem is I don't know that
I can work in the game with her.
That's fair, but we just got
to make it to the next step.
Me and Sami need our buffs.
- We can settle this later.
- Okay.
My main question is
is Gabler with us?
And I think he understood
where I was coming from.
So hopefully
he'll stick true to his word,
and we will vote together.
Maybe just tone it down
a little bit,
-'cause Jeanine's got an idol.
- I know.
- She could play it for Elie.
- Yes.
So you got to keep things cool.
- That's all I'm saying.
- Okay, okay, okay.
Got you. Got you.
Yeah. I'm freaking down.
- I don't want to scramble.
- Yeah.
I want to trust, you know,
in the things
- that I talk about and say
and call it a day.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Elie is still
saying Cody's name,
but I feel
something sketchy is up.
So I need to talk to everybody
to see
where everybody's head at.
Yeah.
According to James,
Elie put Cody's name
on the chopping block.
It seems like Elie's out here
trying to, like,
make moves, and, like, you know,
cause discord and spread
a little bit of misinformation,
from what I can tell.
And so
Elie's name, you know,
was already out there by Gabler.
And so I think
that's the way to go.
- Elie's the one...
- Elie's the one that's doing it.
And I think that we need
to break up Elie and Jeanine.
- And...
- Yeah.
I agree with that.
- What's up, bro?
- What's up, buddy?
Elie.
All right.
- Okay.
- If we can get Gabler,
we have the numbers
- to get Cody out.
- Gabler's not gonna
vote that way, though.
- You don't think?
- No. Gabler wants Elie out.
He may give it to me.
Frickin' Elie and Jeanine,
guess whose names
they're throwing out.
- Who?
- You two.
- Shut up.
I swear to God.
Damn.
Elie was targeting Cody,
and now she's coming after me.
I knew that I couldn't
trust her, but then
a lot of people
don't trust her,
and that's good for me.
So it's important
that Baka votes James.
Everyone in Baka
is voting James.
- James?
- Yeah.
- Can we do this? Now's the time.
No, I understand.
I understand.
Jeanine is really scrambling
to try to get me on board,
but it's too little, too late.
We're still not
Baka strong.
We're a Baka ... show.
These people think
that they've got me fooled,
but I know what's going on here.
I'm being played.
So I'm gonna vote Elie tonight,
and that's it.
- He just came to me, he said...
- Why would I ever trust him?
I'm gonna go home.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- I'm down.
- No, I know.
I'm the one without any power.
I thought I was in a position
where I could call the shots,
but now I think
I might be going home.
Fortunately, Jeanine might be
willing to play her idol for me.
Either way, it's gonna be
a real trial for me tonight,
and I don't want Gabler
to be the person
that crafts my exit out.
Wow. A lot of people.
A lot of people.
All right, so, big day.
The result
is seven people are safe.
Six people still
have to get to the merge.
So, Gabler, what happened
when the seven of you showed up
and now we have 13 people
all back together in camp?
We started off
at the merge meal.
There was a little bit
of talk of strategy,
and then we leisurely
walked back in, and boom,
everything just exploded.
I thought
I was gonna go lay down
and just try
to digest for an hour...
...and I have
not stopped talking all day.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah, Jeff. It's gonna be
very interesting
this evening, I think.
Cody, how'd you see it?
Oh, it was nutso.
It was complete chaos.
There was, there was
no organized chaos going on.
- It was a dust storm.
- Really?
Absolutely crazy.
- It was almost nauseating. Man.
- It was a lot.
So, Sami, tonight
there are essentially
seven people
who have individual immunity.
What are you feeling?
Because you're one of the six
that's in trouble.
Honestly, as soon as
we lost the challenge,
all I could think about
was how scary it is
to be vulnerable
versus being safe.
It gets to the point where
every conversation that
you have with somebody, every
look that you give somebody,
it really matters,
because it gets back to you,
at some point.
- Cassidy,
you were nodding.
- Yeah, it's true.
And it's hard to know
what dynamics
are going to shift
when you bring
a certain group of people
together, you know?
And anything that anybody
tells you could be a lie,
it could be the truth, and it's
really hard to differentiate.
So it can form bonds,
but it can also
cause chaos, too.
Jeanine, how is this vote
different now that
we are into the individual
portion of the game?
It could not be more different
than a-a tribe vote.
Like, we're all trying
to gauge not only what is best
for our individual game,
but what is every other
individual thinking
is best for their game.
And that's just, I don't even
know what factorial that is,
but 13 to the 12th?
Like, that just, there's
so many permutations of people
working together
and thinking different things.
Elie, Jeanine just hit
on something so important,
which is you have to look
at the game from every single
person's point of view,
and it gets very complicated.
Yeah. Everybody's
got their own mission.
Everybody's got their
own goals and their checklist.
And so today was no different.
I was thrown a little bit,
because, all of a sudden,
my name had at least, you know,
had-had bubbled to the surface.
And in that moment, I'm like,
"Oh, this is Survivor?
Like, what have I been playing?"
And so I felt really panicked.
And spending a lot of time
with somebody who doesn't
see me as an asset,
that's a wasted five minutes.
And in this game,
five minutes could be your life.
Wow. So, Owen,
is it that tight
that you really have to decide
where you're gonna
spend your time?
Right. Trust is the only
currency we have out here,
and that's
the beauty of Survivor
is that you can
never trust anyone 100%.
We can only trust ourselves
in trying to figure out
who trusts me.
Do I trust them?
And, like, all the possibilities
that come after that,
it makes your head spin.
So it was, uh, it was
an exhilarating afternoon.
So, Karla, there had
to be talk of advantages,
idols, Shot in the Dark,
all the things
that could change
or blow this Tribal up.
Of course. Right. You...
Not only do you have
a combination of alliances
or just
people working together,
but there's been nine people
on journeys already.
You don't know what people
have and what's out there.
And so that adds
another element of stress.
And, Gabler,
when you have an advantage
or an idol,
you don't want to play it
if you don't have to,
'cause you want to save it.
Absolutely, Jeff.
That is riding the razor's edge.
You know, the people
that have idols or advantages
in their pockets,
playing them at the right time
is the masterful piece
of Survivor.
And if you play 'em wrong,
you've got bad jewelry
to go home with.
So, Sami,
it sounds like there were
at least some discussions
where people said,
"So-and-so might have this,"
or "So-and-so has this"
or "I have this."
- Were you a part of that?
- Yeah, and I think
one of the more
important things is, like,
the way that those advantages
and idols are played,
whether they're played
the right way or not,
can change the way that people
view an alliance, you know?
If you said you had somebody's
back and they went on ahead
and played an advantage
or an idol or something,
what does that tell you
as a person in a group?
That tells you
they didn't really
come in here trusting you.
James, couldn't have said it
better than what Sami just said,
and yet,
it doesn't solve anything,
because if
you think you got to play it,
you got to play it, because
you got to get to tomorrow.
For me, I'm just like,
"Hey, I trust the people that
I've talked to,
and it makes pragmatic sense."
The vote I'm gonna make tonight,
just trying
to not flunk kindergarten, Jeff,
and move forward.
Jeanine, if you look at what
Sami's saying a different way,
he might really be saying
that sometimes a big move
is to not make the big move.
If you're right,
it can lock you like this.
If you're wrong, your torch
is here and you're gone.
This is a game
of paranoia versus gut.
And the difference
is paranoia is very present,
and gut is the ability
to latch on to things
that are behind you that
you can look back on and say,
"My gut instinct is that
that relationship
in the past worked,"
or, you know,
"I can trust that person."
And it's not just
so caught up in the momentary
feeling of what you should
be doing right then and there.
All right, time to vote.
Jeanine, you're up.
If anybody has
an advantage or an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
All right, I'll read the votes.
First vote, Elie.
James.
Owen.
Cassidy.
One vote Elie, one vote Owen,
one vote James,
one vote Cassidy.
DWIGHT [whispering]:
Geez, what a crazy game.
James.
That's two votes James.
Elie. We're tied.
Two votes Elie,
two votes James,
one vote Owen,
one vote Cassidy.
Elie.
That's three votes Elie.
Elie. That's four votes Elie,
two votes James,
one vote Owen, one vote Cassidy.
Sixth person voted out
of Survivor 43... Elie.
- Dang.
- You need
to bring me your torch.
- All right.
- Be safe.
Love you, Elie.
- Sorry.
- Bye.
- You're good, bro.
Y'all see what
trusting Gabler will get you?
- Ooh.
Right back at you.
Elie, the tribe has spoken.
Thanks, Jeff.
- Time for you to go.
- Thanks.
Congratulations.
You have all now made the merge.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
- Good night.
And the game continues.
- Thanks, Jeff.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
You can watch Noelle
accumulate this power
or you can make a move now.
An alarm bell's going off
for me, like, "Oh, my God."
None of us know what to do.
What's happening?
What do you mean,
"He found something"?
"Alli-Gabler" came up to the
surface. I'm ready to strike.
They got me. I think
it was a good move on them.
I had a lot more game to play.
Gabler really
threw me under the bus.
I think he's the reason
I'm here today.
I'm sure I came out of the gate
playing a little too hard,
but I don't
have any hard feelings.
And I had so much fun.
This was an opportunity
of a lifetime.
I will never ever
forget the people that I met.
And it was
the best time of my life.