Welcome to the season finale
of Survivor 44.
Well, great players
make great seasons,
and this group
has delivered every day.
It's been an unpredictable
season of Survivor,
starting with three medical
visits in our first three days.
There's been a lot
of well-crafted blindsides,
ever-shifting alliances.
We even had a little romance.
But now we are down to five
and once again,
they'll be starting over
on a new beach with no shelter.
Tonight, we'll have
two immunity challenges,
two Tribal Councils,
and one fire-making showdown.
Then we will read the votes
here in beautiful Fiji
and crown a winner
of Survivor 44.
We'll immediately
go into the aftershow,
which I think is gonna
be a lot of fun
with this group of players.
All right, let's get into it.
Our final five.
Carson, Carolyn, Yam Yam,
Lauren and Heidi.
There are a lot of ways
this could still play out.
And only one question
left to answer:
Who will be the Sole Survivor?
Settle in.
It's the finale of Survivor 44.
♪ ♪
(Carolyn screaming)
(Yam Yam laughing)
(screaming)
I need help. Oh, my gosh.
Wow.
- (Carolyn yells)
- Aah!
- Hell, yeah.
- (Lauren laughs softly)
Oh, I love these. Oh, my gosh.
- (Lauren laughs)
- HEIDI: Where are we going?
YAM YAM: Once we get to this
new island, we see we have nothing.
But we're so happy
to be in the final five.
This is the last leg
of the game, and
I'm happy to be here.
If I don't have anything
in this new island,
I'm okay because I'm still here.
Oh, my God!
(laughing)
- Where was it?
- A-a tree close to the cage.
- Shut up.
- Yeah.
CAROLYN: Tonight at Tribal,
Heidi played an idol.
I would like
to make it to five myself.
CAROLYN: I was surprised,
but at the same time, I wasn't.
Why would she trust us?
Thirteenth person voted out
of Survivor 44... Jaime.
CAROLYN: Our plan was Jaime,
and it worked.
So, now, Heidi's idol's gone,
so everyone's thinking,
"Okay, it's rehidden."
And I'm good at looking. I am.
I look.
I'm looking,
and I have, like... good.
I have experience doing this.
Like, I just feel like
we got to find it.
CARSON:
I'm gonna go look tomorrow.
But I think that's a good idea
for you if you want to.
Well, why-why don't you want
to find it?
Because I can't see.
I'll guide you.
I think I'd rather
look in the morning,
when I can be more efficient.
(laughs)
- CARSON: Oh, the idol? Well...
- Yeah.
CAROLYN: As far as
the idol goes, I feel like
I don't miss anything, and I,
like... (imitates whooshing)
I'm in there.
And I don't waste my time
digging a foot underground
like Yam Yam does.
That's his strategy, is digging.
It's not gonna be
a foot underground.
- Shut up.
- Wait.
Shut up. Come here.
I just want...
Oh, you...!
- (laughs)
- That's...
- Oh, my God!
- Like...
CAROLYN: I thought you had it.
YAM YAM: Getting an
idol will help me a lot,
but it could be anywhere.
So if you want
to not find an idol, ask me.
(laughs)
♪ ♪
HEIDI: Day 24!
And you just found an idol.
- Please.
- CARSON: Do you all really think another one's gonna
- be hidden because you played yours, Heidi?
- HEIDI: Yeah.
- CAROLYN: Yeah.
- Here's the thing. That thing
burns a hole in your pocket
because you're like, like,
"Are they gonna vote me out?
- "Like, I should play it now?"
- CARSON: You know what, Heidi?
HEIDI: Like, I don't know.
I didn't want to go home
with an idol in my pocket.
I'd rather play it.
And I didn't get any votes.
People may think
I'm regretting it.
No regrets. I made my decision,
and I'm here,
and I'm loving every second
of making it to final five.
Now, we think there's something
in this island,
and finding an idol
on the last day you could
actually play an idol would be
a huge game-changer.
'Cause I feel like
I'm flying a little bit solo,
but I think
I have a pretty decent résumé.
I mean, I found an idol,
I had alliances,
I'm the last Soka Survivor.
I've been
in holes, and I've been able
to survive, kind of dig out.
That's a fantastic résumé.
There's a lot of things
that could happen for me here
to go to the end.
We got to find it, though,
so, I'm not trying to, like,
beat around the bush, but
I'm not gonna, like, let them
- find it for us. You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
So, like, obvious or not,
it's, like, we got to find it.
I think
it has to be here somewhere.
CAROLYN: I'm gonna
find that idol. I-I just...
I have a good feeling.
Just, like, the entire game,
it's really been a lot
about my gut,
like, trusting my gut
and trusting my heart.
I'm emotional, but it... helps.
It helps with connecting
with people, it helps
people see that I'm real.
So I feel like people trust me
because they see that, like,
I'm just being myself,
and that's exactly
what I wanted to do.
That's not it.
- (laughing)
- That's not it?
Doesn't work like that.
YAM YAM: If I find this idol,
I'm winning
this million dollars.
I have everything else done.
I outwitted people,
I outlasted people.
I need to outplay them
by having these idols
because people like that thing,
you know? People like
big moves,
people like big finds.
People like big things
and showy things.
Even though they say
it's not about a flashy game,
it definitely helps, you know?
But there's a lot of stuff
we don't know about this island.
I'm climbing rocks,
digging in roots,
getting in branches.
It might be
in the middle of the ocean.
I don't know.
♪ ♪
I need to find that thing.
Oh, my God.
I hope it finds me first.
♪ ♪
CARSON: The idea of idols
scare me, and so I try
to circumvent them
in every case possible.
And I've not really
circled my game
around idols and advantages.
My game has fully been about
numbers, relationships
and strategy.
I have been on the right side
of the vote every single time.
I've known exactly
what was going on, and I know
everyone sees me
as a threat, so,
that's not good for me.
(Lauren laughs)
I'm on the outs.
I was totally blindsided
by the vote.
So I do feel kind of alone
that Jaime has left.
But I've been
through tougher than this.
You know, like,
through adversity,
through the challenges,
I never gave up,
and I never will give up,
and it could be
the difference between winning
a million dollars or not.
It's crunch time.
That's what it is...
Crunch time. But then,
you also need to be
in conversations, as well.
It seems as though there are
three Tika members
who are running the show, so,
I need to break that bond there.
...us three
would make it this far?
Yeah. Look at.
We're the Three Stooges
still here.
- What...
- I'm feeling really nervous about today, y'all.
Like, really nervous.
I'm gonna keep saying this.
Carson's gonna beat us.
Carson is a unanimous threat.
Everyone thinks
that Carson is a threat.
Carson has been
in every single vote.
on the right side every time.
Everyone loves him.
Carson is everyone's
little brother or Carolyn's son.
And I also think
that Carson believes that
he can beat me
in the end of the game.
He's gonna be a threat
in the end.
- But I didn't trust... I know.
- He's gonna knock all of us out.
- Yeah.
- Every... He's voted correctly...
Every single time.
CAROLYN:
Carson is 100% loyal to me,
and I believe he thinks that
I would always be loyal to him.
But now I'm thinking about,
like, the endgame.
I'm trying to weigh it all out,
but I do believe that
Carson is the biggest threat
out of everyone.
He's played the best game.
He speaks the best.
He is so articulate, he's so...
He's just the sweetie pie.
He would win.
How are you feeling?
I'm pretty nervous.
I think you're the name
I've been hearing, and I...
and you're probably
hearing my name.
- I think you're a big... you're a big threat.
- You and me.
- Me and you, you know.
- Yeah, for sure.
Most definitely.
CARSON: I feel like
Lauren has played
a good game, but
I think everyone here knows
that I can beat them.
And so, I am worried
about where things could go
considering how sporadic
my own alliance is.
Carolyn and Yam Yam are the
people I have to worry about
most in terms
of flipping or flopping.
Well, I'm banking
on winning immunity.
♪ ♪
Come on in!
- Good morning.
Taking in
that final five challenge.
Wow.
PROBST: What awaits you.
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
First things first, Lauren,
- got to take it back again.
- (groans, laughs)
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna race
through a massive,
three-level obstacle,
collecting keys along the way.
You'll grab
your last key using a pole.
Once you have your keys,
you'll unlock a chest,
use the rope inside
to drop a ladder.
You'll climb the ladder
to the top of a tower
and race
to solve a Survivor puzzle.
First person
to finish wins immunity,
is guaranteed
a spot in the final four.
The final four is unique
because you can't be voted out.
You will either win
that final four
immunity challenge
and earn your way to the three,
somebody will take you
to the three,
or you will fight
in a fire-making showdown
to get to three.
But it won't be because
somebody wrote your name down
on a piece of parchment. That's
what's represented here today.
In addition...
(all whooping)
- ...you're playing for reward.
- ALL: Yes!
- Tell us, Jeff.
- The winner will be taken
-to the sanctuary,
-LAUREN: What?
Where good things happen.
- Ooh!
- PROBST: You will feast
on spaghetti...
- Ooh, yes!
- With meat sauce,
chocolate cake.
- Oh!
- No!
PROBST: Carrot cake.
- Oh, my God!
- (cheering)
That's your favorite.
Wait a minute. Shocker.
- Carrot cake!
- PROBST: Carrot cake
over chocolate cake?
- LAUREN and HEIDI: Yes!
- Oh, yeah. - Oh, no.
I'm-I'm choc...
I-I like chocolate.
- What about the frosting?
- Carrot cake.
I mean, that's exciting.
Cake, just cake, in general.
Both of them.
- CARSON: Wow.
- Worth playing for?
- ALL: Yes!
- PROBST: All right.
- Let's draw for spots. We'll get started.
- HEIDI: Oh.
- Wow. - Oh.
- Here we go.
♪ ♪
All right, here we go.
Final five, immunity
and reward at the sanctuary.
Survivors ready?
Go!
First, you're going for key
number one on that first level.
So you're going up and down
to get to it.
There's Carson,
there goes Carolyn.
Heidi's there.
Here comes Yam Yam.
Lauren's there.
Once you untie it,
you head all the way to the top
to get key number two.
It's Carson and Heidi.
Carolyn right on their tail.
Here comes Lauren
for key number two.
Yam Yam now heading up
Heidi has number two.
Carson has number two.
Once you have two,
you head down to three.
Carolyn has her second key.
Lauren has her second key.
Yam Yam working
on that second key.
Heidi has key number three.
Carson has it.
Carolyn's got it.
Here comes Lauren.
She's got key number three.
Yam Yam dead last,
but he's in it.
You've got three of your
four keys. Still one key left.
It's Heidi
through the knots first.
Working on that fourth
and final key.
Gonna have to fling it.
Carolyn has her knots done.
She's working
on that fourth key.
Here comes Carson.
Lauren's in on it.
Everybody now working on
their fourth key except Yam Yam.
He's still working on the knot.
Carson! That's how you do it.
Heidi has hers.
This challenge is on.
Heidi working on her chest.
Carson working on his chest.
Here goes Yam Yam.
He's through the knots.
Oh, my God.
PROBST:
Carson has his chest unlocked.
Now you're gonna use that rope
and try to drop that ladder.
Heidi has her chest open.
It is Heidi and Carson.
- (grunts) All right.
- PROBST: Lauren has hers.
Carson does it with one tug.
Heidi does it. Wow.
We have got a challenge.
They are side by side.
- (grunting)
- PROBST: Lauren has hers open.
Yam Yam still working to get
his fourth key. So is Carolyn.
- (Carolyn yells)
- Once you have the knots done,
you can go up.
Heidi's good. She's up.
Carson's good. He's going up.
It is Heidi to the puzzle first,
Carson one step behind.
Lauren's got it.
Drop that ladder.
Untie those knots, Lauren.
Let's go!
Carolyn and Yam Yam,
the only two people left.
- Come on!
- PROBST: Carolyn has been so close.
Yam Yam has his key. Yam Yam
gonna get in this now.
- Carolyn close once again.
- Oh! My God.
PROBST:
Carolyn, keep working now.
Now Lauren's in on the puzzle.
Breathe, love. You got this.
- You got this.
- PROBST: Final five challenge.
You make it to four,
it's a whole new ball game.
Yam Yam has it. Pull on it.
Yam Yam has his ladder down.
- Carolyn, you're still in it.
- (yells)
- Will not...
- PROBST: But you got to get a move on.
You got to get that last key.
- (yells)
- Fling it!
It is Heidi, Carson.
- HEIDI: We got this.
- And Lauren on the puzzle.
Here comes Yam Yam. He's gonna
be in on the puzzle now.
- (yelling)
- PROBST: There it is!
- Carolyn! Carolyn has her fourth and final key.
- (yells)
Heidi trying to find another
piece, and she's got one.
It's Heidi trying
to catch Carson,
Yam Yam trying to catch Heidi,
- Lauren trying to get in it.
- Jeff, am I still in this?
You are, Carolyn.
One step at a time.
- (whoops)
- Drop that ladder first.
It is Carson in the lead,
but Heidi right on his tail.
This is close.
Carolyn drops her ladder.
- There you go!
- I just want to get up there.
PROBST: It is Carson
barely in the lead,
maybe one or two pieces.
And Yam Yam not far behind.
Yam Yam making a go of this.
This challenge is far from over.
You are in it.
Here comes Carolyn.
Everybody gonna be in
on the puzzle now.
Final five, day 24,
Survivor 44. You win this,
you're in the four.
You can't be voted out.
Carson has completed the circle,
the outer edges. Now he's got
the middle to fill in.
You get to four,
anything can happen.
Carson's struggle now
is keeping that puzzle together.
He's got a flimsy
outside structure.
Heidi still fighting
with another piece.
Heidi working to catch Carson.
Can she do it?
Yam Yam has hit a roadblock.
- Lauren has slowed down.
- Come on, Lauren.
You can't slow down very long
in this challenge,
or you're out of it.
What am I doing?
PROBST: Carson getting
closer and closer to the finish,
if he can
keep his puzzle together.
The hardest part about
building it from the outside
is what Carson is gonna battle,
and that is
keeping the pieces together
when you add another one
in the middle.
Carson with another piece.
He's down to three pieces.
Heidi unable
to gain ground on him.
Oh, yes!
Okay, I got one. I'm happy.
I'm... I am really proud
of myself right now.
PROBST:
Carson down to his last piece.
Come on, Carson.
- I see it.
- For the win.
Jeff.
Carson has it!
- Carson wins his second.
- Good job!
-Individual immunity,
-Thank you.
Guaranteeing him a spot
in the final four.
- Ah!
- Good job.
PROBST: And lots of different
ways he could get to three
where he could plead his case
to the jury. Wow.
All right, Carson, come on over.
- Yes.
- (Carson laughs)
- Good job, baby.
- Thank you.
For the second time, Carson,
individual immunity is yours.
You are safe.
You are in the four. You have
a big decision to make 'cause
you're going to the sanctuary
where you're gonna refuel
not just your spirit,
- Mm-hmm.
- But your body.
- Yeah. Right.
- Pasta, carrot cake,
chocolate cake.
Choose one person,
and you're only
going to bring one person.
So, two people are gonna
go to the sanctuary.
Three are gonna
be left behind at camp
to conspire
or do whatever they do.
- CARSON: Yeah.
- PROBST: Who's it gonna be?
I'm sorry to everyone,
but Yam Yam, you're my pick.
- Sorry, guys.
- PROBST: Yam Yam, come on over.
CARSON: I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- Good. Go.
Ooh!
Oh, thank you.
PROBST: All right.
Grab your stuff, head out.
Boat will take you to the
sanctuary where you will have
a great afternoon.
You will return
back in time for Tribal Council.
- All right. - Thank you, Jeff.
- Thank you, Jeff. Thank you.
- PROBST: Enjoy. Well earned.
- Love you.
Good job.
Carolyn, Lauren, Heidi,
Tribal Council tonight
where somebody will be
the 14th person voted out
of Survivor 44.
Grab your stuff.
Head back to camp.
- Thank you.
CARSON: To actually pull out
the win when I needed it most
in this game...
It feels incredible.
And to know
that I have a guaranteed spot
in the final four
and no one can vote me out?
I mean, I'm just so proud
of pushing myself
to get to this point.
So now, I need to set myself up
in the best position
I can be in
in order to win this game.
♪ ♪
- (Carson sighs, gasps)
- (Yam Yam laughs)
- Oh, my gosh.
- Oh.
CARSON: So happy. (Laughs)
Yes.
CARSON: Going to the sanctuary,
where good things happen,
I was ecstatic.
- YAM YAM: You're gonna take the cake now? Yes!
- Of course.
- Yes!
- You're kidding? That's what I start with.
I mean, I was in heaven.
And to know that
by winning the necklace,
I'm going to the final four
feels pretty amazing.
We are.
Yes. This is awesome.
YAM YAM:
We're like this crazy duo
going into a pasta dinner date.
It's so much fun.
I was so
freaking happy when
I saw all that food. I was like,
"Oh, my God."
Yeah. I'm so happy.
Salud.
But the most important thing
was we had the opportunity
to talk about what we're gonna
do tonight at Tribal Council.
How should we go about today?
So, the biggest threat
is Carolyn.
I get that Carolyn
has played an idol,
but is she really a threat?
- Do you... I mean, she might be... I...
- I think...
Mm-hmm.
It was, yeah.
And I think
people are gonna like that.
But I think
between Carolyn and Lauren,
Carolyn is the biggest threat.
She says
she's not playing a big game,
but we all know
she's playing a big game.
She's just being loud and crazy
about it, but that's her game.
She wants us to believe
that she's not in control,
but she knows
exactly what she's doing.
But I feel like the Tika Three
have a better shot
against ourselves than we would
against Heidi
or definitely Lauren.
Now, Lauren needs to go.
I feel like
there's one big target,
and that's Lauren. Lauren has
played a great game.
In addition
to winning immunity twice,
she's also played
a game based off
of building bonds
with people and friendships.
So, Lauren has a lot
of friends on the jury, so,
Lauren could get a lot
of jury votes.
So, tonight, Heidi, me,
you, Carolyn, vote Lauren.
Heidi might do
something different,
but I don't see why anyone would
want to go a different way.
The only way Lauren survives
tonight is if she has an idol.
YAM YAM: I needed Carson
to work with me
to get Carolyn out,
but he's not having it.
I think it's a mistake,
but Carson is like,
"It has to be Lauren,"
so, what am I gonna do?
I hope it doesn't bite me
in the ass, you know?
CAROLYN: Oh, my gosh.
HEIDI: Crazy.
So, Carolyn, I'm confused
why he didn't take you
and he took Yam Yam.
You saved Carson, so I-I would
have guessed it was you.
Yeah, I don't know.
I mean, I think they're working
very closely together.
- Yeah.
- And it's gonna be...
most likely me.
Tonight is definitely hard, not
having the immunity necklace.
I know that people want me out
because I have
two immunity wins,
I won one reward
and I have a lot of allies
on the jury.
So I think that I am a threat,
and other people
know it as well.
So, if I don't find an idol
or come up with something,
I think they're gonna
vote me out tonight.
I'm pretty positive. (Laughs)
- I-I don't want to be...
- HEIDI: It's an opportunity
for us to come up
with something.
- CAROLYN: I don't want to be...
- HEIDI: At this point...
I mean, the only person
we can get is Yam Yam.
- CAROLYN: Mm-hmm.
- LAUREN: But I don't know
because the last vote,
I wasn't in on the vote.
- HEIDI: I wanted Carson out the previous vote.
- What...
You.
The vote was you.
Carolyn is more dangerous
than Carson.
- Yeah.
CAROLYN: Lauren
told me that last Tribal,
Yam Yam was
putting my name out there.
Up until now, I felt
solid with Yam Yam and Carson,
but it sounds like
they might be up to something.
There's always a possibility,
and even
if it's like a one percent
or two percent,
it still scares me!
Hey, I'm dependent on y'all.
If y'all don't vote Yam Yam,
- then...
- I feel like.
Yam Yam's a way bigger threat.
Isn't that what we're doing
at this point, or no?
- Yam Yam is in with everybody.
- HEIDI: I'm trying to think.
CAROLYN: Look at him at Tribals.
- Everyone's laughing, loving him.
- Yeah. I'm-I'm...
- Exactly.
- Should we just...
I've been with Yam Yam
from the beginning,
and I thought
we were going to the end,
but if he's putting my name
out there, everything changes.
Maybe I will vote for Yam Yam.
LAUREN: Hello!
How are y'all feeling?
- Oh, God.
- Good. It was... it was yummy.
YAM YAM: Hi.
YAM YAM: I come back from
the reward, and I see Heidi,
Lauren and Carolyn sitting
by the fire eating rice,
being all sneaky.
And they look at me
super awkward. I'm like,
"What's going on?"
(chopping continues)
YAM YAM: I have to say it
feels awkward coming back.
I feel, like, guilty.
I'm immune.
I have no reason to lie.
I'm voting for Lauren,
regardless
of whatever else happens.
If we look at the jury,
like, I don't...
There's... logic.
Although, the other option
is me, which I know.
- And it's a good possibility.
- Thing is that...
The thing is that...
YAM YAM:
Carolyn, what are you doing?
Are you trying
to put my name out there?
I guess you are 'cause
you're never like this.
So the first thing
I think is like,
"Oh, my God, I'm in trouble."
It's, like, weird.
Like, I go to camp, and...
- No one's talking to me.
- It was weird.
Yeah, very weird.
I feel like something's up.
Fact that Lauren hasn't even
talked to me,
not even tried.
Like, I've never seen
someone give up.
Maybe she's not giving up.
She knows something else is...
Mm-hmm, that's
what I'm thinking.
I know.
If Carolyn and Heidi
are dumb enough
to actually take Lauren...
Yeah.
Carolyn... I don't know.
She drives me crazy sometimes
to work with
because she doesn't
have a filter, and
she is unpredictable, doing
random things all the time.
And now, she's causing paranoia
to where I'm not really sure
voting Lauren out
is the best option.
I was thinking. I was like,
"Hey, would it make sense
"to talk to Lauren
and tell her to vote
for someone else just in case?"
CARSON: I think that
might be a better play
than letting her
just vote for you.
YAM YAM:
The plan is to vote for Lauren.
Lauren is a big threat
to win this game.
But I need to make sure
that if Lauren plays an idol,
I don't get voted out.
And if that means
Carolyn goes instead of me,
I'm okay with that.
Yeah.
It's me or you.
(laughing): Yeah.
(chopping resumes)
LAUREN: I...
He's not...
I'll be willing
to vote wherever.
Yam Yam and Carolyn...
They're throwing out
each other's name,
but I don't know
what to believe.
They bicker a lot, but
I think it's like a family
bickering, you know? Like,
I argue with my sister
all the time,
and we come back together,
and we-we know
that we still have this bond
that's deeper than the fighting.
So I think maybe
that's what it is.
You know, there's deep bonds
here. There's deep connections,
and... but deep down
inside, I think
they're still together
as one Tika family.
So, at this point,
the only way to make sure
that I stay in this game
is to find an idol.
I just keep thinking
about my family.
And my sons,
before I came out here said,
"Finding the idol is like
playing hide-and-seek.
You know, like, the idols are
hiding, and you are seeking."
So, I'm a fighter
so I'm not gonna give up.
I'm fighting for my boys.
I'm fighting for my family.
Like, this is
what I am here for,
and I'm gonna do everything
I can to make it
to the end.
I'm just worried. I'm, like...
CARSON: Yeah.
Tonight is
a very important vote.
This will determine who's
going to be in the final four.
For me, the best route
is to try to keep Tika intact.
But Carolyn is clearly
upset with Yam Yam, so,
who knows what Carolyn could do?
CAROLYLN: I'm not kidding.
I'm not, either.
CARSON: It's crazy that
with only five people left,
it could be
so up in the air right now.
I've always felt like I've known
where the votes are going,
but this time,
other than myself,
anyone could be going home.
♪ ♪
All right.
So let's start with Carson.
Because, Carson,
by winning immunity today,
you guarantee yourself
a spot in the final four.
You cannot be voted out.
You will either win your way,
somebody will take you,
or you'll make fire
and have a shot at it,
which makes tonight's vote
so important, Lauren.
Was it crazy at camp knowing
that "if I can
just get to four..."
You're already laughing.
LAUREN: To be 100%
honest, I don't think it was
crazy or chaotic at camp
or anything.
I'm... Jeff,
I'm probably the one
that's gonna go home tonight.
PROBST: How do you know that?
- What transpired?
- Because, I mean,
we have three Tikas here.
They're all close.
They're connected,
they're aligned.
My girl Jaime left yesterday,
and I have a target on me,
and it's just been known.
No one came to speak to me,
which was kind of weird
to me just because,
like, if I'm the one
going to the jury,
you would want
to be talking to me, right?
- Nobody t... Okay.
- I did. - I did.
They-they talked to me,
but it wasn't like a,
"This is who we're gonna
vote for tonight."
I felt like
we had conversations.
Yeah, I'm shocked.
I really... I really am.
And I know, Lauren,
it's been hard,
me and you, with trust,
but I felt like today,
I know I took you aside, and
I made time to speak with you.
LAUREN: I... It wasn't like
the conversations
we would normally have.
You know, like, there was names.
There were names,
but it was just no solid plan.
I-I, like, I... I'm sh...
I really am. I-I...
I just... I didn't... I don't...
- I don't feel...
- I felt like we all talked.
PROBST:
Carson, something's off tonight.
It started from the moment
Lauren sat down and said,
"No one talked to me." And then,
suddenly, everybody said,
"What are you talking about?
What are you talking about?"
So what's going on
that I'm missing?
I'm not sure, Jeff. I feel like
there could be something
at play tonight.
Even Lauren not approaching me.
Like, if I were ever
in that position,
I'd be talking to everybody.
Maybe it is a facade.
I don't know.
PROBST: So, Heidi, is the threat
of an idol what is making this
so unsettling?
I think anybody here
could have an idol.
I think
we all search all day long,
so any of us.
- Not me.
- Could have something in their pocket right now.
It could be Lauren,
and it will be a great play
on her part
- if she does have something.
- Lauren, what do you make
about the uncertainty
that maybe you do
have an idol
and this is an elaborate ruse?
Yeah, I mean, we'll-we'll see.
We'll see.
PROBST: I will say
it's a testament
to the gameplay this season
that I think
it's very difficult right now
to know what the truth is.
I don't know
if this is vulnerability
meeting inevitability,
where Lauren's saying,
"It's over,
and I'm just gonna
let you see it,"
or if it's maybe
one of the biggest moves
about to happen because
nobody here seems to know
for sure if there's an idol,
and if so, who has it.
It definitely...
will be amazing
to see something happen.
But that "amazing"
might be me going home,
so I don't want that to happen.
So, Yam Yam,
you're saying tonight,
you think it is Lauren or you?
(sighs) From my reaction
coming into camp,
I feel like that,
'cause everybody knows
there's one plan, and one,
uh... and one plan B. Like,
let's get real, you know? Like,
that's what I feel,
and no offense to you,
because I feel like
I'm the other plan.
If it's me or if it's you,
it sucks that it's going down
like it happened today.
It-it shouldn't have happened.
Like, today,
the energy shouldn't have been
where it was.
I don't know. It's so hard.
I'm-I'm really taking this
very personal.
It's, like, really...
it-it hurt.
How are you feeling now, Lauren?
I mean,
I feel like I knew coming
into today,
if I didn't win, like,
it was gonna be it, so...
PROBST: And if you're
right, to get to day 24,
on one hand,
is pretty remarkable.
And I'm super proud.
(Lauren sniffling)
My main thing coming out here
was to know, like,
that my boys were gonna
be proud of me. (Cries)
And I think they will be.
Like, I was giving
Frannie vibes, man.
I won two immunities
and a reward.
Like, I feel like a boss,
you know?
Like, I did awesome out here,
and, like, I'm so proud
of just who I've become,
you know,
and, like,
how much I've grown here.
Like, I didn't think I was gonna
be able to do that, Jeff.
Like, did you see me? (Laughs)
I did.
I was killing it.
And, I mean, like,
I never would have imagined
to be here.
PROBST: I'm always
trying to find new ways
to connect to somebody who
thinks they might want to play.
That speech you just gave
is the best inspiration
for why to play,
and it was one sentence.
"I'm so proud
of who I have become."
Yeah.
- PROBST: Not who I was or am.
- Right.
"I became."
You transformed out here.
LAUREN: Most definitely.
Like, I'm a single mom, right?
So I'm like,
"I can do everything by myself.
I don't need anybody
to help me."
But then I realized very quickly
that I needed my Ratu people,
or I needed, like,
everybody here,
like, to help me get to the end,
and if it wasn't for them,
like, I wouldn't be here.
You know, and, like,
just transforming in that way
and realizing, like,
I don't need all of the extra.
And even my kids.
Like, they don't need all
of the extra things that I'm...
I'm continuously trying
to give them.
Like, I work so hard
each and every day
to provide for them, and, like,
I go above and beyond.
But even knowing that, like,
we don't even need
all of those things.
Like, we can survive just off
of, like, very little
and still be happy. (Crying)
It's amazing, and this
experience has just been, like,
life-changing for me,
and I'm so thankful
and so grateful.
Thank y'all. (Laughs)
Y'all ready for the vote?
(laughing)
PROBST: And on that note, it is
time to vote. Lauren, you're up.
(sniffling)
♪ ♪
I'll go tally the votes.
If anybody has an advantage
or an idol
and you want to play it,
tonight would be the last night
you can do so.
Jeff.
- Just kidding.
- Oh. (Laughs)
(laughter)
Don't have anything.
I'll read the votes.
First vote: Yam Yam.
Lauren. One vote Yam Yam,
one vote Lauren.
Heidi. That's one vote Yam Yam,
one vote Lauren, one vote Heidi.
Lauren.
Fourteenth person voted out
of Survivor 44:
Lauren.
Need to bring me your torch.
Oh!
Lauren, the tribe has spoken.
No...
- Love you, Lauren.
- Good job. Good job.
Well, you've made it
to the final four.
Tomorrow, you'll compete
- in your final immunity challenge.
- Thank you.
Try to get some sleep.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp. Good night.
It feels great to come out here
and make my family proud.
I made it 24 days here
on an island.
How awesome is that?
Even though I'm not the Sole
Survivor, I'm still a winner.
And I'm just so grateful
that I was blessed
with this opportunity
to come out here and play.
♪ ♪
Come on in.
Here they come.
The final four.
Are those tears in your eyes?
Yeah. (Laughs) Yeah.
♪ ♪
Carolyn, what's the emotion
as you walked up the steps?
Um...
just walking up...
(sniffling) and knowing
that I would be here at the top.
And just...
that dream that I would be here,
but not necessarily thinking
that I could and that now I am.
It's just... it's overwhelming.
It's-it's...
There's just so much emotion,
and, like, we're up here
in this view, and, like,
we all just dreamed about this.
And it's just, we're here.
(sniffling)
I'm here.
PROBST: This makes me so happy
because you're right.
The view alone...
We saved this for the last
'cause it's the greatest view
in Fiji.
A classic Survivor challenge
has become one
of the most iconic challenges
in our arsenal.
You will compete for it.
Potentially worth
a million dollars.
Shall we get to your final
immunity challenge?
First things first.
Carson, I'm coming for it.
Like they say,
"You go to the power."
I'm coming to you.
You got the power.
For the last time,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna have one hand
tied behind your back.
On my go, you're gonna
drop a ball down a chute.
It will spiral to the bottom.
You'll catch it, put it back in.
At regular intervals,
we will add another ball,
making it more difficult.
If at any point a ball drops,
you're out.
Last person left standing
wins immunity,
is guaranteed a spot
at that final three,
where you will get a chance
to plead your case
to your jury
about why you deserve it...
The title of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars.
Plus, you have all the power.
You decide who sits next to you
in that number two spot
and who you force to make fire
for the third and final spot.
Biggest challenge of the season.
All right, give you a minute
to get ready, and we'll go.
Let's do it!
All right, everybody is belted.
Got one hand behind your back.
We are ready to go.
Final four immunity challenge
begins right now.
Everybody grab one ball.
And drop it in your chute.
This challenge...
is on.
This is the easy part.
This is the warmup.
You don't want to drop here.
You have one job:
Just follow one ball.
Where it gets more difficult
is adding a second ball.
Huh.
The gates alternate
so it's always going to be
left, right,
left, right, left, right.
Remember that.
All about concentration.
If your ball drops, it's over.
Your fate will be in the hands
of somebody else.
Aah!
In a moment, you're gonna
add a second ball,
and you'll have 15 seconds
anywhere in that window.
And if you drop
during that window,
you're still out.
All right, you have 15 seconds
to add a second ball.
Carson drops. Heidi drops.
Carolyn drops. Yam Yam waiting.
He drops.
Everybody now with two balls.
Now it got
a little more difficult.
Now you have
to really pay attention.
- (screams)
- Carolyn,
remember...
Left, right, left, right.
(screaming)
That's it, Carolyn.
That's how you do it.
- (Carolyn yelps)
- Everybody looking great.
Stay on it. One gate,
then the other gate.
One gate, then the other gate.
Yam Yam Very calm.
Always trying
to improve your spacing.
You want as much time
in between balls as possible.
Day 25 of Survivor 44.
Heidi the only person
who has not won
individual immunity.
What a time
to win it right here.
Carolyn drops.
- She's the first out.
- Aah!
We're down to three.
(Carolyn grunts)
Carolyn, one tiny mistake.
It is now Carson, Heidi
and Yam Yam.
All right, in a moment,
we're going to add a third ball
and the pace is gonna
get a lot faster.
You have 15 seconds
to add a third ball.
Heidi drops immediately.
So does Carson.
Yam Yam taking his time,
waiting.
Yam Yam drops.
Everybody now with three balls.
And now you can feel
the intensity kick in.
Balls are coming faster.
Got to respond more quickly.
♪ ♪
Stay on it.
This could be worth
a million dollars.
That's how much
is at stake right now.
You're doing great.
Do not trip.
All right,
you have 15 seconds to drop
a fourth ball
anytime in that window.
Heidi drops her fourth.
Carson has four.
Yam Yam has four.
Everybody now at four balls.
We're in it now.
Yam Yam drops.
He's out. We're down to two.
It is Carson and Heidi
fighting for immunity.
Stay on it, you two.
Keep fighting.
You got nothing else going on
in your life right now
but this challenge.
Carson is out! It's over!
- Heidi wins her first individual immunity!
- Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
- It could not come at a bigger time.
- HEIDI: Yes! Yes! Yes!
- Oh.
- PROBST: Guaranteed herself a spot
in the final three
of Survivor 44.
What a finish.
(sighs)
- Heidi, get over here.
- Ah!
Aah! My girls are gonna scream.
- Ah.
- I want to know this feeling.
You did not win a challenge
until just now,
and it couldn't be
a bigger challenge.
- You are in the final three.
- Yes! Oh, my God!
Yeah, so...
Yeah, I have the power.
I have been so close
in every freaking challenge.
It's like
I finally pulled through.
I'm so blessed and excited.
Wow! This is like
a dream come true on day 25!
(sighs) - PROBST: Heidi,
you're in the final three.
You will get a chance
tomorrow night
to plead your case
to a jury of your peers
about why you deserve
to win this game.
Before we get there,
though, tonight,
you will decide
who gets the number two spot,
- Mm-hmm.
- Who you bring with you to the final three,
and who you are gonna force
to make fire at Tribal Council
to earn their way
into that final three spot.
Unless I make fire.
(sighs)
- PROBST: Would be a big move.
- HEIDI: Yes.
PROBST: And why?
HEIDI: Um,
a lot of people
have big résumés here.
This builds and helps me.
But making fire and winning it...
It's like the cherry
on top of everything.
So I would 100% consider it.
I have not made my mind,
but I'm confident,
so, who knows?
We'll see what happens tonight.
All right,
everybody head back to camp.
I will see you tonight
at Tribal Council
for a big night.
Grab your stuff. Head out.
- Congrats.
- Thank you so much. Thank you so much.
Ah!
This is, like,
that extra boost that I really
needed to have the power
and the control of my own game.
I have to really make
a humongous decision
to see who I send to make fire.
How do I position myself to win?
Did I do good enough already,
or should I put myself
and risk it
into the fire-making tonight?
♪ ♪
YAM YAM: Congratulations.
CARSON: That's... Me, too.
That was awesome. Great job.
HEIDI: Winning the very last
immunity challenge
feels amazing. And
I'm pretty sure
none of the Tika members
saw it coming.
I mean, there's three of them,
and all of a sudden,
the one that was flying solo
has the power to decide
who's making fire tonight.
- What?
- Oh!
Yeah.
L-Let me ask you guys,
anybody wants to make fire?
Maybe make my life easier.
Sounded like
you wanted to make fire.
I am, I'm considering it,
but I just got to practice.
- So if anybody, at some point...
- I like, I like making fire.
Okay. Let's all practice
and let's see what happens.
There's a lot
on my mind right now.
I just have to make sure
I do what's best
to position myself
to win tomorrow.
CARSON:
Not being able to pull through
at the very last challenge
kind of sucked,
but considering
no one can vote me out,
I at least
have a chance to make fire.
So I'm trying to be optimistic.
I know that
I am the biggest threat,
so I'm just trying
to be as prepared as I can
to go against whoever,
'cause I feel like,
regardless of who it is,
I'm probably making fire.
But I'm not very good at it,
I've figured out.
(chuckles) It's so weird.
I mean, I was able to make fire
in three minutes at home
with a flint and machete,
and here
I'm struggling.
I haven't even gotten a flame.
Maybe it's that I'm just
not confident in myself.
I do struggle
with self-confidence, um...
And I've always been
someone who struggles with...
...pulling through.
And to think
that I would allow myself
to fail at the very last second
just is heartbreaking,
'cause I feel like
I will win the million
if I get to the end. And just
knowing that
I might not get there
because of my own insecurities
is really hard. But
I'm not gonna give up.
I don't want to let
my own self get in the way
of my success in this game.
YAM YAM: It would be
the best game move for me
to have that little notch
in my résumé...
...of winning
the fire-making challenge.
It's something that
everybody sees you do.
Like, it's not something
that you go to Tribal Council,
you tell the jury about.
It's something that
they're watching. So watching
you make fire,
you're like, "Hey."
That's my hero move, you know?
But making fire
against someone from Tika...
...it's really emotional for me.
You know, we talk about
Carson being this big threat.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, well, how do I know that Heidi really thinks that,
- you know?
- Mm-hmm.
You think you're going tonight?
I-I don't know.
I do know that people think
that you can
make fire really well.
CAROLYN: I have been
making fire
for the last five years,
practicing for this day.
Am I good, though?
I think I am.
But out here,
I never wanted to, like,
rattle the tribe and
sneak off
and make fire and practice.
So today, I have to.
I don't know what Heidi thinks.
I hope she picks herself.
And then who?
I won.
Part of me wants
to be brought to the end,
but part of me doesn't.
And I want
to fight my way there.
And it would be so wonderful
to have struggled at...
...pretty much...
...pretty much every challenge,
and then to win one
would feel really great.
Carson's the master
of feeding it. For sure.
You're the master
of the quick start.
So is mine. (Sniffs)
I'm on an incline, man.
No, you're not.
You're in a perfect crevice.
I feel comfortable making fire,
and so does Carolyn.
But I saw Carson,
day one, doing the fire...
He no good.
When Carson and I
made fire, day one...
Watch me fail really bad.
(laughs)
You're trying it.
You're not failing.
...I saw him
destroying that flint
like it was a piece of meat.
I was like, "Dude,
you don't go at it
like that, you know?
You-you caress it with your,
with your steel."
CARSON: Yeah.
YAM YAM: I don't want to
see him fail in front of everyone.
That's not what friends do.
CARSON: That's really good.
You're gonna do it now.
CARSON: Yam Yam
could very well be the person
going against me in fire today.
And to know
that his heart
is in the right place
just really makes me
feel good, because
I don't know if I would
do that for someone else.
(crying)
I struggle with
seeing people suffering.
And seeing Carson do so well
in this game, and be so strong,
and be so amazing
at everything he tackles
and then seeing him
give up at the end,
I wouldn't wish that on anyone.
I want Carson to go out
giving everything he has in him.
And if it means that I need
to teach him my tricks,
and he wins over me,
is it a bad move?
It's not important to me if
it's a bad move or a good move.
It's something that I really,
honestly wanted to do.
I don't know why
you're even helping me, but...
I really,
I really appreciate it.
I'm here for you, dude.
I'm here for you.
We've been here for each other
since day three.
There's no reason
why that needs to stop.
(laughs)
May the best Tika win.
CARSON: Just the fact that
he would help me in a situation
where it would be
an easy win against me,
it's pretty amazing
and really speaks to,
I think, how this game
goes beyond just the money.
Do you want us
to watch the other way, Heidi?
I'm making the decision,
so it doesn't matter.
This game is about risks,
but you
got to take calculated risks.
I feel comfortable
with my own skills.
Fire.
But someone else could be just
a little bit faster than me.
That's amazing.
HEIDI:
I've seen Yam Yam making fire.
He looks solid.
Carolyn also says she's decent.
I feel like
Carson is the only one that
is a little bit of
I have no idea
if he's good or not.
He's an Eagle Scout, though,
so he knows, probably,
a lot about fire,
compared to everyone else.
So I'm weighing everything.
If I win the fire,
I think I have the best case
to win
the whole million dollars,
but I have
to win the fire first.
So this is a big decision.
My husband and I
usually have
these conversations,
"What would you do?"
And I wish I could just
get some inspiration from him.
Would he tell me to do it
or would he tell me
to not be silly?
I want to go
with my own gut here,
and I just have to live with it.
It may be the million-dollar
decision where I win it
or it may be the million-dollar
decision where I lose it,
but I have to be comfortable
with the decision I make.
Do I want
to take that risk or not?
I don't know.
♪ ♪
All right.
Tonight, all of the power
sits with you, Heidi.
So let's review.
We do our final
immunity challenge.
It's Simmotion, a classic.
Survivor final four challenge
that anyone can win.
It came down to you and Carson.
You won your first
individual immunity win.
You have a spot
at the final three.
You also get to decide
who you force to make fire.
But at the end of the challenge,
you said, "I'm going to consider"
"a risky idea
and give up my spot,
and actually go make fire
against somebody else."
So now that
you've had all afternoon,
let's just start there.
Did you contemplate
that more today?
A hundred percent.
I mean, when we got to camp,
after the challenge,
we started practicing.
And up until now,
I'm, like, still like,
"What's gonna happen?
Am I gonna do it or not?"
- I-I'm still wondering my options here.
- Right now?
Yes.
- Is that true?
- HEIDI: It's true.
I haven't told anybody
what I'm doing.
- Wow.
- HEIDI: Um, so it's gonna be
new news for everyone,
including myself.
- All right, let's talk about the pitch everybody made.
- Yeah.
Yam Yam, you talked
to Heidi, I'm guessing.
What was your pitch?
(clicks tongue, exhales)
It's complicated,
you know, because...
...I like making fire.
I'm a pyro.
I like flames,
I like striking it,
but I also want to be safe.
So we talked about
the possibility of
the success that might
bring to any of us.
That's something
that is undeniable,
and it's something
that the jury is watching.
PROBST: So, Carolyn, what
was your pitch? Yam Yam says,
"Hey, man, I'm good with fire
if you want, put me over there."
CAROLYN: Heidi, at one
point, said, "Anybody who wants
"to volunteer and maybe
make this a little bit easier,
and just say, 'Hey,
I'm interested in doing fire.'"
I feel like a lot of people
were coming forward
wanting to possibly do fire
because of
how it may look in the end.
And I believe
we all felt pretty confident.
Carson, how about you?
Mm, I don't know
how comfortable I am
with making fire, and,
um, that's me being honest.
I made it, and I can do it,
but I think it starts
getting in your head,
and then all the pressure, like,
kind of starts piling on.
But I think for me, my pitch
really revolved around the idea
that it might
make more sense for her to,
you know, put herself
in the position
to go against someone
who has been in control.
So if I were in her position
and, like, had played her game,
I would put myself up there.
I know making the fire
and winning this...
It's another bucket list item
for your résumé.
I don't want second,
third or fourth.
I want one.
I want first, Sole Survivor.
It is a big decision.
Am I nervous?
Yes, I'm very nervous.
PROBST: Are you ready
to make the decision?
- I'm ready.
- PROBST: All right.
Who are you going to put
in that number two position
that's going to be
in the final three tomorrow?
They will get a chance
to plead their case
and they
will not be making fire.
I am going to put there...
...Ms. Carolyn,
and I hope she enjoys it.
PROBST: Carolyn, how does
that feel? You have made it
to the final three.
There is nowhere
else to go. Now it becomes
- about pitching your case.
- CAROLYN: I know, I know.
I-I don't have words right now.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- PROBST: Don't be sorry.
- I don't have words,
'cause I-I didn't expect this.
Me, especially.
I'm, like, that kid who, like,
couldn't shut up
in fifth grade, who...
(sniffles) was separated
from the rest of the class
because I was
so weird and different.
And people just said,
like, "Just stop talking.
Why can't you just be normal?"
And just to be here at the end,
it-it feels amazing.
What do you say to the little
girl who was called weird?
(laughs)
That it's okay to be you.
Because that was my goal
when I came into this.
That's all I wanted to do.
And to think that
I'm here without trying
to hide myself
or be a different person,
it's like I don't need to hide,
in real life or here.
It's too much, like...
No, it's not too much.
It's perfect.
You just learned a huge lesson,
which is you are okay
- exactly as you are.
- (laughs)
All right, Heidi, you decide
what you want to tell us next.
So, I'll say one of the people
who will make fire.
The first person
I'll put there will be Carson.
PROBST: Earlier, Carson,
you said the pressure mounts.
Is the pressure real?
Yeah, it's pretty scary.
I mean, I'm-I'm going to do my
best, and that's all I can do.
That's gonna be the test,
is whether
I can pull through myself.
It doesn't depend on anybody
else here. It depends on me.
And that's where the pressure
is really hitting. (Chuckles)
All right, so, Heidi,
we have one person
making fire is Carson.
The big question is
are you gonna take Carson on
in a showdown
or are you gonna
take what you earned
and keep your spot
in the final three
and put Yam Yam against Carson?
Who's gonna take
the other spot in fire?
So I've been thinking about this
ever since you put this on me.
And the reason
I put Carson there
is 'cause he's
a great player, right?
So I am going to do fire
with Carson.
Wow.
Damn.
HEIDI: I'm taking a chance.
I don't want two, three or four.
I want one.
And I think I will
have an easier time convincing
everyone to vote for me
if I can beat Carson
- making the fire.
- PROBST: I got to say,
if I'm at home
watching right now,
I'm like,
"Give me a big bowl of popcorn."
- My family's gonna lose it that I'm doing this.
- (laughing)
Yam Yam, how does that feel?
You have made it
to the final three.
Five minutes ago,
I couldn't believe Carolyn
was speechless, 'cause this is
not something that Carolyn does.
And I feel
the same freaking way.
Like, to be
100% honest with you,
I never imagined, ever,
that I would be in a position
to talk to the jury.
And I freaking love it.
(laughs)
So, Heidi,
you and Carson are gonna
take part
in a fire-making showdown.
The winner will be
the third and final person
in our final three.
All right, take your spots.
It's up to you which one
you pick. They're identical.
Good luck, Heidi.
No, no, no.
Good luck, guys. You're amazing.
Aah!
I can't believe I'm doing this.
PROBST: All right, I'm
gonna give you two a moment
to take everything in,
get acquainted
with your supplies,
and then we will start
what might be a million-dollar
fire-making challenge.
All right. Big decision
made by Heidi to take on
Carson in
a fire-making challenge.
It's not an exaggeration to say.
You both have the same supplies.
You know the rules.
Build a fire big enough
to burn through that rope.
The person
who does that will sit
in that stool tomorrow night
at the final three.
Are you both ready?
This challenge is on. Go.
CAROLYN: Oh, my gosh.
PROBST: You need heat.
You get that from the friction
of striking that flint,
creating that spark.
Then you need fuel,
which is what you're burning.
You're both going with hessian,
and then you need oxygen.
You got to build that fire
so it breathes.
Heidi quickly going to it.
Getting a spark.
Trying to get a flame.
There's a little flame.
Can she breathe
some life into it? She has.
Now you got to make
that a fire that'll last,
because that hessian burns
quickly, and it will burn out.
There goes Carson now,
trying to get a little spark.
And he's got it.
Can he get a flame?
Got to get something to burn.
Heidi doing a nice job
of nurturing her first flame.
Carson scraping more magnesium.
- Strike it.
- Strike it. Strike.
PROBST: Heidi doing a
nice job, slowly building.
Carson now has a flame.
He's got to get that
to take without smothering it.
Heidi doing a really nice job.
- That flame is starting to grow.
- YAM YAM: That's amazing.
PROBST: She's using kindling,
one or two pieces at a time.
Now Carson trying to get
a couple of pieces of kindling.
Go crazy.
PROBST:
Heidi doing a really nice job
of slowly nurturing that fire
while letting it breathe,
which is essential.
Heidi's building an inferno.
That is a real fire.
Carson's now got a flame going.
- He's putting some kindling.
- YAM YAM: You're both in it.
You're both...
Carson's now in it.
We've got two fires going.
Don't quit.
- Believe in yourself.
- PROBST: Both players now working quickly
to get more kindling in there.
Carson's flame is starting
to grow, but he's got
- to get more height quickly.
- CAROLYN: Hurry up.
PROBST: Heidi's flame
is all over that rope,
- and it's over.
- Yes!
- (laughing)
- Oh, my God.
PROBST: Heidi has done it.
One of the fastest fires
we've ever had.
Heidi has taken
the spot in the final three.
- I'm sorry, Carson. I love you. I love you, sweetie.
- No, no. No, Heidi.
- I-I would have done the same thing if I were you. Yeah.
- I love you.
- Carson, I got to say, your fire was lasting.
- Yeah.
You were just a little late,
but you built a decent fire.
- Yeah.
- PROBST: Nothing to be ashamed of with that fire.
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
- Heidi was on fire with her fire.
I can't believe I just did that.
PROBST: Heidi, that is
- the fastest fire ever made...
- (squeals)
- Oh, my God.
- ...on Survivor.
Oh, my God. That's awesome.
YAM YAM: Good job. That's great.
LAUREN: That's crazy.
(laughing)
That is remarkable.
- You put your money where your mouth is.
- Yes.
You said, "I came to win."
So you put yourself,
literally, in the hot seat,
and you pulled it off.
- That, in and of itself, is a massive victory.
- ...legend.
But I was so scared
because this is a risk.
Like, you never know if it's
actually gonna work here.
And doing it
feels absolutely amazing.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh. It... I-I have no words. This moment is ridiculous.
- PROBST: All right, Carson, let's talk.
- Yeah.
25 days, and you came
this close to getting
to the final three.
Yeah.
- PROBST: It's a massive achievement.
- Thank you.
And I hope
you have impressed yourself.
Yeah. I mean,
I think everyone here
can attest to my day today.
I was in tears.
- PROBST: Aw.
- I was...
- Aw. I'm sorry.
- Like, I, like, let it out,
because I wasn't
confident in myself.
And, so, for me
to start fire
and at least have something
going against the fastest
fire-making winner ever,
I'm so proud of myself
for challenging myself,
becoming more self-confident,
and that is what
I'm leaving here today.
All right, Carson,
it is time to grab your torch.
Okay.
- So proud. You're amazing.
- Thank y'all.
- Love you.
- CARSON: Love y'all, too.
Carson, the tribe has spoken.
I didn't think I'd be smiling.
- (laughing)
- This is awesome.
- You should be smiling. Good job.
- Thank you.
Good luck, y'all.
- Y'all are amazing.
- You are, too.
Uh, I can't wait to hear it all.
G-Give it your all tomorrow.
All right.
You have made it
to the final three.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
PROBST:
Tomorrow night, the game shifts.
All the power...
Boom, right there.
People you
had a hand in voting out.
They will decide
who wins Survivor 44.
You have one more night
in beautiful Fiji.
I know it's gonna
be hard to sleep, but try,
'cause you want to be
clearheaded tomorrow
when you make your case.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp. Good night.
Thank you.
- Great job, Heidi.
- CAROLYN: Good job, Heidi.
Oh, my gosh.
(laughing)
You all are nuts.
CARSON: To lose against someone
who made the fastest Survivor
fire-making challenge in history
feels pretty awesome.
Even though I didn't
get to the final three,
I'm so proud of myself,
and it's incredible
to be on Survivor and actually
live my dream of playing, so
I'm still kind of pinching
myself that I'm even here.
♪ ♪
YAM YAM: The final three. 44.
Just a few more hours.
Girl, I'm gonna cry.
I'm so freaking scared.
You think?
That's how I feel.
Like, I feel like it's finals,
and I'm gonna, like...
Yup.
I don't want to sound stupid.
- I... Trust me.
- HEIDI: You won't.
- We've all seen...
- You're gonna sound
- more stupid than me?
- CAROLYN: Probably.
Okay. Thank you.
Making it to the final three
on Survivor,
it's freaking awesome.
Not everybody
gets to the final three.
You know how many
get to the final three?
Only three. And I'm one of them.
Now the only thing
I need to do is win the game.
But the biggest hurdle
is tonight. Am I gonna be able
to convince the jury
to vote for me to win?
I decided how I wanted
to get here, and I got here.
But it doesn't matter
what I did,
because it's all
perception here.
It doesn't matter
the way I see it,
because I'm not the one voting.
Now I need to make
the jury members believe
I played a million-dollar game.
My words are my weapons.
I'm gonna
use them to my advantage.
KANE: Yam Yam is a
very perceptive player.
The guy can read
body language from a mile away.
Like, if you fart at the
water well, he knows about it.
He made himself
a part of everybody's plan,
to the point where I could
not get him off the beach.
MATT:
Yam Yam played the middleman.
He had relationships
with most people,
and he was able to sort of,
like, straddle this line
brilliantly, in a way
that no one felt betrayed,
but benefited his game.
BRANDON: Yam Yam
is absolutely hilarious,
and he understands
his game to a T.
Every move that he made
along the way was intentional.
It was all deliberate.
He put himself in the position
where he had the option
to decide what he wanted to do,
and he took advantage of it.
- HEIDI: Let's go!
- CAROLYN: Oh.
YAM YAM: No way.
Don't drop it.
Oh, my God. Thank you so much.
Oh, there's a griddle.
(squeals)
HEIDI: I think the jury
has seen my game.
This was not
an easy ride for me.
I fought every single day
to make it here.
I had to do whatever I could
to survive, and I took risks.
I think making the fire
really boosts my résumé.
- This is our dream.
- Final three breakfast.
- Yes. It's our dream.
- (whoops)
Salud.
I'm proud of my journey.
I'm proud
to make it to final three.
I'm gonna put my heart out there
for the jury to vote for me.
CARSON: Heidi killed it.
She put herself in a vulnerable
position to take me out.
Fastest fire-making ever
in Survivor.
For her to pull through
to the very end gives me
more of a reason
for me to vote for her.
Heidi made
a huge move last night.
Carson was the king.
You take a shot at the king,
you best not miss.
And Heidi didn't miss,
so that makes her the queen.
JAIME: Heidi never gives up.
She is such a strong woman.
If she can articulate
how she ensured her safety
every single time,
she's gonna get my vote.
Are you worried?
Of course I'm worried.
I'm nervous.
I'm scared
of getting tripped up,
not thinking I'm good enough,
not thinking I'm, like, worthy.
All that type of stupid,
like, self-loathing
is gonna be my, like, downfall.
Kind of like how you get
when you're
talking emotions sometimes.
Remember day one,
when you interviewed me?
INTERVIEWER: Yeah, I do.
We're here on day 26.
This is full success.
Did you think
you'd make it this far?
No, not a chance.
I didn't even think
I'd make merge.
Did I think that
my personality would get me...
Uh, no, I didn't,
but it feels amazing.
Coming here was the dream.
Finding an idol was the dream.
All the crazy blindsides
I made happen,
I might as well just win.
I'm ready.
So now
I have to convince the jury
being emotional
was part of my strategy,
and that
it can be taken seriously,
and that being emotional
can be respected in this game.
FRANNIE: I believe that you can
be an incredibly intelligent,
strategic player and a player
who plays with a lot of emotion.
That is what Carolyn did.
She used her emotions
as an advantage.
LAUREN:
Carolyn was such a great player,
authentically, as herself.
Who has played like that before?
I don't know... Carolyn.
If she's self-aware of that,
she'll definitely
get my vote tonight.
JAIME: Carolyn was
all over the place
in the most masterful way.
She let us believe
that she didn't know
what she was doing,
when she knew what she was doing
every single conversation.
And that's brilliant gameplay.
FRANNIE: Everything
is riding on this final Tribal.
I don't want anybody to sit back
and feel like their game
has spoken for itself,
because it hasn't.
YAM YAM:
It is the moment of truth.
MATT: Season 44 was
an absolute banger season.
So my vote is going
to the person
who saw opportunities
and smashed them
out of the park.
BRANDON: I want to see
fireworks. I want to see people
who are hungry for that million.
LAUREN:
I want them to be confident
in their individual game
that doesn't rely
on anyone else.
JAIME: I am hoping the gloves
come off and we get to see
everyone's true colors.
DANNY: This is gonna
be Tyson vs. Holyfield.
There's no way
you can predict this.
CARSON: My vote is on the table.
You've got to grab it.
KANE: I want to see sword
and shield tonight.
This is a fight
for a million dollars,
and I'm ready to watch
the fight of my life.
All right, here we are.
Heidi, Yam Yam, Carolyn.
26 days gets you here,
and now the power
shifts to the jury.
Eight people
that you played alongside
will be casting a vote tonight,
and it's gonna be for the person
they think is most deserving
of the title of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars
that goes along with it.
Your job is to convince them
it's you that deserves
that title and the check.
What did you do
better than the other two?
You have to step up
and claim your game
in order to claim your victory.
If you don't,
you'll get left in the dust.
Jury, your job:
Hold them accountable.
Make them defend their case.
What is it they did
that is better
than the other two people
that they're sitting with?
That's who
deserves to win this game.
Heidi, Yam Yam, Carolyn,
I'm gonna give you a minute
to prepare for their questions,
and then we'll go.
All right, it is time to get
to the final Tribal Council
of Survivor 44.
Social, physical, strategy.
It's fine if we overlap.
Kane, get us started.
- (whoops) (chuckles) Let's go.
- (laughter)
Uh, first off,
I want you guys to know
that we are
all very proud of you.
I think
every single person here,
their vote is up in the air.
So for me to vote for you,
you need
to explain your game to me,
and then you need to
convince me that it is better,
unapologetically,
than the other two people.
So my first question to you
is what do you think
our perception of you is
and do you think it's accurate?
- Yam Yam.
- YAM YAM: What do I think
it is your perception of me?
I think you love me, of course.
(laughing)
I believe that
all of you perceive me
as a happy-go-lucky person,
which I am.
I believe all of you
perceive me as someone
that loves this game and love to
make moves, which is also true.
What I think
the biggest perception of me,
which I think
is the wrong perception,
is that I was following
Carson's steps all the way.
Carson and I did an alliance
day three with Carolyn,
and the perception was,
like, we were a disaster.
But we know
what was the target every time.
- Carolyn also had...
- Can I say something within that?
Towards the beginning
of the merge,
you guys were kind of riding
a little bit of...
- It wasn't like that.
- The wave of the, of the Soka members.
It wasn't like that. That's what
we wanted you to perceive.
We wanted you to perceive
that we were willing
to go with the target
that you chose.
Oh.
So I knew
every single people's vote,
every time we go to Tribal.
Heidi.
So, how do I think
you perceive me? Right?
I think it probably varies
throughout the entire game.
When we started the merge,
I think the perception
was that I was
very much into the strategy.
Then when I got
into the hole that I lost
some of my Soka numbers,
it probably was like,
"Well, Heidi's
no longer strategic.
"She's just
riding everyone's tail
because she has to survive."
But within that hole,
I really was trying my best
to still be strategic.
I tried to really
integrate a little bit
of my social game
to get to where I was.
And at the very end,
which happened yesterday,
I used everything I could
to put myself
in the best position, so I could
have a good speech to give you.
- Okay, Carolyn.
- Carolyn.
So right away, I didn't fit in.
I was a little quirky
and different, and...
and then I found Carson.
And we connected
over genuine realness
and him saying, you know,
"I was that quirky kid,"
and that was day one.
And then I found you,
and I said,
"How in the heck
did he get on my tribe?"
(laughing) - Because we are
so similar, and he is so much,
- and I am so much, too.
- Girl.
But as far as perceptions go,
I know that I was
looked at as, like,
"Girl, like, who is this?"
And I was underestimated
this entire game.
I was playing,
but I was so underestimated
that sometimes
it kind of played into itself,
if that makes sense.
CARSON: And I just want to
give you and Yam Yam props.
You were able to evolve yourself
and make those relationships,
and that's what I'm impressed
with both of you about.
And, Heidi, I didn't
get to really know your game,
'cause I didn't
play with you as long,
but I'd love
to hear your own gameplay
and your own social
relationships you built, too.
Yeah, so we had four Soka
members going into the merge,
but the players that I was with,
we all got targets right away
'cause we were all
strong in some capacity.
I mean, the difference
between their game and mine
is they were on a high.
I suffered
through a heck of a lot,
and that's
the reality of our games.
Very different games.
And we all, the three of us,
I'm proud to say,
we made it here
in very different ways.
We were not always in a high,
and we took advantage
of not being in a high.
We took advantage
of the perception
that you were saving us,
and we were saving ourselves.
But you can see how
Carson is defending you because.
- Carson was a lot of the brains behind that, though.
- YAM YAM: I was gonna get there.
- I was gonna get there.
- Okay.
DANNY: But with all due
respect, I'll tell you right now,
I played my game
compartmentalized, and I take
pride in that, and I have
so much respect for this game,
if my mother was up there
and she had a bad pitch,
she's not getting my vote.
So what I want to hear is
how did you guys use Carson?
'Cause I'm sure
that nothing you guys did
was just going with it.
I used Carson
to get a lot of information,
but I did that
with a lot of you guys.
It wasn't only with Carson,
and I got to eat...
- (laughter)
- because Carson took me.
And that was no mistake
on my part, you know?
But it's not a thing like,
"I use Carson for this."
I use everyone.
And that speaks to my game.
They should have been coming
for me, and they didn't.
Well, your name was
written several times,
and you said you had to survive the
first few Tribals, -It was, it was, it was.
- So...
- That's right.
I thought that was
because I'm pretty.
(laughing)
DANNY: And, Heidi,
for you, who did you use
to propel your game,
as kind of, like, a shield
to move yourself forward?
Thank you for the question.
I think the answer, it's you,
'cause I truly thought
we could work together,
and we did
for almost the entire game.
And I knew you look
physically more fit than I do,
so I knew you will
have a bigger target than me.
So, did I use you as a shield?
100%. 100%, I did.
But that doesn't take away from
the friendship that we created
throughout the game.
Yeah, of course. But, yeah,
it makes sense. Perfect.
FRANNIE:
Um, I love all the strategy,
like, love the numbers, but
I feel like there's a lot more
- to dig into with, like, social.
- Mm-hmm. - Right.
- Yeah.
- So, one thing that we talk about and think about
a lot in this game
is emotions, right?
And on one end,
there is an emotional player,
and on the other end, there is
an intellectual,
strategic player.
And you can use both
effectively in this game.
So I want to understand
from each of you how you managed
your emotions, how you saw them
as a strength or a weakness.
And I would
love Carolyn to start,
because you've been so open
about saying that you are
an emotional person
and an emotional player.
I'm gonna get emotional.
(chuckles)
- Good. Good.
- Yeah, that's a good thing.
When you're actively addicted,
you hold things in.
I didn't express myself.
I didn't know
how to express myself.
what emotions were.
I learned that all
going through treatment.
So there's that spectrum
of you're either strategic
or you're emotional.
You can't be both.
There is no in between.
And honestly,
I just didn't want to do that,
because, to me,
it was way too painful
to go there and numb that.
Yes, there were times
where I knew that
they're gonna expect me
to be emotional right now,
because I cry
when I eat a papaya.
We get rice, I'm crying.
You give me a hug, I'm crying.
I'm so grateful.
That was all real.
But I know
that there were moments
where I needed
people to trust me.
I knew I needed to fake those
tears, and then compose myself.
It wasn't always easy for me.
PROBST: Yam Yam.
So, emotions,
which I have,
I have many emotions.
My happiness, my love, my care,
how do I use this in my favor?
And I don't want to,
like, offend anybody
on the conversations
that I had were real,
but some of you were very
blank when I would talk to you.
Jaime, for example,
was super blank.
Brandon was super blank to me.
- Kane is still like that, you know?
- (laughter)
But how did I knew
if you guys were
telling me the truth or not?
I would take my time
to build real relationship
with each of you
and see how your eye twinkle
when you're talking about
your loved one, or your eye
twinkle when you're talking
about food or about your work.
So when you guys
were lying to me
or not telling me the truth,
that twinkle went away.
So I use your emotions
and your facial expressions
that I knew were real
and compared them
to when they were not real.
And that's why I'm so
successful working with people.
I'm there working
with 25 crazies,
so I'm, like, right at home
when I was next to her.
But in all the best way.
And it was hard. It was scary.
I was like...
(sharp inhale) "Can I do this
in English? Let's see."
But that's how
I use emotions in my favor...
Not only my emotions,
but how I use your emotions
to know what was going on.
Amazing.
PROBST: Heidi.
I'm glad
you asked that question,
because I-I really
want to explain myself,
and I'm gonna get
to the emotions with this,
but the why I'm in Survivor,
why I'm here is
I want to represent people
that sound different,
that look different.
I want to represent
girls out there that want
to be in science
and want to be different.
Right? And with that comes
a whole lot of responsibilities.
Being Latina in science,
I work with all guys,
so I have to keep my composure.
And I have learned
to control my emotions
to be successful at what I do.
So I feel like I have been
in the spectrum of emotions,
but I have tried to control it,
so I can still
represent the best way I can
for the people that I want
to show that they can do this.
LAUREN: And I want to say
thank you so much for sharing that.
And I definitely saw
you controlling your emotions,
and that made you continue on
throughout the game.
- Thank you.
- LAUREN: You know, and you just
externalize it or internalize
it differently than the others.
Um, I just want to, like,
slide one little thing in.
This is less of a question than
it is just, like, a statement.
Um, something I admire
about all of you is you guys
did a really good job of being
yourselves out here. All of you.
- Thank you.
- MATT: Big personalities.
You shared with all of us,
and that's really hard for me.
And I'm, like, so happy
that you get this platform
to, like, really,
really show off who you are.
- That's all I wanted to say.
- Thank you. It's a hot seat, though.
- It is, but... (laughs)
- HEIDI: But thank you.
- We love you.
- PROBST: All right.
Who wants to get us into
the physical part of this game?
Uh, I just want to talk quickly
about the challenges.
You know, I think you all know
that I had a lot of fun
with the challenges,
and I was just curious
how you thought you would come
in and perform in challenges.
And I'll start with Carolyn,
'cause you've been
so open about
your challenge performance
- that I just want to give you a chance to speak.
- Here I am.
- (laughing)
- Yeah, um,
well, first off, let me say,
I'm an athletic person
in real life,
so I'm not joking...
I thought I would do great.
And it was, like,
one embarrassing thing
happened after the other.
Like, I got stuck
in a spiderweb,
and so it was just humiliating.
And I hear your voice, Jeff,
and I had to tune you out,
but I needed to hear it,
like, "Keep going!"
And I'm like, "I know."
And then I got my letter.
"Mom, I hope
you're winning challenges."
It broke my heart reading that,
and it was so hard.
It was so hard.
To see myself,
like, failing at them.
But then, at the same time,
I promised my son I wouldn't
talk poorly about myself,
because that's what I teach him
is positive self-talk.
So all I could do is just accept
that I'm not at that level,
and it's okay.
PROBST: And, Carolyn,
I just want to say, -Amen.
I never see it as humiliating.
I see somebody
giving everything they have.
And anybody who sits at home
and talks smack
about you and the spiderweb
- should come out here and apply to be on Survivor.
- (all agreeing)
Instead of sitting
on your couch talking smack.
(laughing)
- YAM YAM: Yes.
- PROBST: It's not easy.
HEIDI: Seeing Carolyn
trying inspired me,
and I want to use it
to inspire my kids.
Like, this is what you do.
You-you are not gonna
be good at certain things.
You might struggle
with certain things,
but you keep trying.
And she's still here
in the top three.
- So props to you, because you inspire me.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
CARSON: And, Heidi,
let's dig into day 25,
where you not only won immunity,
but you put yourself
in a vulnerable position
to make fire.
- HEIDI: Yeah.
- Even though you didn't have to.
But I want you
to talk about that,
because that was part
of your physical game.
Yeah.
So, thank you for the question,
and I'm so proud
I pulled through that one.
And I think I was perceived as,
"She had a good game,
"but she doesn't
have this in the bag." Right?
I think if I didn't
go for fire yesterday,
I would have
never won this game.
And not that
I'm saying I'm winning,
but it gives me
the best opportunity
to plead my case here,
because I truly think
Carson was very much
the brains of what was
happening with a lot of this.
So I had to make a big move.
And it so happened
that it happened on day 25.
And not only did you just make
fire when you didn't have to,
you made fire the fastest
in the history of Survivor.
That I didn't expect,
but if that's
a record or whatever,
I take it, because
this game is amazing.
And I'll put a plug that maybe
we can make history today,
because
if you vote for me to win,
I will be the oldest
female contestant winner.
- CARSON: Wow.
- So we can make even more history together.
- (laughing)
- Vote for me.
- But thank you for the question.
- CARSON: Yeah.
And, you know, Yam Yam
and Heidi, you made it through
a lot of challenges
that you didn't win.
You know, Yam Yam,
I'll go to you.
Like, how did it feel
to perform the challenges,
maybe differently
than you expected,
but then how was it when
you finally did pull it out?
So, the physical aspect of the
challenge was super scary to me.
Like, super scary, because
I'm not a physical person.
I don't have good balance.
I'm not fast.
I'm afraid of heights.
But I'm coming
from a very physical family.
Like, my father is a cyclist.
My brother
has been athlete of the year
and played in every single
sports team until now.
Like, I am, like, just the kid
that watched TV, you know?
So I had to channel them.
I had to channel their energy,
their words, their strength.
And that's what happened
to the last gasp challenge.
And I had no idea
I had it in me.
I was doing everything
that I could do
to distract from your voice,
which is very supporting,
but it's very annoying
(laughing) - when you're
in the middle of a challenge.
And if I win,
I'll be the first Puerto Rican
male to win tonight.
(laughing)
HEIDI: I love that.
PROBST: All right, let's move
into the last section,
which does involve strategy,
idols, and advantages
and how you use them.
Who wants to get us going?
Yeah. So, Carolyn,
you had your name written down
three times
throughout the game...
The least
out of the three of you.
You were on the right side
of the vote 88.89% of the time.
Very impressive.
Walk me through
the strategy of that.
Um, part of my strategy
was putting my trust in,
one, Carson,
you, who again,
we were so much alike.
- Some of the bickering was kind of play...
- Was on purpose.
We played it up, but a lot
of it, too, it wasn't.
And it was
a risk to work with you,
but still, I was
underestimated so much that
when it came to me finding
that idol, nobody expected that.
Nobody. Plus,
I didn't say a word about it.
But your idol
being played on Carson,
you didn't
need to play on Carson.
You needed to trust me
that Lauren and Jaime
were gonna vote the way they
said, and I told you, like...
CAROLYN: Okay, so
here's the difference is
- do I trust you? Yes.
- Yes.
Did I trust Lauren and Jaime?
No.
But I knew that
I needed Carson here
to assure that Danny went home,
'cause I wasn't gonna
get to the end with you here.
- I needed the three.
- DANNY: Why?
How did I logically
get in your way?
'Cause that's
a very specific thing to say.
Because you were
seemingly running things,
were the one controlling votes.
You were the one
coming up with plans.
You were influencing
Jaime, Lauren, Heidi.
I needed you out.
Cool. Well put.
CARSON: Okay, great. Thank you.
Yam Yam,
you voted 90% of the time
on the right side of the votes.
I've worked with you personally.
I saw how you kind of
controlled your own destiny.
Can you explain how you
continued to have control
throughout this game,
strategically?
This game
is about getting to the end.
If you don't get to the end,
you don't get to win.
And I knew
there were people in the way
of me getting to the end.
So I wanted people
that had the comfort
of writing my name down
not be here
playing the game with me,
'cause they were gonna
get that little feeling,
the good feeling
of writing my name again.
And it was
with the help of everybody,
but it happened
because I wanted it to happen.
So my game is about knowing
who wants to work with me,
who thinks I'm not a threat.
I won a necklace,
and I wasn't a threat,
because I made myself
not a threat.
I really love talking.
I cannot go into a challenge
and push the biggest block
or jump the highest
or do the best balancing.
What I can do
is I can talk, talk, talk, talk,
in a way that
people were comfortable
to feel like,
"He's here just to have fun."
I'm here to have fun,
but I want to win.
And I hope
I make my family proud
and my brother proud,
because he told me,
"They pick you
because of who you are.
"Just be yourself. You're gonna
do okay." That's all I need.
And that's all that
I keep repeating to myself.
I just need to be who I am,
and I'm proud of it.
CARSON: Great. Thank you.
So, Heidi, you were
on the right side of the vote
66.67% of the time.
How did you navigate through
- your game, strategically?
- HEIDI: Yeah.
My strategy coming into this
was not to have this.
Okay?
However, the way it happened,
I had to keep adapting
to survive here.
And the difference
between some of the people here
and myself was like,
"Oh, my God, I'm by myself.
How am I gonna able control it?"
And maybe that's
part of the reason why,
like, I kept my idol
a little bit longer.
So I hope you respect
the fact that
I had to adapt, and it hurt.
It hurt. And you hit
the high highs, it's awesome,
but not until
you hit that low low
is when you truly find yourself
and you realize
this game goes way beyond money.
This game is all about
finding myself
and realizing the growth,
because I've been in the U.S.
almost 20 years,
but when I moved, I struggle.
I couldn't speak English.
I didn't have anything.
And that made me grow.
Like, I see the growth in me,
and now seeing that I'm here,
living my dream, I truly
am living the American dream.
So for those people
that sound different,
look different, want to be
in science and they're girls,
follow your dreams, no matter
what age or who you are.
You're female, male,
whatever age you are, follow
your dreams no matter what.
And that's the reason I'm here.
PROBST: I love this.
Right before
we get ready to vote...
- Carolyn.
- One last hug with the final three.
It's-it's crazy to be here.
- It's a privilege.
- PROBST: You did a great job.
The only thing left to do now
is for the jury vote
for who they think
is most deserving
of the title of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars
that goes with it.
Jury, I'm gonna
give you a moment
to take in everything
you've heard,
collect your thoughts,
and then we vote.