Seriously, both of you guys.
You knew I was paranoid all day.
You did it all day.
Once.
We get back to camp.
I say, "Carolyn,
I need to talk to you."
"Carolyn, I need to talk to you.
"Carolyn, we need to sit down,
and we need to talk
about Tribal Council."
Because the two people
that she trusts the most...
Carson and I...
Left Carolyn out of the vote.
Frannie.
That's three votes Frannie.
Frannie was such a juicy target.
It was impossible
not to vote her out.
I could not resist.
Frannie, the tribe was spoken.
I knew leaving Carolyn
out of this vote was gonna be
bad, and it backfired.
- Right.
- There's nobody here. Like...
No, there's not.
At every... vote.
- And I could. And I could.
- Once. That was once, man.
This is the first time for...
- Yam Yam, you were over that.
- I'm...
This just happened, man.
I feel bad for Yam Yam and
Carson. She's, like, yelling.
I just think
she needs some time.
Dude...
- I'm sorry. Like, just stop.
- Yeah. It...
I don't play.
Let 'em. Go bond with them.
Like, I-I... It's...
Sorry. You guys know what
you were... doing to me.
To find people that you actually
trust and then they betray you?
It's torture.
It is. It's mental torture.
I didn't expect this
from you two, okay?
- Yeah.
- Like, God.
Yeah, it's... I'm so sorry.
They're just
telling me what I want to hear
so I'll vote
with them the next vote.
Do they actually care?
Probably not.
I should just be able to, like,
turn the page and be okay
with it, but I can't.
I don't know what to say.
I just need a break.
I think she thought
she had the perfect game.
- Yeah.
- She was right on every vote so far.
Exactly.
No.
It really wasn't
either of you guys?
- It was not me.
- It wasn't me, I swear.
My vote was big "F"
- and a dotted "I."
- Mine was a little "E" at the end.
I got one vote. I
didn't foresee that coming.
So, I want
to figure out
who put a name on me.
Who has a motive
to put a name on me?
I feel like it was Frannie.
To this point,
I have Heidi, and right now,
she's the only thing
I trust in this game.
Yam Yam? Well...
I don't-I don't...
You know me. I don't...
I don't take it personally
whatsoever.
Ay. It was me.
I put Danny's name down, but
I never
in a million years thought
Danny would still be here.
So, I am gonna lie my way
out of this one
because he's my closest ally,
and I got two votes
at Tribal Council that
I did not see coming at all.
Luckily, I still have my idol,
so I have to somehow
come up with a plan
on how to get out of here
and not be at the bottom
of the totem pole
for the next one.
Inhale.
Finding that total relaxation
and peace.
Exhale.
If you guys are comfortable,
we want to share our gratitude
and use this energy
to amplify it.
Every night, I try to thank
the universe or spirit,
whatever higher power, like,
my ability to see, hear,
speak, breathe, run, jump,
things, like, I take
for granted sometimes, so...
So it was super emotional
after Tribal.
And this game is
really emotional, but
we really are a family out here,
and we are creating real bonds.
I just really appreciate y'all
and your stories
and sharing them with me.
Because we can all come together
and meditate together
and have this really
high-vibe experience,
it does give permission
for us to be super cutthroat.
We are all
cheering each other on,
but battling toe-to-toe
at the same time.
Being here and dealing
with all the emotions
that we deal with...
We have lows, we have highs...
But I feel growth.
I feel growth every day
from a young age or even
when we started day one,
and I hope that we can utilize
it to be a better human being
outside of this game.
Mm. - We have lows, we have Heidis.
I think all of us
have gone through some struggles
in our lives.
I moved to this country
from Puerto Rico,
barely speaking any English.
I mean, I had nothing.
I don't have family.
I didn't have friends.
So I had a lot of struggles.
Sometimes you get stripped
of everything,
and then you find
within yourself your strength.
Just likeSurvivor.
I have to work really hard
to finish my college degree,
and now,
I am an electrical engineer.
I have a good life.
I work,
I'm a mother, I'm married.
It's all a dream,
and it's coming true
because
I just go the extra mile.
And in this game, if I have
to go the extra mile, I will.
I'm willing to take some risks
in order
to be the Sole Survivor.
Oh, I know...
I know, like, I can't, like,
play the game, and then, like,
isolate from people,
- and, like, I just needed a minute.
- You played...
- Like, I need a minute.
- Carolyn,
you play the way
you want to play.
No, I know, but I'm saying,
like, I know in my head.
Can I see?
No. I can't do this.
Like, go away from people,
and, like...
I can't take it
sometimes, though.
There's a difference
between playing the game
and, like, taking things
personally. I know that.
It just takes me
a little bit to figure it out.
So even though
they betrayed me, like,
last vote, I'm over it.
I can go back, and I do trust
Carson and Yam Yam.
I need Tika to stay together.
Oh, and duh.
I have my idol
no one knows about.
So I feel good. I feel like
I am in a good position.
- I cannot wait...
- No, you're not in it.
- You're not in it.
- Oh, I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
So, we've been doing,
I think, good together.
We came in here
with three people at 12,
and we're now down to seven,
- and so we still have all three of us.
- I know.
Maybe last vote
was a little bit crazy, but I think
- we're in a great position.
- It's all good.
After talking with
Carolyn, she's back on track.
And Tika is still going strong.
Yeah, we get in silly fights,
but we are
controlling the votes,
kind of pulling the strings, and
we are playing
a very under-the-radar game.
And by the way, we need
to make sure Danny knows
that Heidi was the one
who wrote his name down.
I feel like he knows.
At the last Tribal Council,
Heidi voted for Danny.
When she looked around,
nobody was there with her.
Someone voted on me,
and everybody's saying,
"No, it wasn't me."
Someone here is lying to me.
I'm always
using everybody's sloppiness
to my advantage.
Telling Danny
that Heidi voted for him
makes the possibility of the two
of them working together
against me harder.
Jaime or...
- No.
- Heidi?
Really?
No... Oh, that's wild.
Yeah, I didn't even think it.
I start trying
to dissect the logic.
How can voting me
propel Heidi's game?
Because Heidi's
not gonna do anything illogical.
It doesn't make sense.
I'm Heidi's number one.
But you don't know
who's telling the truth
and who isn't at all.
We're gonna... we're gonna
get back on the same page
next Tribal?
It wasn't me.
Doesn't make sense, you know?
I don't... Yeah, I don't know.
- If-if it was you, I'm-I'm still...
- Yeah.
- Down to work, you know, together.
It's-it's a game. You know,
I don't look-look at it.
Oh, God. I said,
"No, that wasn't me."
I'm lying left and right,
just digging
out the hole that I dug myself.
Yeah, I-I feel confused.
So, I-I... I'm pretty sure...
Could it be her?
Maybe. I think it was Yam Yam.
Don't say anything, though.
No, let-let's not
make a big deal of it.
- So, I... I think Yam Yam had this planned.
- Yeah.
I know Heidi
very well. I believe her
and that-that
she didn't turn against me.
I think Yam Yam and Tika
are trying to split me
and Heidi up, but
it's silly. I would
find it difficult
to find first graders
who would buy that story.
So, now I have
my sights set on Tika.
Ooh. Ooh!
What is that?
Isn't that a lobster?
That's the body.
I'm not worthy.
I am, too. No.
Okay. Uh, rock, paper, scissor.
Okay.
Rock, paper, scissors.
- You win.
- No!
- No, I feel like I don't deserve it.
- Take it.
I was gonna put it, like,
somehow in my hair.
So I found this lobster thing.
I love it.
And then, Yam Yam
found this one for me
at the beach.
Over there.
It's cool. It's different.
I'll never come across
something like this again.
I know I won't.
So this is, like, special to me,
and I needed to just, like, get
in the water 'cause, like,
I want to be, like,
one with the lobster.
And I'm doing it.
This is beachy.
Like, it's beautiful here.
And it's just...
it's overwhelmingly amazing.
Like, it's...
there's nothing like this.
To see all these fish,
and, like, I got to be a mermaid
and, like, just be in the water
and have fun.
I can't do this game 24/7,
and that's how it is.
And I always feel better
with Yam Yam.
Us being like kids. Whoa!
I was singing
The Little Mermaid.
I was doing flips.
I was free.
Just made me happy
to not think about
all the chaos
that's going on here.
So...
So, who's your ideal, like,
three being at the end?
Can I be there three times?
I have multiple personalities.
I know you do.
Danny.
- And then I would say Lauren.
- Lauren.
- The thing with Danny is,
any say... any name we say, he's
gonna vote with us right now.
Yeah.
We're... we are
in a position to prove...
- We're pretty much equal right now.
- Yeah.
Where keeping Tika around
has to be...
Yeah. Yeah.
I do agree with Danny.
I think that
the former Tika tribe...
Yam Yam, Carolyn
and Carson... is a threat.
They have been
running the show here.
- You. Both of you.
- I agree.
I just had to work with them
to just survive
in this game, but now
they need to be split up.
The Tika Three...
They are not
breaking each other.
They are gonna
pick us off one by one.
- They want... Yes.
- Yeah.
It's an automatic, like,
- easy final three for them.
- So...
They are so...
they are super tight.
So I think it's either
Carson or Yam Yam.
Yeah.
I'm nervous working with Danny
and Heidi, but right now,
we are aligned, target-wise,
and that's Yam Yam.
This makes sense for everybody.
- Yes. Yup.
- For the four of us.
- For the final of us.
- So, um, yeah.
Yam Yam has
played a brilliant game.
He's fantastic
socially with everyone.
Everyone loves Yam Yam.
But those three have
to be broken up.
That's the number one goal.
- So, you..
- It's gonna hurt
to write his name,
let's be honest.
It...
Uh, he... yes.
For me, 'cause he's so likable.
But that... This is the game.
- This is the game. I'm playing the game.
- Yes, and...
Yeah.
That'sSurvivor 101.
It's not personal.
It's strictly business.
Gameplay is gameplay.
Friendship is friendship.
There is no winning this game
without being aggressive,
especially now, down to seven.
Like, you better start
taking everything by the reins.
It's a 12-round
fight. I would say
we're in the ninth round,
and it's a doozy.
There's a lot of right hand,
right or left hand,
swinging, ducks, stiffs.
Everybody's been
knocked down once.
Everybody's got votes on them,
everybody's been punched
in the face. It's up in the air.
This is a barn burner, but
I'm playing hard,
and I'm trying to win.
I didn't come here to take part.
I came here to take over.
Final seven, season 44.
If you want this, you got
to apply to be on Survivor.
Welcome.
Yam Yam,
you know this challenge?
Of course I know that challenge.
I don't think
it's gonna be a fun one.
It looks like torture chamber.
I remember.
Ozzy going
with the little snorkel thing.
I have fat hands. I don't know
how my snorkel is gonna work.
You know?
Maybe not a lot of air.
- We'll find out. Shall we get to it?
- Yeah.
First things first. Let me
take back the necklace, Carson.
Thank you.
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
Today's challenge
is a Survivorclassic
built to test
your ability to overcome fear.
Here's how it works.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna be in the water
underneath
a grated steel barrier.
As the tide rises,
your breathing room
will decrease.
That's when
the panic will set in.
Last person left standing
wins immunity,
guaranteed a spot
in the final six.
Losers, Tribal Council,
where somebody will be
the twelfth person voted out,
become the fifth member
of our jury.
- Shall we draw for spots?
- Yes.
Let's do it.
All right, everybody ready
to officially begin?
This challenge...
is on.
And now we settle in.
- Really?
- Yup.
You're all looking great.
There's no panic yet,
but that tide
is gonna slowly rise,
and that breathing room
will decrease.
And that's where
you have to manage that panic,
'cause the panic will come.
Got plenty
of breathing room now.
We could have a nice, long chat.
- This...
- Yam Yam,
how you doing down there?
I'm chilling. It's like
being back in Puerto Rico.
I'm trying to sunbathe,
get a little warm, not get
too cold, not get too anxious.
Getting used
to these little bars.
They're becoming my friends.
I'm trying to connect with them.
I hope it works
when that time comes.
Lauren, 21 days into this game.
Are you surprised
you're still here?
- Really?
- I'm, like...
Are you panicking now
or are you okay at this moment?
I'm okay at this moment, but...
You've been here 30 minutes.
Now you're gonna
start to feel it.
One of the worst parts
of this challenge is
how slowly the tide rises.
You can feel it working its way
up the side of your face.
But this is how
you get to day 21,
by this kind of performance.
And how you get to day 22
is by winning this challenge.
Lauren can't take any more.
Lauren is the first to drop out.
Nice effort. Lauren lasted
- an hour...
- Good job, Lauren.
...doing something
that you are
very uncomfortable doing.
We are down to six.
Everybody now with their face
through the grate.
Different strategies
for how you do it.
Some people using the snorkel.
Carolyn plugging the nose.
Yam Yam fighting to stay in it,
body kicking.
This is where
you really have to start
overcoming that fear
that's gonna kick in.
Jaime pops up.
Cannot take it anymore.
We are down to five.
That's that panic,
and it is not fun.
Tide continues to rise.
This is a great test
of controlling your thoughts,
the thoughts that make you feel
that sense of panic.
Carson is gonna duck out.
And we are down to four.
Nice job, Carson.
It is Heidi,
Danny, Carolyn and Yam Yam
still fighting
in this challenge.
A little bit of a swell
puts Danny fully under water
for a moment.
Heidi fully under.
Carolyn is under.
Everybody fighting right now.
Will she come back up?
No, Carolyn is out.
Great job, Carolyn.
- Yeah.
- We are down to three.
That tide is
really up there now.
Danny fully under now.
Fully under.
This is a test,
and it's a tough one.
Danny's body twisting
all over the place,
trying to find some relief,
some escape.
Danny fighting,
fighting, fighting.
Danny's up. Danny's out.
And we have Heidi on one end,
Yam Yam on the other
in a Survivorshowdown.
Here we go.
It will be Heidi or Yam Yam
wearing the necklace
for the first time this season.
This is a great effort.
Keep digging!
Keep digging! Don't you quit!
Been in there
an hour, 25 minutes.
This is absolutely
miserable right now.
Every time
you try to get a breath,
that water
tries to sneak in.
And all you want
to do is just quit.
- Heidi, is out. It's over. Yam Yam!
- Yam Yam!
It's over.
- Yam Yam cannot hear me.
- Yam Yam!
- Heidi, great effort.
- Yam Yam has won individual immunity.
- Yam Yam, you won!
- You won, Yam Yam! You won!
- Yam Yam.
Yam Yam wins
individual immunity.
- Congratulations.
- You did it!
What an effort.
What a showdown
between Heidi and Yam Yam.
Yam Yam, get over here.
- Right here.
- Yeah, yeah.
Oh, my God.
Good job, brother. Good job.
Oh.
Open up here.
You earned this.
There is no denying you overcame
a lot of panic and fear
out there, outlasted
all of these competitors.
What's the emotion?
All right, you're safe.
You are guaranteed a spot
in the final six.
For the rest of you,
after 21 tough days,
somebody will be
voted out tonight,
twelfth person, and become
the fifth member of our jury.
You have the afternoon to
figure out who it's gonna be.
All right, swim out.
See you tonight at Tribal.
Go for it.
You know whose name
is not gonna be written down?
"Yam Yam" is not gonna
be written down tonight.
Makes me feel like a Badass,
like I can do anything,
I'm powerful.
And for Tika,
tonight's vote is huge.
If we survive this vote,
we have the numbers
to take everybody out,
and it's us to the end.
I am excited for us...
You, me and Yam Yam...
Because I feel
like we're so close.
This is the most critical vote
because there's seven left.
Three are Tika,
the rest are other people.
We just have
to get it down to six
for Tika to have the majority.
He-he will. He will.
Okay.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Yam Yam winning
the immunity didn't go my way.
It's beautiful.
Good on him, but
let's get back to game planning.
We're putting the votes on
Carson. He's in the Tika Three.
He's got to go home.
I don't want to go
to the final two with Carson.
If I... if I cloned myself,
and I saw me up there
against Carson,
I might vote for Carson.
When they ask me,
I'm gonna tell them
that I'm voting one of you guys.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
We'll split... we'll do...
We'll do three-three on Jaime,
two on Lauren.
Everybody who's not in on
the plan, you have to have a lie
'cause tonight's the last night
to play Shot in the Dark.
If somebody plays
Shot in the Dark tonight,
a lot of people messed up
because this should be,
hopefully,
a complete blindside on Carson.
You and Heidi vote for Lauren.
We're all gonna do Jaime.
Is that cool?
Are you...?
Is that the for-real plan,
- or is this the fake one?
- That's-that's the real plan.
If you guys are cool with that.
I'm cool with that.
My strategy
is keep the numbers down
of the other people
that are not Tika.
People that I need out
are obviously
Lauren and Jaime because
I don't need them
with me at the end.
I don't think they're gonna see
this coming.
- Oh, no, no, no.
- But be ready when we come back.
Carolyn's gonna be crying.
Right now, we
are all voting for Carson.
If the plan works out,
Carolyn could be a...
a cannonball
when we come back.
Just open!
Usually, I go like this,
and then, it's...
Oh, there it is. Got it.
That's the worst
I've ever tried in my life.
I don't look forward to that,
but right now,
the biggest threat is Carson.
And I've been getting
my name written
in the last two Tribal Councils,
so I just got to make sure
that it's not me.
And I do have an idol
in my pocket that could save me.
So, you kind of have to be
ready for...
for any-any surprises.
I'm just worried.
I get the vibe
that they're voting for Carson.
Oh. I feel like
they're gonna vote... vote him.
Something's not right, and
there's nothing more annoying
when you're told by Danny,
"Yeah, that's a plan.
Let's just keep it simple.
Let's just not even have
any more discussions."
I'm worried now
that Danny is planning
to take Carson out
for this vote.
I need to investigate this.
I know that Carson has a...
He is a big threat
so I'm not opposed
to voting him.
Yeah. Nah, I, uh...
- I mean, would...
- I think down...
Right now,
I think it's bad timing.
You're lying to me.
Even with me, like,
interrogating
the strategy talk out of you.
I still need Carson around,
and so,
I want to vote out Danny.
I don't trust him at all. Also,
he does have a good chance
of winning immunities.
But, like, once again,
Danny, like... It's, like, he...
You-you just don't trust him?
Something's not right.
- With you.
- With me?
What-what do you mean?
I'm just getting vibes
that it might be you.
For this almost
entire game, this is
the first time I'm starting
to hear my name, and
it's stressful, and I'm,
like, feeling claustrophobic.
I've worked so hard
to be in this power position,
and now to know
that it might be all
crumbling down,
I could be screwed.
Yeah, I know
Danny's coming af... I think
he's coming after me.
Do you think
we should split it
between Danny and Heidi?
But, like,
I've been so, so fearful,
Danny, and, well,
I think he might
- have an idol or something.
- I know. - Yeah.
At this point, I'm depending
on Lauren and Jaime
to vote with me. Otherwise,
I'll probably be the one
going home tonight.
I don't. I promise. I, like...
Believe me, if I have one,
I would play it today.
But I'm pretty sure Jaime
and Lauren are really with us.
I feel like
it's pretty equal at this point
- between Danny and Carson.
- Yeah.
I mean, Danny is a threat,
but he's not good at puzzles,
he hasn't won immunity.
Carson's won immunity,
and he's great at puzzles.
But I think
Tika has the numbers.
That would be the benefit
in also getting Carson out.
They're just gonna pick us off
one by one.
- We just got to get through this one vote.
- Mm-hmm.
- Then we run... We can run it.
- Yeah.
Tika's been
controlling everything,
but now, Lauren and I have
all the power.
Do we want to go Danny
or do we want to go Carson?
It's a great place
to be inSurvivor land.
Yeah. Isn't it fun?
It's so cool.
I love it. Moves so fast.
I love this game so much.
No. I know, do... Jaime just...
Jaime just looked.
Because I don't feel good
about this plan.
Yup. So will you stay strong
and vote Danny with me?
- Yes.
- You-you promise?
We can't.
Will you just promise me?
Please vote Danny.
- I'm gonna vote Danny.
- Yeah.
But be chill.
We need to
make it past this next vote.
So it's crucial
that we keep Carson.
But I truly believe
people are just telling me
that they're gonna
vote for Danny,
but they're voting for Carson.
What? You
out of all of the Tika people
have an idol,
and you didn't tell us?
I'm in awe.
Like, there's so many
thoughts going through my head.
First thing is, like, I've just
got to make sure that Carolyn
actually plays it for me.
- Because I'm scared that if I play an idol for you...
- Right.
They're not.
They're not, you know...
- Or something, like, stupid happens.
- Right.
- Is what I'm afraid of.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm nervous. This is a lot.
What if something changes?
Then I'm gone.
That's, like,
the worst case scenario.
I, like, give him my idol
and then
I get voted out?
You know how bad
that would suck?
- Or something.
- So maybe it's best,
two votes against Heidi
so Heidi would go home.
What if Danny
has an idol? Then I would want
to vote Heidi 'cause, like,
I wouldn't have to use my idol.
So should I just vote for Heidi?
- Oh, God.
- Oh, my gosh.
Oh, my gosh. I hate this.
Again, there's so many plans
that I'm gonna be spinning
up until Tribal.
- Everything seems good, right?
- Yeah.
Like, I'm scared, I'm nervous.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
All right, so, Jaime,
Tribal Council
after Tribal Council,
you all have said
the same thing,
which is, "It's up in the air."
"We don't know.
Who I was with last week
"may not be who I'm with
this week. It may not even be
who I'm gonna be with
at the end of this Tribal."
- But the game continues. Now what?
- You know, I think
if you can find
a group of people where
your target aligns, that's what
it looks like for one day
and only one day.
That's the beauty of this game.
It's different
every single time.
Danny, given how many times.
Tribals have gone
left and right,
do you have moments where
you have to say to yourself,
"I'm tired, but I can't be.
I have to pay attention
even though I'm exhausted"?
Yeah, absolutely, because
everybody's name's
being mentioned
because everybody's a threat.
And you don't want
to look back and be
a coulda, woulda, shoulda dude.
You know, you're not gonna win
the million dollars
if you leave with "what ifs."
Heidi, Danny
just encapsulated what I think
is the truth about any player
who is in
the Survivorhall of fame.
They never said,
"Woulda, coulda, shoulda."
100%, and we are all
gonna take risks
sooner rather than later,
but when is the right timing
to take that risk
that it's not gonna backfire
and it's gonna
work for me?
That is extremely hard.
Yam Yam, given
that the jury is growing now,
how much time do you think about
the person we vote out
will be deciding our fate?
That's the only thing
I think about.
There's not a moment
that you're not, like,
cleaning a shell and
not thinking about that jury,
and like, counting the rocks
and thinking
like, "This rock is this person,
and this vote is..."
- Rock is this person, and this vote..."
- Wow.
It's so intense. It's, like,
draining, but it's so exciting.
Carolyn, why are you laughing?
Because it's non-stop
flowing. Like,
I'm up every hour.
- Really?
- Yes. I really don't sleep.
And I start thinking
about, like, the plan,
and then, the next plan
and the next plan.
So, by the time I get here,
I still am kind of spinning
and second-guessing
and paying attention
to what people are saying
during Tribal.
And then, in between,
we have these days where
we're meditating,
and we are just
telling each other how great
one another is, and then
it's, like, the next Tribal,
- completely different.
- Danny, you agree with that?
No, I don't agree with it.
I feel like as Tribals go on,
I kind of look at it
like fighters.
You look at a fighter,
and he's got his first fight.
You look at him like, "Oh,
that's a first-time fighter",
"right?" Yeah. He's nervous.
He's doing a lot of,
like, extra work.
And then, you look over
at a guy who's got ten fights.
You know, he's calm, relaxed,
he has a routine down.
So, I feel like
as Tribals go on,
we all kind of develop our own
routine, and we're kind of like,
"All right, man, I might
get knocked out tonight, but,
- "you know, that's the game."
- Yeah, I don't...
I don't see it like that.
I see it as,
we have, like, those rest days,
or then it turns into scramble.
And Lauren, that's
another complication is no one
here is gonna experience
- any moment of any day the same way.
- Right.
Right. We're all different
types of players, you know?
Like, some are just, like,
more experienced
than maybe even,
like, strategic players,
and others may rely a little bit
more on their emotions,
you know, and we all experience
things in different ways.
Case in point... Carolyn
exhaling while you're talking.
No, I just don't
understand the experience.
To me, it's like a comparison
between somebody
- who's a... I'm not...
- I think that was the wrong terminology
- for being experienced.
- I'm not pointing at you.
But neither is wrong or right,
you know?
I guess I just heard, experience
versus, like, emotions,
- and so, it just... I...
- It was wrong. I...
I think that was
the wrong comparison.
Comparison is the thief of joy.
That's what she just did,
so that's why I asked
a question, Danny.
So I'm not comparing.
I was just clarifying.
Oh. Okay, cool.
Are you annoyed?
Absolutely.
You get some sleep, Carolyn,
who knows how you'll see things?
Are you mad at menow?
Yes.
- Why?
- No.
I say the same things sometimes.
Why are you mad at me?
What did I do?
What did I
say? You're not sleeping.
I was merely commenting.
No, I'm good. I'm good.
I'm glad we cleared it up.
This is awkward,
but I'm good.
Carolyn, one of the many things
I like about you is you just say
what's on your mind.
- That's a problem, too.
- Well, okay, maybe at times,
it's a problem,
but it's a million-dollar game.
- Yeah.
- You should be speaking up.
This is somebody's
last Tribal Council.
We're moments away from voting.
Yam Yam, you're safe.
So, based on
what you saw at camp,
are you uneasy about which way
the vote's gonna go?
Definitely someone
that I don't want to leave
might be leaving today, And
that scares me 'cause tomorrow
I might not have
this necklace on.
Jaime, what do you
read into that?
You know, I feel really solid
with the vision I have,
the goal we set out there,
and the roles
that each person is
playing in tonight's vote.
Wow. Danny, "the roles
that each person is playing."
You could read a lot into that.
Do you feel the same certainty
that Jaime has?
I feel good about,
you know, my decision
and the people I'm working with.
Uh, our logic is aligned,
and if someone else
needs what I need, I trust them.
If they don't need what I need,
then I don't trust them.
Heidi, there's a
couple of people who say,
- "I feel pretty good."
- But the difference
between me and possibly
everyone else here...
I had votes last Tribal Council
and the previous one.
So, I'm not comfortable
because I keep seeing my name.
Carson, how about you?
How comfortable are you with
what you think has happened?
Um, to be honest,
I'm a little scared.
Um, I'm kind of, like,
on the edge of my seat.
You know,
I love this game so much,
so I am a little nervous.
The way you just said that was,
"I love this game.
I don't want to leave."
But if it is you, what
will your takeaway be, Carson?
I think coming
in at such a young age,
I wasn't sure how
I would be with all these people
that have so much more
experience than me.
Also, just battling my own
insecurities about myself.
I was the weird kid.
I was definitely
not cool in high school.
I just learned how
to do the bro handshake,
like, a month
before coming out here.
Like, I'm such a quirky person,
but I think Survivorhas taught
me how to accept my quirks
and be confident in them.
And that's something
I would never be able to buy
with just a million dollars.
So I'm beyond
grateful to be here.
How beautiful is that?
We are all in awe of Carson
and everything he's done
at that age and the way
he's performing here, and
everything about him is amazing.
Thank you.
Carolyn, how comfortable
are you with where you think
the vote is going and
what you're gonna do tonight?
Yeah, I'm scared. I'm not
comfortable. I'm-I'm nervous.
I'm putting my trust
in people that did not
vote with me last time.
It's just, I'm nervous.
All right, it is time to vote.
Danny, you're up.
I'll go tally the votes.
If anybody has
an advantage or an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
- Okay.
- Jeff?
I'm gonna play this for Carson.
Okay.
This is a hidden immunity idol.
Any votes cast for Carson
will not count.
I'll read the votes.
First vote, Carson.
Does not count.
Carson. Does not count.
Danny. One vote Danny.
Danny. Two votes Danny.
Heidi. Two votes Danny,
one vote Heidi.
Heidi. We're tied.
Two votes Heidi,
two votes Danny, one vote left.
Twelfth person and
the fifth member of our jury...
Danny.
Need to bring me your torch.
What?
Oh, man.
Jeff, I promised
everybody back home,
if you snuffed my torch,
I would De Niro face you.
Sure. This is your moment.
You snuff my torch, Jeff?
Snuff my torch.
Huh?
Snuff it. Yeah, snuff my torch.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Oh, my God.
Snuff, snuff it.
Go ahead, snuff.
Huh?
Snuff.
- Danny.
- Hmm?
The tribe has spoken.
- Love you, Danny.
Yeah. You guys are awesome.
Great move. Great move.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
Good night.
Amen.
Captioning sponsored by CBS.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Somehow we
are finally in the majority.
And so now we can run this game.
Next time onSurvivor...
We are outnumbered.
We have to break that up.
Carolyn
plays like she's clueless,
but she's fooling all of us.
I need to take Carolyn
out. It breaks my heart
a little bit.
Oh, I got voted out
by a great move.
That's how I wanted to do it.
It was certainly clever.
I played my heart out.
Uh, I left it all out there.
I have no regrets.
This is the adventure
of my life, for sure.
I'll tell you that much.
And, yeah, you know,
it's, uh, you know, Jeff...
Jeff had to snuff my torch.
He's gonna get De Niro face.
Jeff, this guy over there,
he likes to snuff torches.
Yeah, let him snuff my torch.
Yeah.