♪ ♪
Okay.
Tribal Council was chaotic.
Kane, the tribe has spoken.
FRANNIE: In this game,
it's been Ratu against Soka,
with Tika
floating in the middle.
And they didn't loop me in
on a plan to vote out Kane.
- How you doing, Frannie?
- I don't know. I'm just...
I'm just frustrated 'cause
I-I would have voted for Kane.
So I don't understand
why nobody wanted to tell me.
I realized
that every single person
on the beach lied to me.
So, as of right now,
it sort of seems like
I have no one on my side.
CAROLYN: So nobody
stuck with the plan, or what?
I didn't know the actual plan.
I'm very confused because
I was left out of the vote
and I feel like our Ratu numbers
are starting to dwindle.
It's only me and Jaime left,
and now my extra vote's gone,
but it seems like
it was just used for no reason.
So I could be next
or Jaime could be next.
Apparently, everybody
didn't know every plan.
CARSON: Everyone was saying
this was such a chaotic Tribal,
and, like,
no one really knew the plan.
I knew the plan. [Laughs]
I do want
to tell you something, Jaime,
but it's, like,
more of a private thing.
- JAIME: Yeah, we can talk.
- Okay.
I focused my game
upon relationships,
and so it's
really important for me
to focus on damage control.
I was wanting to work with Kane,
but I wasn't really sure
where his loyalty lies.
Okay.
- But, like...
- That makes me not trust him.
CARSON:
And I explained to Jaime,
Kane had been telling everybody
that she had an idol.
In reality, I had told
everybody that she had an idol,
but Kane's gone,
so I can say whatever I want.
I love being able
to make up lies about people
who aren't in this game
who can defend themselves.
It's wonderful.
I didn't know
how close you were.
- Especially if that was true.
- Yeah.
No, I'm really grateful
that you told me.
- I appreciate that.
- I won't tell anybody else.
JAMIE: Tonight at.
Tribal Council,
my number-one ally,
Kane, was voted out
with my idol.
It's the worst thing
that could happen inSurvivor.
It's like, "No! Come back!"
Like, we'll definitely
talk to tomorrow.
I just wanted to,
like, give you some
- peace of mind...
- Yes.
Right now,
it's kind of a tricky situation,
because I didn't tell
anybody that I gave Kane
the idol to protect it
from Knowledge Is Power,
but people are still suspicious
that I might have the idol.
So, to combat that,
I either need to come clean
or find a new idol.
♪ ♪
Come on in.
Good morning.
ALL: Good morning.
[exhales sharply]
All right, shall we get
to today's reward challenge?
ALL: Yes.
PROBST For today's challenge,
you're gonna
spin inside a metal frame,
slowly winding
the buoy across a line.
You'll then make your way
over a series of obstacles,
grabbing
two balls along the way.
You'll then race to land
those balls on a tall ledge.
First person
to finish wins reward.
- Want to know what you're playing for?
- Yes.
- The winner will be taken to the sanctuary.
- [Jaime gasps]
Where good things happen.
Yes.
PROBST: You'll enjoy tacos.
[all cheering]
- Tacos!
- PROBST: Apple empanadas.
Oh, my God.
PROBST: Cold beer, margaritas.
Oh!
Virgin margaritas
if anybody's under 21.
- [laughter]
- Worth playing for?
- Yes!
- PROBST: All right. I like it.
- Day 18, we'll draw for spots.
- [excited chatter]
We'll get started. Here we go.
All right. For reward.
Survivors ready?
Go! First
you got to spin yourself.
Pulling that buoy
across this line.
That's how you do it.
Frannie is whipping through it.
Heidi looking good.
Danny's got momentum.
Lauren trying to get some.
- [laughs]
- PROBST: The faster you go,
the faster
that buoy will get here,
and you can
take off to the next stage.
Jaime taking her time like she's
enjoying a Sunday at the park.
[laughs]
- Frannie, you're good. Danny, you're good.
- [Frannie whoops]
Holy mother of... [exhales]
PROBST:
Frannie and Danny both, dizzy.
You wouldn't know it
watching Danny.
[laughs]
[exclaiming]
PROBST: Now you got to get over
that beam while you're still dizzy.
You're good, Heidi.
Carolyn, you're good.
Oh, my God.
[screams]
- PROBST: You're good, Jaime.
- [screams]
You're good, Lauren.
Wow. Oh, my God.
[laughing]: Oh, my God.
[screams]
PROBST: You're good, Carson.
LAUREN: [laughing]: Oh, my God.
PROBST: Yam Yam.
Slow motion. You're good.
I can't even find it.
PROBST: Everybody dizzy.
You can get across the beam
any way you want, but you can't
touch. You got to go back.
Frannie has to go back.
She's got her first ball.
Danny has his first ball.
He's crawling across the beam.
That works.
♪ ♪
Frannie now
working on the second ball.
And she's good.
It's Frannie in the lead.
She's won
two individual immunities.
Danny has his second ball.
Can he navigate?
No. Big fall by Danny.
He's got to go back.
Heidi has her first ball.
[exclaims] - PROBST: Heidi
with her second, but she drops.
Got to go back.
Danny better this time.
You're good, Danny.
Start working on the knot.
It's now Frannie in the lead.
Start working it, Frannie.
There you go.
Trying to land
that ball on a narrow trough.
Carson's across.
You're good, Carson.
Here comes Jaime.
Carolyn's good. Heidi's good.
It's now Lauren and Yam Yam
still working the beam.
Everybody else has their balls.
Lauren's across. You're good.
It's Yam Yam,
last to get across the beam.
Frannie has her first ball.
Rain is coming down heavier now.
You're looking to land
both balls in that trough.
It is Frannie with one.
Nobody else with anything.
Danny trying to get his first.
No.
- Frannie does it.
- FRANNIE: Yes!
Frannie wins
her third individual challenge
- of Survivor44.
- [cheering]
And the biggest reward
of the season.
Wow, what a challenge.
That was a sprint.
Frannie, come on over.
Right here.
[whoops]
All right, so here's
what's gonna happen, Frannie.
You're gonna spend
the night at the sanctuary.
Oh.
PROBST: Blankets,
pillows, a roof over your head.
[all exclaiming]
In addition,
you will fall asleep,
drifting off
with memories of home,
- because you'll also be reading your letters from home.
- Oh...
PROBST: The reason you're out
here, the people who are back home
waiting for you to get back home
have written
you letters to encourage you.
So you've got food,
shelter and love.
Biggest reward of the season.
Choose one person to join
you tonight at the sanctuary.
FRANNIE: Jeff, um, as soon
as you say that family's involved,
this becomes
a whole different question.
So... [sighs]
Carolyn.
PROBST: Carolyn, come
on over. Why Carolyn?
I know she's missing
her son so much, and...
[sobbing]
PROBST: Frannie, choose
one more person to join you.
I'm gonna go with Lauren.
[crying] - 'Cause I know she
hasn't been eating as much,
and I know
she misses her son so much.
- Thank you so much.
- Yeah.
[sniffles]
FRANNIE: I'm so sorry.
PROBST: Now it's really tricky.
One spot left.
- FRANNIE: Oh, my God.
- Oh...
Oh, my gosh.
[breathing sharply]
Heidi.
PROBST: Heidi, come on over.
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, Danny.
- That's okay.
PROBST: Three moms.
[laughs]
[Heidi sniffles]
PROBST:
All right, Frannie, Carolyn,
Lauren, Heidi, head out.
Boat's gonna pick you up.
Take you to the sanctuary.
You'll return to camp tomorrow.
Enjoy.
Have fun.
- Bye, guys. Have fun.
- PROBST: All right.
Danny, Carson, Jaime, Yam Yam,
got nothing for you.
Head back to camp.
FRANNIE: For me, winning
this challenge is bittersweet.
This is probably
the biggest reward
of this season of Survivor,
and I get to be there
with these
other three amazing women,
but I see their faces
when I win for a third time.
It's simpleSurvivor strategy.
Take out the person who could,
in theory, win every challenge.
If you want this, you got
to apply to be on Survivor.
♪ ♪
JAIME: Okay, so how many
scoops am I doing?
Like 4,000.
CARSON: Four thou... [laughs]
I'm excited. Thank, y'all.
JAIME: Thank you, guys.
I'm happy you're excited.
I'm... mad. I wanted food.
I'm the only person
that hasn't gotten a reward now.
I would have loved tacos,
but this is a lot more
than just food.
Like, was there anyone
specifically you were looking
to get letters from?
- What?
- [sniffles]
YAM YAM: The fact
that I know that my letter
is in Jeff's hand, and I'm not
gonna be able to read it...
It's heartbreaking.
I was looking forward
to reading a letter from Karim,
my husband.
He always writes
really nice stuff.
My mother...
She's, like, super energetic
and she always
gives me strength.
It would have been nice
to read some letters
and have some peace of mind
that they're okay.
You know?
DANNY: You're missing
your husband bad, huh?
Hey, man, this is gonna
make it that much more sweeter.
- DANNY: No, you're not stupid, man, you're...
- No.
DANNY: You're feeling it,
and you're talking to us
'cause we're close.
- It's real.
- Yeah.
The only good thing
about being here is that
I get to sit down
with Jaime and Danny,
which I really haven't talked
serious strategy,
and lay out a plan
that may benefit us.
How do you be a good player
and not look at Frannie
as somebody
that needs to be taken out?
- She's three and 0. Um...
- CARSON: Yeah.
She's three and 0,
no one's beating Frannie, and
she knows puzzles,
she's a beast at comps.
- I agree. I agree. I agree.
- She can balance.
She has strength.
CARSON: As of this morning,
Frannie wasn't even
on the radar,
but she's won three
out of the five
individual challenges.
That's saying something, and so,
being able
to use that against her
can be
a really effective strategy
to kind of bond us together
because we didn't get
to eat the delicious food.
We didn't get
to read our family letters
from home, and so, now,
tides have shifted. It could
be Frannie going home next.
- [shrieking, giggling]
- HEIDI: What?
[screaming, gasping, muttering]
FRANNIE: I walk into
the sanctuary, and I see
everything you possibly need
to have a good time.
Tacos and margaritas, you know?
What more could you want?
- Do it.
- [screaming]
Yeah.
- Yeah.
Salud!
- That tastes...
- [giggling]
- HEIDI: What?
- LAUREN: Like what? - So good.
- CAROLYN: Ooh!
- [laughter]
- Best reward ever.
- CAROLYN: Yes.
This, like,
couldn't be a better four.
I'm so glad
that you did think about it,
like, too, as, like, moms,
- and, like, you know what I mean?
- Thank you so much.
Like, that's so human and so...
Ugh. Like, I just...
I appreciate it.
Frannie, like, thank you.
FRANNIE: As soon as I
knew I was gonna have
to choose people,
I couldn't help but think
about the moms out here
on this island,
and Carolyn is somebody who
I want to build
a relationship with.
I don't always feel
like I fit in.
And she is
so unabashedly herself that
it's inspiring to me.
CAROLYN: I'm so nervous.
HEIDI:
I am, too. I'm not gonna lie.
- Oh. All right.
- [crying, sniffling]
[sniffling]
You know, my daddy is not,
like, an emotional person.
And, like...
[crying]
Both of my boys...
They were just letting me know,
like, they're doing so well.
But for my dad... that was
probably the most memorable.
Him saying like,
"When others doubted you,
you always persevered."
And it's so true, like...
Being married and then
going through a divorce...
Like, I'm single,
on my own, like,
and many people in my family
have been, like, on welfare.
And, like, my dad was like,
"You're gonna...
"you're gonna have to
figure something out because...
because you're gonna
be that way."
And I was like, "No, I'm not."
I went, and I got two jobs.
I went back to school,
and I got my master's.
And then,
even withSurvivor, like,
I'm telling my family, I'm like,
"I'm gonna apply for that
show and I'm gonna go."
And they're like,
"No, you're not."
Then, I'm freaking here. Like,
I have surpassed, like,
everybody's expectations,
and I'm a living example
for other women to know,
like, doesn't matter
your circumstance.
You can do it.
It's crazy to think
a letter can mean so much.
CAROLYN: Yeah.
And my son hates writing.
Like, he doesn't like
writing at all.
So it's, like, this is probably
the most he's ever...
[laughter] - I've never seen
him draw anything like that.
I don't even know what that is.
[snorts]
CAROLYN: I feel like I had a
good relationship with Frannie,
but going on this reward
with her, like,
took it to a whole new level.
And I know that
Frannie's a threat, and, like...
But I'm like, "I don't want
to ever vote her out now."
To see you, Frannie, winning...
I'm literally living
through you, and I think
we should keep up the whole,
like, women winning.
HEIDI: I agree.
- After all, we got this.
- LAUREN: Yeah. - FRANNIE: Yes.
- Yes. - LAUREN: Yeah.
- CAROLYN: Okay.
We're not just talking,
we're real?
- I'm manifesting it.
- CAROLYN: What do you mean?
Tomorrow, we're gonna win it.
Oh, I thought you were saying,
"Vote Danny out."
[laughter]
- I'm down for it.
- CAROLYN: When are you ready
- to let go of Danny?
- FRANNIE: Yeah, yeah.
- Let's-let's ask that question.
- That's the true question.
I have no ties to Danny.
We never said "Oh, final two."
'Cause we both know we're gonna
kick each other out
whenever it's time to.
- It's time tomorrow.
- Well, is it time to?
It-it could be.
CARSON: I'm not...
Heidi will vote out Frannie
next-next Tribal 100%.
That's the only thing...
Like, the letters.
JAIME: With Carolyn, I know
that that's gonna be tough.
So you guys have
to come up with the story
that you're gonna tell her.
Like, what name is
she gonna write down?
DANNY: Well, if you want
a really believable plan?
- What's that?
- We could just say we're trying to flush your idol.
And that'll be really...
that'll be really cool.
- Do you want me to tell you what happened to my idol?
- Yes.
JAIME: It's time to come clean.
The only reason that my name
was ever brought up
or ever written down
is because they thought
that I had the idol.
- Okay, so...
- Do you have an idol?
I hadan idol.
We thought that somebody had.
Knowledge Is Power,
so Lauren gave me
her extra vote to protect it.
I gave my idol to Kane.
Kane was voted out.
The idol's gone.
Wow.
It's a good story.
That's just what it is.
It's a story.
Actually, um, I take that back.
It's a horrible story.
It's absolute B.S.
Isn't it such
an unbelievable story, though?
They're gonna be like,
"Yeah, right.
You gave your idol to Kane?"
- Like, I legit don't have the idol.
- Yeah.
JAIME: After coming clean,
I really believe
the target is off my back.
I do believe that Danny,
Yam Yam and Carson believed me.
Yeah, that story's total B.S.
CARSON: And now
we're doing an idol search
- because there's one out there.
- DANNY: No, no, yeah.
You know, good on her
for at least trying that.
CARSON: It was so good.
It's honestly put her more
on my radar
- because it's like, "Wow, she's good."
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Hmm?
DANNY: My game plan
moving forward now is simple.
If Frannie loses
an immunity challenge,
we vote her out.
If she wins, we vote Jaime out
or flush the idol.
I can get Heidi on board.
Does your gut say
it's too early for...
- For Danny?
- Mm-hmm.
No. Uh, he wouldn't expect it.
It has to be a blindside.
Danny and I are close allies,
but I want to make sure
they know that I'm here
to play the game.
It's not just I'm saving Danny.
I'm actually playing this game
for myself and for my family,
not for Danny.
Va Va.
Good morning.
Welcome home.
I was up at the crack of dawn
just waiting
for the women
to come home because
I was so excited
to finally share
the truth about my idol.
I did have the idol.
Because we were fearful
of Pow... Knowledge Is Power,
I gave my idol
to Kane to hold,
and then Kane was voted off,
- and he walked away with it.
- Are you serious?
JAIME: It feels good.
I'm finally free!
The truth shall set you free.
Oh, my God, Jaime,
why didn't you, like, stop it?
Oh, but it's so public. I would
have been like, "Stop!"
I would... I know.
JAIME: Lying and keeping secrets
is the name of the game,
but it's a lot of weight
on your chest, so,
I love being honest. [Laughs]
Don't tell anyone
when I said that.
- I appreciate you saying that.
- Yeah, totally.
I mean, I had heard
that you had one.
I smell bull. Oh, no.
Oh, man. How great is it?
FRANNIE: Are you kidding me?
Really? You know, Jaime,
do you think we're that silly?
It's too much.
What, does she think
we're all idiots?
FRANNIE:
And the fact that she can lie
right to your face
only exacerbates for me
the idea that Jaime's
a dangerous player in this game.
♪ ♪
Come on in.
If you only knew
how good you looked.
- [laughter]
- Warriors!
[whooping, laughter]
Weathered, dirty,
- hair's grown out.
- Thank you, Jeff.
Yeah, it's beautiful.
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- [all voicing assent]
- First things first, Frannie.
Got to take it back again.
Thank you.
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
your feet will be tied together.
- Oh.
- Your arms will be tied to your side.
- Oh, my God. - Ooh.
- Yeah.
PROBST: On my go, you're
gonna slither through the sand
while using your mouth
to drag a buoy
through the course.
- YAM YAM: No.
- [laughter]
YAM YAM: Oh, God.
When you get to the end, you're
gonna maneuver the buoy
through a final obstacle
and then race to finish
a star-shaped puzzle.
First person to finish
this challenge
wins this necklace.
- You can't be voted out tonight.
- Oh.
Losers, Tribal Council
where somebody will be
the eleventh person voted out
and become the fourth member
of our jury.
- Big enough stakes?
- [all voice assent]
All right, we're gonna draw
for spots. We'll get started.
- Here it is.
- Here we go.
All right,
for immunity. Survivors ready?
- Go! You're slithering...
- Ooh.
...through the sand.
Your feet are tied together.
- Your hands are tied together.
- [grunting]
Danny doing a nice job,
out to the early lead.
You got to really attack this.
- [grunting]
- What Danny's doing.
Keep that mouth
holding on to your buoy.
Oh, my God.
PROBST: You're good.
Danny is flying
through this course.
[grunting, screaming]
Danny is whipping
through this course.
It is crazy. You're good, Danny.
Untie your hands and your feet.
It is everybody
- trying to catch Danny right now.
- [grunting, screaming]
Now you're gonna maneuver
that buoy through the obstacle.
Here comes Carson. Lauren doing
a good job. Here comes Heidi.
Here comes Frannie. It's Jaime
and Yam Yam in dead last.
You're maneuvering that buoy now
through an obstacle.
It's about rope management.
[screams]
Here comes Carson.
Carson's made up a lot of time.
Here comes Heidi.
Frannie's in it now.
Here comes Lauren.
Yam Yam heads over
that first hill.
There goes Jaime
over the first hill.
- Carolyn still struggling. She's sideways.
- [grunts]
Carson, you're good. Untie.
You're good, Heidi. Untie.
You're good, Frannie. Untie.
You're good, Lauren. Untie.
Now you're maneuvering that buoy
through one more obstacle.
This is all about managing
that rope and the slack.
You got to create slack.
And it's Danny in the lead.
Let's go, Carolyn!
You're almost there.
Get your face on the mat.
You're good, Carolyn.
You're good.
Danny has his buoy through.
You're good, Jaime.
Danny first up to the puzzle.
Everybody is working on
their buoy except for Yam Yam.
You're almost there, Yam Yam.
You are good, Yam Yam. Untie.
Yam Yam is now in it.
Heidi's through.
She can untie her puzzle pieces.
PROBST: Trying to work that buoy
through those ropes.
Carson is through.
He can untie his puzzle pieces.
The faster
you get through that obstacle,
the faster
you get to your puzzle.
Carson's up here.
Frannie's through.
She can untie her puzzle pieces.
Frannie's won two individual
immunity challenges already,
- plus a reward.
- Oh, my God.
She's up now working
on the puzzle.
There goes Lauren.
She's through.
Yam Yam is through.
Yam Yam made up a lot of time.
Yam Yam is now in it.
Look at that.
Lauren's up here.
Jaime's through.
- Oh, my God!
- PROBST: It is now
just Carolyn
working on the buoy.
- [shrieks]
- Everybody on the puzzle now,
except Carolyn.
Danny was first here,
but has made absolutely
zero progress on the puzzle.
Carson's getting progress going.
It is a complicated
star-shaped puzzle.
It's a complicated knot.
PROBST: It is Carson
in the lead right now.
Now Frannie's got some momentum.
It's now Frannie and Carson
side by side.
It is Carson now pulling away.
Frannie trying to catch Carson.
Carson down to four pieces left.
Oh, my... Who did this?
Come on, man.
Carson down to two pieces left.
Frannie trying to catch him.
It's gonna be too little,
too late.
Carson down to his last piece.
For immunity, does it fit?
He's got one piece left.
He can't get it to fit.
Frannie fighting.
Stay in this, now.
Carson now gonna
take a piece out.
Something is not right.
He's readjusting his puzzle.
Frannie moving faster now
with another piece.
Carson lost some momentum.
He seemed to be one piece away,
but it wasn't right.
He can't get it to fit.
That has opened the door
for Frannie,
who is trying to close the deal.
- Jeff?
- Carson rearranges again.
Thinks he has it.
And he does. Carson wins
- individual immunity.
- Oh, God.
- Safe tonight at Tribal Council.
- Wow.
PROBST:
Wow, that went together fast.
Carson, come on down.
- [whooping]
- Yeah!
- Yeah, Carson!
- Good job, Carson!
Before I put this on,
how's this feel?
It's incredible.
I never thought I would win
an individual immunity.
And so, being able
to put that puzzle together
against, like, some powerhouses
in this group... this is awesome.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you so much.
- Yeah!
- [whooping]
Carson is safe tonight,
- cannot be voted out.
- Oh.
PROBST: As for the
rest of you, after 19 days,
somebody will be
voted out tonight.
Eleventh person out of this
game, fourth member of our jury.
Grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
- See tonight a Tribal. Congrats.
- Thank you.
- YAM YAM: Congrats, Carson.
DANNY: Not winning's never fun.
But I'm happy
it wasn't Frannie. So,
tonight's Tribal,
if it goes exactly how I want,
Frannie goes home.
She's a powerhouse in this game
and nobody wants to go
to the final three with her.
We have an opportunity right now
to strike. Let's strike.
DANNY: Way to go, Carson.
- That puzzle was awesome.
- Right. All right.
FRANNIE:
Of course I wanted Jeff to put
the immunity necklace around me
for the third time,
but there's kind of a sense
of renegade excitement in me
that I don't have
that security tonight.
- What do you think? Would you rather Jaime or Yam?
- Um...
I am...
I will be absolutely fine.
FRANNIE:
I have had some sort of security
every single Tribal Council
I've gone to.
So, I kind of haven't had
a chance yet in this game
to put my social strategy
to the test.
And I love tests, you know?
I...
Yeah.
I-I just keep thinking Danny,
but again...
- HEIDI: I'm okay with that.
- Yeah, I'm good with Danny.
Me, neither.
- HEIDI: Yeah.
- I'd rather just...
Like,
we all know she has an idol.
Carson,
you're the necklace holder.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
My idea would be to split it
between the two of them...
Three-three... and on a revote,
if Jaime doesn't play her idol,
vote her.
Okay.
So what are you thinking?
DANNY: Nobody's beating Frannie.
Who wants to sit with her
at the final three?
I mean... [laughs]
- Are you down for that?
- I'm down.
Danny brings up Frannie's name,
which is mind-blowing to me,
because Danny hasn't been one
to talk strategy with me.
And then, also,
I just went on a reward with her
at the sanctuary.
What about you?
Yeah.
We wanted to vote out Danny
at the sanctuary,
but I do think
it could be a good idea
to vote Frannie out of the game,
being that she has won
so many immunities.
- Everybody's on board with that?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
- All right.
YAM YAM: The fact
that Frannie lost the challenge
is huge for the tribe,
'cause now we can target her.
But I think Jaime's the biggest
threat out here right now.
She might have an idol.
There's only eight of us,
and right now,
Tika is making
all the decisions.
So I have to talk to Carson
to see what he wants to do.
Danny wants to get Frannie out.
Yeah, so then, we can take...
But I also want
to get Jaime out.
I know.
I want to get Jaime out, too.
We just got to choose
which one we want to do.
And it's complicated 'cause
I don't really know what's best.
I want you, me and Carolyn
to be the closest to each other.
What I see brewing
is Carolyn forming
- a closer bond with Frannie.
- YAM YAM: Yeah.
[Carolyn groans]
CARSON: I think Carolyn
might have found a number one.
- That's...
- If you're feeling like we're gonna lose Carolyn
because Frannie's here, I think
getting rid
of Frannie's the best option.
But Carolyn gets really annoyed
when she's not included
in stuff.
True. It's scary.
YAM YAM: Carson and I...
we might vote out Frannie,
but the worst thing
that could happen would be
that Carolyn finds out
about it because
she might not be
our ally anymore.
Who's everybody?
HEIDI: Danny wants to target
Frannie, and Frannie is trying
to split
between Jaime and Danny.
Those are the three names I've
heard from different plans.
I don't know
what's gonna happen.
I don't feel good with any
of them, in all honesty.
But if I feel weird,
I do have an idol.
I am bringing it tonight.
Depending how I feel
at the moment,
I may or may not play it.
Are we comfortable?
Like, is someone going rogue?
- I don't think so.
- Danny's... voting for,
- um, Frannie.
- What?
He told me,
"I don't need your number
if you don't feel comfortable."
What. Wait. What?
So, who does he think
is voting with him?
Well, I think... I thought
he saw... He thought you guys.
- Not me.
CAROLYN: The plan was,
split it between Jaime and Danny.
That was the plan, I thought.
And then, I start hearing
this stuff about Frannie.
So he's saying because he
doesn't need you for the vote?
- It doesn't matter.
- Well, what is he doing then?
Danny tells Heidi, "Oh,
I don't need you for a vote.
I already have the numbers."
He would never
say that to Heidi.
Something doesn't make sense.
Not knowing
who exactly is voting
for you if that's the vote
they've planned?
CAROLYN: Something's not right.
People are scared.
"Frannie wins all
the immunities." Who ca...
Like, I'm not
voting Frannie this vote,
and they know that, probably,
and are leaving me out.
I'm pissed.
I think it's stupid.
Well, I know we always haven't
all been on the same page,
but, like, seriously,
are we gonna let Danny
control another vote?
Yes. Yeah.
[laughs]
- Us four and one more.
- CAROLYN: But, um, split?
- Maybe Carson.
- FRANNIE: Do you want...
- Let's... do it.
- Let's do it.
Oh, let's... do it.
Every single time everybody
thinks they have a plan,
she goes around
and she freaks out.
And yet, she's the one who...
She's...
- Then ask him.
- FRANNIE: Yeah. Perfect.
- That was good.
- Hmm. Yeah.
[Carolyn whoops]
This is what we're doing now.
Okay, I-I don't know
if I'm in yet, but tell me.
Me, Frannie, you,
Lauren, Jaime for Heidi.
[laughs]
I don't like... I don't like
the last-minute thing.
Sometimes the
last-minute stuff is the best.
CARSON:
We have this plan for Frannie,
but all of a sudden,
Carolyn and Frannie are trying
to now move the numbers
to Heidi.
And so,
I'm just trying to figure out
what the best course of action
is from now.
- I need to have a conversation.
- Mm-hmm. I don't...
with Yam Yam and Lauren
and-and Jaime.
The best move for me,
I feel like,
would be to take out Frannie,
but doing so
would really risk
my relationship with Carolyn.
But I do want Heidi out.
I can see right through her.
She is working this game
pretty well,
and she is a big threat.
CARSON: But I'm really not
sure what is going to happen.
And it's stressful,
it's chaotic.
I just wanted it to be simple,
but that never happens
with this group.
In this game, I feel like
I've really tapped into
both of my chaotic
and clever side,
but right now I'm, like,
in full chaotic mode,
and I know there's going to be
a betrayal either way.
I just have to decide
who I am betraying.
♪ ♪
All right, let's start
with the reward challenge.
Frannie, you win your third
individual challenge,
and with it,
the power to choose three people
to go with you
on the biggest reward
of the season.
Sanctuary, food,
letters from home. Let's debate.
Is there a case to be made
that it's better to be chosen
- for that reward than to win?
- FRANNIE: Oh, yeah.
You know, I wanted to win
the challenge. I wanted tacos,
and I wanted to be
in the sanctuary.
But, you know, you never want
to be the one who has to decide
who gets their letters
from home.
PROBST:
And Danny, make the other case...
Why you want to win a challenge
that shows
you're a competitor
and you're in charge.
DANNY: Jeff, there's a bunch
of Survivorlegends out there,
and they're legends
not because they lose a lot,
it's 'cause they win a lot.
Frannie put on
three performances
where she kicked ass, and the
game ain't over yet, so, yeah,
you want to play
to win the season, but also,
you don't want to just be good.
You want to be great.
You want to be one
of those players... the Robs,
the Parvs, the Jeremys.
These are legends. Like,
- why not strive for that?
- PROBST: I agree with you.
That's the only way
to play Survivor
is full tilt boogie every single
second of every single day.
- Wow. Full tilt boogie.
- [laughter]
I don't know
what full tilt boogie is.
Probably like this.
I don't know.
Full tilt boogie's
a state of mind.
- Oh, yeah.
- PROBST: It's like
you could call it "Club Condo."
You can call it
whatever you want.
It's just a state of mind.
So did I full tilt boogie
at the sanctuary?
You could full tilt boogie
at the sanctuary.
I don't know if you did or not.
- Oh, I did.
- PROBST: Okay.
[laughter]
PROBST: So, Yam Yam,
what does it say about this game
when the better you do,
the bigger the target becomes?
YAM YAM: This is a game of
doing great things and knowing
how to smoke-and-mirror it,
you know?
This is a very difficult game
to play, you know?
You want to be great,
but being great maybe is not
the best thing always.
- I'm not winning.
- [laughter]
I don't have to worry
about that, you know?
- But...
- PROBST: Jaime, Yam Yam said it really well.
That's why the great players
are great, is somehow,
they were great,
and they still got to the end,
and they still won
in many cases.
JAIME: It is a balancing act.
Another example is when somebody
finds an idol, like myself.
You automatically have
a giant target on your back.
And I just want to make it
extremely clear
to everyone, Jeff.
My idol walked out the door
at the last Tribal Council
with Kane.
So, I'm saying this again
so that there are no secrets.
I don't have the idol
any longer, sadly,
and now, I'm hoping
that everyone believes me.
PROBST:
Carolyn, here's another example.
Finding an idol, earning an
advantage really, really good.
- Yeah.
- PROBST: And then, suddenly, you're Jaime
going, "I'm so sorry. I promise
I don't have it anymore."
"You can check my bag.
I swear I didn't mean to...
I'm so...
Please don't vote me out."
- [laughter]
- Exactly.
CAROLYN:
It is such a balancing act.
I've been battling this
the whole time I've been here.
I don't want to be too loud,
but I don't...
I want to be relevant.
But you can't say anything,
but you got to trust people.
It's stressful. PROBST: Jaime,
you have eight people here,
eight different plans
to get to the end.
And Frannie winning
some challenges
is one layer
to a reason you might think
of voting somebody out.
There are all kinds
of things going on in this tribe
- that factor into the vote.
- JAIME: Yes.
That's what I love
about this new era of Survivor
is it is new. Every single day,
it's a brand-new game.
So, the people that
you worked with last Tribal,
you might not talk to them
at all this Tribal.
It's always gonna be different
because everyone's motives
are different,
and depending
on what happens that day,
it might change
who you work with altogether.
So, the era of alliances...
is over.
PROBST: Danny,
what scares you most
about the game right now?
DANNY: Uh, to be
honest, Jeff, we genuinely,
like, all really get along.
So now, like, it's no secret,
like, me and Lauren have been
on the opposite sides of voting.
But, like, on, like,
a personal level,
I love the hell out
of this-this woman.
But it's also scary
because everybody else
has those relationships.
- LAUREN: Yeah.
- DANNY: And it could be,
"Oh, now that friendship
has evolved into an alliance."
PROBST: Frannie, you
were nodding in agreement.
Oh, yeah. I thought
one of the great certainties
in this game is that
Danny and Lauren didn't have
a strategic relationship.
- Yeah.
- You know? You can't sleep
on any permutation in this game.
- Wow.
- Right?
Anybody can talk to anyone
and be working
with anyone at any time.
- It's crazy.
- [laughter]
You know?
You see everybody here laughing,
- but everybody's, like, nervous.
- CAROLYN: Yeah.
This was my most stressful day,
and I had immunity.
I hear one plan,
and then someone else might
leave. Then the plan changes.
Then someone else leaves,
plan changes again.
We add a person, plan changes.
So I would not be surprised
if we had about 20 different
plans going on today.
It is pure pandemonium,
like, legitimately.
Heidi, can a plan get detoured
with one comment?
Yes, especially when you have
so many uncertainties out there.
If you hear something that is,
like, high alert, like, "Okay,
I'm not going with that plan.
I'm going with this other plan."
100%. There's so many plans.
None of us are solid.
So I truly think,
you say the wrong thing,
and you could go home.
PROBST:
I feel like I have to ask
before we go to the vote,
are we good to vote?
Okay, in that case,
it is time to vote.
Danny, you're up.
[sighs]
♪ ♪
I'll go tally the votes.
If anybody has an advantage
or an idol,
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
All right, I'll read the votes.
First vote:
Frannie.
Danny.
Heidi.
Heidi. That's two votes Heidi,
one vote Frannie,
one vote Danny.
Frannie.
We're tied. Two votes Heidi,
two votes Frannie,
one vote Danny.
Frannie.
That's three votes Frannie,
two votes Heidi, one vote Danny.
Eleventh person voted out
and the fourth member
of our jury: Frannie.
That's four. That's enough.
Need to bring me your torch.
Carolyn, I'm wearing your belt.
CAROLYN: Aw.
♪ ♪
Frannie, the tribe has spoken.
Time for you to go.
- Love you, Frannie.
- Love you.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
Good night.
♪ ♪
Captioning sponsored by CBS.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
YAM YAM: Leaving Carolyn
out of this vote...
It backfired.
PROBST: Next time onSurvivor...
CARSON: I've worked so
hard, but it's all crumbling down.
JAIME: Now, Lauren
and I have all the power.
I didn't come here to take part.
I came here to take over.
I put my game to the test
tonight, and I failed.
And I don't fail tests,
but I feel like a stronger,
more powerful woman.
I beasted challenges. What?
[laughs]
And honestly,
being a jury member is,
like, the most exciting thing.
It's a front row seat
for my favorite show.
What more could I ask for?
[roars]