We still have
a fire going, guys.
We still have a fire.
And we had
a successful blindside today.
I shook his hand, and he gave me
his word, and he played me.
And am I right, Drea?
He was thinking
he's untouchable.
He's, like, giving me marching orders... Yeah.
Wait. Can you hear it?
Can you hear that?
You know what that is?
That's Hai's head
rolling down the road
because we lopped his head off,
just like he deserved.
Because Hai was playing
too many different games
and got too full of himself.
Final seven.
Congratulations, everybody. Yeah.
Hai thought he was the king, but
his peasants banded together
and set into motion the biggest
blindside of the season.
And quite frankly,
I've orchestrated
right from the beginning.
I hate to say it,
but that was the Tribal
that I enjoyed the most.
Yeah, I enjoyed it a lot.
He kept saying my name,
so I wanted that
for a long time.
I'm playing this game
super chill
and under the radar because
the inevitable is happening.
Everyone's looking
to take out these big threats.
And it's perfect for me.
I can just sit back
and let these big egos
eat each other up, and then
the underdogs
can take over this game.
I guess tomorrow we'll figure
out how much we really have.
Yeah.
So, now
that Hai is gone, the amulet
is now a Steal the Vote,
which myself and Drea are able
to use if we work together.
So we now have
some extra ammo for us
to use
to dwindle down the threats
that might get in the way
of our game to the final.
The game's getting spicy now.
I went...
I was in St. Martin.
Mm-hmm.
And I went to take pictures
of a friend.
- Uh-huh.
- She's like, "Come take pictures of me in my swimsuit."
And she had very, like, thong
swimsuits and stuff like that.
And it's like a wedding, and
I was just like, "You go, girl."
Like, she was really taking the pictures. Like...
I saw it hang...
- Actually, I saw it hanging.
- Yeah. Oh, my gosh.
- Which one happ...? Which one? The pinkie?
- It's fine.
I actually lose my pinkie toes
- pretty often.
- That's odd to say.
- What? They're so small.
- Oh, yeah.
No, no, no,
it's not normal
to lose your toenails like that.
I'm so confused.
No, no.
They fall off, like, maybe,
like, two or three times a year.
Mine's never fallen off.
- No, but they...
- Like, that's regularly?
Like, that you have
an annual amount?
Like...
Two or three times a year.
Hey, there's normal,
and then there's Maryanne.
Like, I don't...
Yeah.
Yeah, right.
I've never been more miserable
or more hungry or more painful,
but I'm having so much fun
out here, man.
I don't want it to end.
How has someone
not addressed this
to her before? Like...
No.
Clearly, right now,
I'm not as big of a threat
as people think that I am,
which is a blessing
'cause that means I'm probably
safe for the next Tribal,
but a curse, because if people
don't think you're a threat,
how are you going
to win at the end?
But I've been really
taking a step back
because if you're someone
who's a big threat,
you're the next one out.
I think
they're going after each other.
Who would have thought
that the people
on the bottom are now
in the power position?
It's Survivor flip.
The bottom's at the top,
- and the top's at the bottom.
- Yup.
I'm telling you right now,
- this ain't brain surgery.
- No.
- It's really not.
If there's five,
and we're the best five,
let us fight it out.
I mean, who wouldn't...? Okay.
It surprises me that the two
of them are still here.
Yup.
Yeah.
Romeo-- it just bothers me
that he's just not working.
It's literally...
And he doesn't care.
- No.
- He just sits there while we're all working.
Don't know if I've ever
seen him do anything.
This is the movement I see.
Into the pot, into his mouth.
That's the only movement I see.
He keeps going, dipping in,
and then he eats the bottom.
You know, at the end
when you can lick the spoon,
from when you're...
they're making a cake?
He licked the spoon.
Yeah.
You know what his best move is?
This.
That's his exercise.
That's what he does.
Romeo, Romeo,
wherefore art thou, Romeo?
He's sitting in the same spot
that he sat in 20 days ago.
Hasn't moved.
That's where Romeo art thou.
Screw them.
I'm not doing anything for
anybody but myself out here, so,
hell yes, I'm gonna eat
that rice. I'm hungry.
And it's not personal. I'm sure
I would love him
in a regular life,
but not here.
It's been aggravating me.
- Yeah.
- So what do you guys want to do?
Take this to the final five?
- I'm in.
- And duke it from there?
Yes.
I'm in 100%.
- You're in?
- Yeah.
I'm a competitor.
I'd rather play against people
who have been
playing hard the whole time.
Like, we came
to play for a million bucks,
and I want to go with the people
who are playing
for a million bucks.
I know.
He just eats. He never cooks.
Romeo literally sits
in the same spot
throughout the entire day
but then will eat
the scraps of rice.
I feel so bad because
he's been with me since day one,
but I cannot.
It's like, "Aah!"
It bothers me so much.
Bah! Aah!
We're gonna do the final five,
and then we duke it out
from there right here.
I give you my...
Listen, I give you my word.
- Same. Yeah. Same.
- I give youse my word.
I'm down.
Let's do this.
- ...bounds, uh, out there.
- Uh, I mean, no, right?
But what are you thinking?
To go with that?
I was saying,
"Top five, us five,
the people
that deserve to be here." But
it's mainly a game,
so Drea sees it
and she believes it,
and she votes for Romeo.
Ah.
To make Drea feel comfortable
that we're
all together in this,
and I think she bought it.
I hope she bought it.
Listen, Drea gets to the final
three, she's gonna win, and...
I got to look
at the big picture here.
And the big picture is,
Drea's the biggest threat left
that I'm not working with.
- Drea is extremely good.
- She is good.
I'm actually really thirsty.
Are you guys gonna be done
with the water yet?
Drea.
- Yeah, we're coming.
- What are they saying?
They want us to be back
with the water.
I actually need my water!
At this point in the game,
people want
to push their agenda.
And after this big blindside
on Hai,
Mike's getting a little like,
"Hmm. I just pulled off
my first big move,
"and now I'm the big man
who can rule and
tell people what to do."
But, like, people will go
after people like that.
He's feeling high after Hai,
if you know what I mean.
So I don't trust anything
Mike says anymore.
I think that he's playing harder
than he's letting on,
and you can tell he's become
what he was accusing Hai
of doing.
He's become the new Hai,
and that's not going to work
for him out here.
I can tell you that right now.
I just can't believe
there was no food.
- Like, this really is way different.
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
Like,
we're all feeling it today.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yes. Oh, my God.
- Like, it hit all of us, you know?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Minnows? Yeah.
Coming into this,
one of the things that I did
was go, "I'm gonna eat the
same amount as everybody else,
not put a target on my back,"
and it's worked.
I'm here. I'm at the top seven.
But I burn 2,000 calories
a day not doing anything.
I'm getting to the point
where moving is-is rough.
Jonathan, we're at the beach.
People here are literally
half my size,
and they're eating the same
amount as I am, so I have it
a little worse than everybody
here, and that's the truth.
How long have I been
laying here?
Over an hour.
- Is there anybody around?
- No, they're all at the beach.
Everybody?
I'll walk down there
with you in a second.
All right.
I wanted to be
the provider,
and I've done that.
I'm still the one
that starts the fires.
that catches the fish.
Six more days, and I can
hopefully win this game
and move on.
But nobody sees how hard it is
for me, which is my game plan.
I don't want 'em to see.
So, how does this exactly work?
What do you do with it?
Meaning what?
Okay.
The little string
from the big string?
Little strings
from the big string, yes.
Huh? Uh, there's two people
working on it,
so I'd kind of get in the way. I...
Everybody, take it easy on me.
I'm doing everything
I can do. Okay, Drea?
Jonathan is acting hangry
and kind of rude.
Kind of pisses me off.
I was just beyond
shocked at how he was
approaching the situation.
- You're the fisherman.
- Yeah.
This is why I was like,
"Can you help?"
Are you kidding me?
If it wasn't for us
coming to get it,
he would have still
just been laying around.
I really wanted to work
with strong players,
but Jonathan's lost
a tremendous amount of weight.
He's weak.
And I have no empathy for him
cause I'm on the same page.
I'm allergic to coconut,
so I can't eat coconut, so,
I'm literally starving.
It comes off rude because...
I'm the one doing it all.
I could use a thank-you.
The provider is supposed
to get props.
I want to be
a little more appreciated
because if it's not seen,
then it's not working.
But...
But the way you talk
to people is not...
- Yeah.
- That's not okay with me.
Yeah, I hear you.
I have held my tongue
so much.
But just because
of that bickering, I know
that that's gonna...
that's gonna put a seed
in their mind
to try to vote me off now.
He's in his mood...
Jonathan's starting to unravel.
And people are picking up
on that.
It's perfect timing because
I want Jonathan out because
of how he acts towards me.
He's not a great ally.
He just dictates
on what I should do,
and if I disagree,
he gets annoyed with me.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Jonathan's the one person
getting in the way
of me winning more challenges.
But I know
what I'm capable of doing.
So it's balls to the wall
going all out
to make sure
Jonathan loses and goes home.
All right,
seven players left in the game,
and today is the dangerous
Do or Die twist.
It's a risky game of chance,
but it could be an opportunity
for somebody on the bottom.
If they win,
they're safe,
can't be voted out.
If they lose, they're out,
but there is no vote involved,
and nothing can save them.
It is them against the game.
Last season when we did this,
Deshawn was in trouble.
He played Do or Die and won.
They couldn't vote him out.
He made it to the final three.
There's no easy choice.
If you need immunity,
you have to compete.
But if you compete,
and you're first out,
you got to play Do or Die.
What would you do?
And remember,
they've not seen season 41.
They're going to be shocked.
Come on in.
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- First things first, Lindsay.
Got to take it back.
- Thank you.
- Yup.
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're going to balance
on a narrow perch
while holding a handle
behind your head.
At any point,
a foot comes off,
or a hand lets go, you're out.
Last person left standing
wins immunity,
guaranteed a spot
in the final six.
There is a twist
to today's challenge.
And it's a dangerous one,
but if you think you're
on the bottom, it could help.
Here's how it works.
The first person
to fall out of this challenge
will have to play a potentially
deadly game of chance
called Survivor Do or Die.
- What?
Tonight at Tribal Council,
the first person to fall out
of this challenge
will play this game of chance.
If you win, you're safe
and cannot be voted out.
Then we have a regular Tribal,
and somebody else is voted out.
If you lose, you're out,
and that's it.
Oh!
Nothing can protect you,
no idols, no advantage,
no Shot in the Dark, nothing.
It is you against the game.
So, your decision right now is,
do I compete or not?
Whoa.
If you think you need immunity,
you got to compete.
A lot of this comes down
to where you believe
you sit in the game.
How much knowledge do you have
about your relationships?
Because several people here
don't need immunity tonight.
Most of you are not going home.
One is.
If you think you're the one,
Do or Die is an option.
Remember, Do or Die
doesn't mean you're out.
It could mean
you're totally safe.
Omar, what are the variables
in this that you have
to think about right now?
Yeah, I mean,
this changes everything.
You have seven people here
who have been making plans
for the last few days,
but none of it may matter.
All right,
shall we make our decision
about who's gonna compete
and who isn't?
Yeah.
All right.
You'll each take one rock.
Purple means "I'm gonna play."
Gray means, "I'm gonna sit out."
It's a complicated decision.
Do or Die.
This is a game about risk, but
it's an incredible opportunity.
- Take a look at which color's in which hand.
- Yeah.
Hell, it could mean
that you're safe
without anybody even voting
for you.
Once again,
purple means "I'm playing.
I got to go for it."
Gray is, "I'm not competing.
"I'm gonna give up my shot
at immunity, and I'm just gonna
"take my chances that I've
got a strong enough alliance
that I'm not in trouble
tonight."
All right, everybody reveal.
Oh, my gosh.
Wow.
Jonathan is playing,
- and Lindsay is playing.
- Yeah.
And that is it.
Ooh!
Wow!
Had a feeling
that was going to happen.
Jonathan, it's kind of crazy.
- I mean, it's literally a showdown.
- I know.
I mean, honestly, I thought
it was gonna come down
to me and Lindsay,
so here we are.
I know. Lindsay,
you know right now
that you or Jonathan are going
to have your fate determined
by a game of chance.
Yeah, it's just the odds
are way worse now.
Like, I was hoping there'd
at least be three or four,
and there'd be a better chance
of me being to outplay that.
But Jonathan and I have been
neck-to-neck
almost every single challenge, so
this is going to be
a battle royale right now.
All right, Omar,
Mike, Drea, Romeo, Maryanne,
you are not competing.
No shot at immunity,
which means you're vulnerable
at Tribal Council.
Take a spot over here.
We will leave
Jonathan and Lindsay
to get ready
for the competition.
Jonathan, Lindsay
side by side in a showdown.
Put your feet into position.
Your heels have
to be against the beam,
your butt and your back have
and your hands are holding
the handle behind your head.
All right, we are good.
And this challenge is on.
- Let's go, guys.
- Good job.
You can't ask
for more than this.
Two warriors...
...battling it out on day 21.
One player will be
in control of their fate.
One player will not.
Once again, Survivor testing you
in ways you could never predict
in a much more dangerous version
of Survivor
where the monster is
always starving.
Nowhere to hide.
You are five minutes
into this challenge.
Good job, guys.
Really impressive.
This challenge is no joke.
This is where you find out
how much is in that tank.
Jonathan
with a lot of movement.
Trying to find some way
to relieve the pain,
some way to block it.
Trying to breathe through it.
Two different body positions,
but both
are still doing
what you need to do.
Keep digging, just keep pushing.
You cannot lose focus.
Keep hanging in there.
Whatever it was
that made you sign up
to come play Survivor,
this is what you wanted.
This kind of a test.
- 12 minutes in.
- Ooh, good job, guys.
Stakes are huge
with Do or Die on the line.
Don't give in.
This is it. Dig it in.
Dig it in right here. Dig it in!
Come on, Lindsay.
Keep fighting.
Lindsay drops first!
Oh!
- Wow.
- Jonathan wins individual immunity
in a torturous challenge.
Wow!
Great job.
Good job.
Jonathan, come on over.
Good job, Jonathan.
Where are you feeling it
right now?
My whole body. I feel like
my forearms are about
to fall off.
Well, you'll have time
to recover tonight
because you are safe
at Tribal Council,
guaranteed a spot
in the final six.
Well earned, risky move.
You are safe tonight.
Head back over.
Good job, Jonathan.
Nice job, Jonathan.
Jonathan, you are safe tonight.
You don't have anything
to worry about.
Lindsay, not the same for you.
So tonight at Tribal,
your fate will be determined
by the game Do or Die.
If you win, the good news is,
you're safe
and cannot be voted out.
But if you lose, you're done.
If you're safe, there is a vote,
and somebody else is voted out.
Day 21 of Survivor 42.
Stakes have never been higher.
All right, everybody, grab
your stuff, head back to camp.
See you tonight
at Tribal Council.
Lindsay is tough as nails.
She's the number one competitor
that I have to go against
for this necklace.
To be honest with you,
it wouldn't hurt me
if she left tonight.
I mean, I hate to say it.
She's a great...
I don't hate to say it.
That's the game.
If it's time for her to go,
then I'm okay with her leaving.
I had my husband's voice
in my head like,
"You suck at endurance."
Especially, like, my feet.
I was like,
"Mm, that's not gonna happen."
Yeah, Lindsay took
a chance, and I'm proud of her.
That was a million-dollar gamble
that I made today.
Now, tonight comes into
a game of chance, and...
I'm very disappointed in myself, because...
that was such a dumb decision.
I felt safe.
I didn't need to do that, but
I wanted to just beat Jonathan.
So, me being a competitor
my whole life
totally came into play.
I've always played sports.
At nine, I was like,
"Football looks really fun."
And I signed up.
I was the only girl
in the entire league
of the town.
And I busted my ass
and I earned my spot
and I played every single game
for six years.
And that's where my personality
and just who I am
just slipped in.
It just sucks how Linds...
- She should have just not played.
- I know.
And now I literally might be out
from that one mistake.
But...
I'm proud of myself
that I gave it my all.
that I fought,
and I'm not out of the game yet.
I let my head...
Which is what I should've done.
No, don't say that.
No, don't live with regrets.
You don't know what it is yet,
you know?
- You don't...
- You're acting like you're already home.
- Like...
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
We'll see what happens.
It was bittersweet 'cause
I was rooting for my girl,
but at the same time,
I am hoping
Lindsay goes home tonight.
Obviously I'm not
gonna tell her that,
but, like, if she goes home,
there's only one amulet
left in the game.
And that means
that my amulet becomes an idol.
So then that would mean
I have an idol in my bag,
plus the Knowledge
Is Power advantage.
I also have my extra vote.
So tonight is
a major night for me.
But if Lindsay does
her Do or Die
and she's still in the game,
we will have to send
someone else home.
And I feel like
Romeo's name is out there
because Romeo doesn't really
do that much around camp.
- It's Romeo.
- Yeah.
Please.
- I'm sticking to the plan.
- I'm gonna...
'Cause I think I'm playing
my idol tonight,
- 'cause I'm nervous.
- No. I'm sticking to the plan.
Yesterday,
I set up a little plan
that the decoy vote tonight
is Romeo.
Thankfully,
Drea bought my story.
Because if Lindsay doesn't go
out tonight, I want Drea out.
...we have a straight line
to the final four.
Right, and she's a huge threat.
- We'd be crazy.
- Right.
Drea's a threat.
She's super likable.
I think she's
a great badass woman.
And I would have
the only amulet left.
I would have an idol
in my pocket
if she left.
I got-- You got my word.
- I got you...
- All right, love you, baby.
I'll see you later.
Drea better hope that I go home,
'cause if not,
it's gonna be her.
If I make it to the final three,
I don't want to be
sitting by Drea.
Drea has more on her résumé
than me.
She'd be hard to beat.
If she makes it to the final
three, she's gonna win.
Yeah.
- Hey, I'm just being real with you.
- Yeah.
Drea's been playing
such a good game.
She's always been
in the majority.
If anybody lets her get
to the end, she will win.
Point blank. Period.
That's my word.
- Drea.
- Got you. Okay, cool.
All right, thank you.
Boom, boom, boom, like dominoes
right in a row.
Everybody's on board.
There's five days left.
I could do it going backwards
with my eyes closed.
And quite frankly,
I have an idol in my pocket.
If I feel even the "bittest"
that I'm being played,
I will not hesitate
to play it in a second.
- So, it's Drea tonight.
- Oh.
- We're just making sure that everything is-is all good.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But she also
can't be aware of it,
- because she has the extra vote.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Knocking Drea out here
removes an extra vote
and removes a player
who's gonna be
a really strong contender
at the end of the game.
Oh, yeah, you should.
But the smarter side of me says,
"Mike is a threat to win,
and I want to blindside him
and make a big move."
But at this point,
I feel like it's too risky,
'cause Mike has
that hidden immunity idol.
And so,
that makes the decision easy.
If Lindsay is safe,
and Drea is going home,
it seems set in stone.
Wait, you were praying?
Okay. Geez.
I could feel
my stomach turning.
I've been staring at people
and observe, like,
how they're moving,
how they're acting,
who they're talking to.
It's weird.
It's a very weird vibe.
Mike is saying that it's Romeo,
but now my gut tells me
that Mike is lying to me.
So... is the plan
- -
- Romeo?  Mm-hmm.
-
Yes.
And then
we have to try to get Mike
to play his immunity idol,
basically.
I'm gonna take
his immunity idol.
- You can take it?
- Yes.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
You can take it from him?
- You're the only person I've told, Omar.
- Okay.
- You're literally the only person I've told.
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's before the votes.
I have to say, "Hey, Jeff."
- It's public?
- Yeah.
Mike does not know
that I have
the Knowledge Is Power
and have the ability
to take his idol tonight.
I decided to tell Omar,
because I believe
Omar is someone that I can work
with towards the finish line.
Mike told me
that he might play it today.
- His immunity idol?
- Yeah.
So...
we may have to vote Mike today.
We have to.
So, it'll be
- me, you...
- Me, you, Lindsay.
Lindsay, Romeo, extra vote.
- Romeo, extra vote.
So that's five votes on Mike.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right.
This changes everything.
I mean, at this point,
Mike thinks he's totally safe.
It's the perfect time
to take him out,
'cause he won't see it coming.
And with Drea stealing his idol,
he has no backup protection.
He told me that it's you.
'Cause he will
never see that coming.
- It would be epic.
- I agree.
This is big,
because Drea told me her power.
So, like, we can't let it spill.
So, she will steal Mike's
hidden immunity idol tonight,
and she wants to blindside Mike.
Whoa.
So Mike's hidden immunity idol
will be Drea's tonight.
Wow.
Oh, my God. This is crazy.
Yeah, for sure.
- I know. This shocked me.
- So...
- I know...
- It changes everything.
Because we can blindside Mike
and get him out,
or--
telling him what the power is--
Mike gives us the idol.
And this way, we still have
control of where the idol is.
By removing the idol from Mike's
pocket and putting it in mine,
Drea's advantage
is basically neutered
and so is Mike's
'cause he doesn't have his idol.
And then it's, like,
free for the taking.
You can take either one out.
- My gut says to take out Mike.
- My gut says...
I know, but my gut says
I don't trust Drea as much.
And there's so many ways
that I could go.
We let Drea steal Mike's idol,
he's blindsided,
and Mike goes home.
- It's gonna be cool. Okay.
- I know.
Or tell Mike
about the advantage
and then blindside Drea
to keep him happy.
He's an ally.
He's a vote.
The other option is,
if I keep his idol in my pocket
and vote out Mike,
then I don't have
to give it back to him.
Officially,
possession of the idol is mine.
I can't wait. Dude.
And yet
none of this may matter.
Lindsay may go home
in the Do or Die,
and then
we're back to square one.
All right,
so let's start with
today's immunity challenge
and the twist.
If I need immunity,
I got to compete.
But if I compete
and I'm first out,
I got to play Do or Die.
And everybody sat out
except Jonathan and Lindsay.
Jonathan,
what was the thought process
of why you were
going to compete?
I know that I need it, Mr. Jeff.
I mean,
we're this close to the end,
so there was
no real choice for me.
I had to commit and do it. Lindsay,
you were the only other person
that stood up
and said "I'm competing."
Honestly, my competitive nature
overtook my gut,
and I made a poor choice.
And I was blinded
without double-checking
does this make sense
in the game to do?
Mike, what was it like
to watch these two?
Because it was
a pretty intense battle.
Their bodies gave out.
It was unbelievable.
I got to be honest with you.
I have total respect
for both of them.
And I know Lindsay said
she did a stupid thing.
I don't think
she did a stupid thing at all.
I think she did a warrior thing.
Whatever happens tonight,
Lindsay's gonna be fine.
She's a remarkable young woman.
She's gonna be successful
through life.
And what she did today
just showed the kind of person
that she really is,
and that's who I can respect.
And then also,
Lindsay and Jonathan have
always been head-to-head
every single competition.
So Lindsay going
and stepping up,
I don't think was
a bad decision
based on the track record.
And, like, I hope that,
however this turns out, that you
don't lose that competitiveness,
because that's a good trait
to have.
- And I want you to know that, okay?
- Thank you.
I appreciate that. Thank you.
Omar, was it hard
for you to sit out
from a competition
point of view?
I was sitting on the bench
watching them, very impressed,
but also happy with the decision
that I made, because I grew up,
my parents were like, "You get
an education, and that's it.
You don't, you don't go to gym class. I don't care."
So, you know,
that's not my strength
to go up against these two.
All right,
so you get back to camp.
Maryanne, what's the vibe?
Because you can't
"kind of" approach it
like there might be a vote,
'cause there might be a vote,
depending on what happens
with Do or Die.
The scrambling always starts,
you know?
And there's some people
who are going in,
they're pulling
many people aside.
There's some people
who are just like...
And then it's the head nod plan
or the scramble plan
that goes tonight if...
And if it even happens.
So, Mike, does that mean
that there are literally
different ways
of communicating
for different plans
within different alliances?
Absolutely.
It's either... or it's...
But if you see this one,
get to the water well.
You see this one, just relax.
So you kind of know
the winks and the nods.
Drea, when you see
the sign Mike talked about,
which is, you know, 911,
how do you react in the moment?
I see who he's looking at,
and I observe.
Just like I see
when Jonathan gets up
and tries to talk to numerous
people throughout the day.
And I observe.
And I see when numerous people
go to the water well,
and they come back and
their canteens are still empty.
I observe.
When they go for wood,
but there's no wood in their hands.
I observe.
Omar, it was almost getting
like a horror movie,
the way she's, "I've been watching you."
Yeah. Yeah.
It's a creepy vibe.
Like, all of a sudden,
you introduce this twist,
and now we can't just
assume Lindsay's going home.
Somebody else may be going home.
Today was the most paranoid
I've ever seen people,
and it's weird, 'cause
we might not even have a vote.
Jonathan, what kind of energy
did you feel, knowing
that you were safe tonight?
When people talk to you,
it's a whole different level,
because they look at you
and go, "Well, Jonathan's safe.
So I can tell him more
or I can do more."
They work with you more.
Drea, that's really interesting,
because if somebody
were to tell Jonathan
more than they might normally--
because tonight he's safe--
and there is no vote,
then Jonathan just got
all this free information.
Him having
whatever information he has
doesn't change my gameplay.
I didn't come into Survivor
to just depend on other people
to help me get through.
Alliances are there,
but alliances also
flip on people, as we see.
So I play like it's my last day.
Listen, everything you say
in this game to somebody
means something about
or to somebody.
So you have to be careful
how you choose your words.
Even in just regular talk,
because people
misinterpret sometimes
what you say to mean
something different.
And you say, like,
"I didn't mean that at all."
Omar, that's also
very interesting,
in that Mike is saying sometimes
you could say something wrong,
even unintentionally.
Yeah, I mean, that's also
why you have to be careful
with the winks and the nods,
'cause people
might get the wrong idea.
And sometimes,
you need to know when to stop.
Because, like Mike said,
"You keep going, you're gonna
run out into the train tracks
and get run over."
All right,
before we go to the vote,
we have to determine if
there is going to be a vote.
Let me set up the game, Lindsay.
Good luck.
- Good luck, Linds.
- Good luck, Lindsay.
Thank you.
- Oh, my God.
- Gosh.
All right, Lindsay, come on up.
Good luck, Linds.
All right, Lindsay,
we have three Do or Die boxes.
In one of these boxes
is a flame.
Flame represents life.
If you choose the flame,
you live, you survive.
- You make the final six.
- Oh, my gosh.
You can't be voted out.
Two of these boxes have a skull.
Skull represents death.
Death.
You draw the skull,
there is no vote, you're out,
you join the jury.
It's a big, big decision.
Take a moment.
I have my idea on one box,
- but then I have a backup of another box.
- Mm.
- Oh... you guys.
- That's a, that's a problem.
- I'm-
- I'm stalling, as you can see.
Okay. Middle box.
Before we open your box,
I'm gonna open
one of these two boxes.
- Okay?
- Okay.
The skull.
Oh, my God.
There is now one skull
and one flame.
The last twist is,
you can swap them if you want.
Oh, gosh.
Your gut told you
to do something,
but you also
said you had a backup plan.
That was my backup plan.
Oh, God.
So I'm gonna go with my gut.
You're gonna stay
with what you chose?
- Yeah.
- Come on, Linds.
If it is a flame,
you're guaranteed
a spot in the final six.
If it's a skull,
you're out of the game
and will go to the jury.
Let's reveal your box.
Oh, my God!
Yeah!
- Oh, my gosh.
- Yes!
Wow.
Oh, my gosh. Yes, Lindsay.
- You drew the flame. You are safe.
- Oh, my God.
Here is the other skull.
Oh, my gosh. Wow.
Oh, my God.
- You deserve that.
- Wow.
- You're back.
- Good job. Man.
That's crazy.
Damn, Jeff.
Man.
What's the feeling right now?
So much relief.
I... I-I don't know. I'm, like,
speechless at this moment.
I can't even...
God, I love Survivor. This is awesome.
Great job, Linds.
- Good job.
- Holy crap.
- Great job. U-Unbelievable.
- Yeah.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Wow.
All right,
despite the celebration,
this means
we are going to vote.
One second. Yes.
So...
...I've heard that my name
has been out there a few times.
And luckily, my work from
earlier in the season helped me
find this amazing advantage.
The Knowledge Is Power advantage.
"This advantage
offers you power in the game.
"Here's how it works.
"You are allowed
to ask one player
"either of
the following two questions:
"Do you have an advantage?
Or do you have an idol?
"If the answer is yes, they
must give you the advantage
"or idol, and it becomes yours.
"If the answer is no,
"you receive nothing
"and this advantage
becomes powerless.
"To be clear, you can only
ask one player one question
one time. That is it."
And I can verify they can't
lie, 'cause I know who has what.
Perfect.
Okay.
Mike, do you have an idol?
No.
Oh...
That wasn't good.
Oh, my gosh!
About a half an hour
before Tribal,
Omar made me aware
that Drea
had this little trinket
that she's gonna use against me.
Okay.
But if I don't have my idol
on me,
Drea can't take it.
I'm giving you my idol.
Giving away an immunity idol.
Could I be taken
to the cleaners by these guys?
Will they give it back?
They don't have to give it back.
They could say,
"Nah, Mike, it's mine,"
and knock me out tonight.
- And with that, it is time to vote.
- Time to vote.
Romeo, you're up.
Nice try, Drea.
If anybody has
an advantage or an idol,
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
All right, I'll read the votes.
First vote. Drea.
Mike. One vote Drea,
one vote Mike.
Drea. Two votes Drea.
Mike. We're tied again.
Two votes Drea,
two votes Mike.
Drea.
Three votes Drea.
Mike. We're tied again.
Three votes Drea,
three votes Mike.
Drea.
That's four votes Drea,
three votes Mike.
One vote left.
12th person voted out
of Survivor 42.
I gave it all.
I love you, baby. Give me a hug.
- Good job, Drea.
- Hey, great job.
Great job.
I went out fighting.
I'm proud of you.
I love you.
You threw two...
I love you, too.
I threw two on you.
Yeah.
I'm still coming out.
I love you.
Bye.
Oh, my God. Oh.
Lindsay, I'm rooting for you. You know why.
Thank you.
Jonathan, believe it or not,
you were never on my radar,
but you were always after me.
Mike, if you make it to the end,
you'll probably win.
Thank you.
Kiss of death.
Romeo, you've been
on the block every time.
Omar, you're the only person
I told the secret to,
and I want everyone else
to know that.
Maryanne, keep being you, babe.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Love you, Drea.
Bye, Drea. Hey.
Bye, Drea.
You gave me two. I like it.
I know! I really did!
- I was, "Where the hell'd that other come from?"
- I pulled it out of my pants
and everything. Damn.
I'll see you later.
I love your gameplay.
I fought to the end...
Good job.
- Hell yeah, you did. Bye, guys.
- Bye.
Never seen a moment like this.
Drea.
No...
Go for it.
- The tribe has spoken.
- No!
You can snuff it.
But I got to say it.
Do you want to say it?
The tribe has spoken.
- Bye, Drea. Love you, baby.
- Bye, Drea.
Bye, Drea.
I love you.
See you on the other side.
Love you.
- That was a great departure.
- Yeah.
I got to say, just as a viewer,
I can't think of a season
where I've ever seen
this much fierce gameplay
and camaraderie.
This is the ideal way,
in my mind,
for Survivor to be played
because it is just a game
and it is just an adventure,
and it's an experience
with people
that you're going
to know forever.
- Yup.
- I thought it was awesome.
- Thank you.
- You've made it
to the final six.
Grab your torches.
- Head back to camp.
- Have a great night, Jeff.
- Thank you. Have a good one.
- Good night.
Oh, man. Lindsay,
- I am so happy for you.
- Thanks.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Taku Four has made it
to the final six.
But now it's time
to break up.
Omar is not her pawn,
and he's working against her.
I want Jonathan gone.
He's my main nemesis.
Nothing from this conversation
can leak.
- I swear.
- Nothing.
I'm a real contender,
not just a goat to be herded.
Man, I played the hardest game
I think
I could have played out here,
and I wanted
to go out with a bang.
I wanted to go out
playing everything
that I had, and I did it all.
I did my advantage, and I did my
extra vote out my pants, so...
Zero regrets.
I just hope
they all actually give a fight.
So, bring it. That's all.