Subtitulado y sincronizado: TwiNe
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Tribal was a blindside
for Rocksroy.
Me and Drea pulled in
Tori to vote for Swati,
and we decided
not to tell Rocksroy.
He's not really a social player,
and once he says something,
he's going to stick to it,
so we knew that he was going
to vote for Tori regardless.
Let's start from the beginning.
Swati looked me in
my eyes, and she said:
- "You're my number one."
- Right.
Come to find out,
she told everybody in
camp that same story.
- Yep.
- To me, she was a bigger...
...threat than anybody here,
and she needed to go.
And I knew that you weren't
going to vote against her.
I feel a little betrayed.
I got duped.
You know what?
I'm actually happy that
you did it the way you did it.
If she's playing both
sides of the coin,
that's someone
we cannot take with us
further in this game,
and I'm happy
that you guys
weeded it out.
- Yeah.
- Good on y'all.
I did not see this coming.
Obviously, I'm not picking up
on social cues.
I guess my social game is
really not that good.
No, it's good.
- But I'm learning.
- You made allies.
If I got to ride you
guys' social coattails,
- I will.
- No.
We just need to be a
strong four here.
"Four strong" literally
makes me laugh.
I sit there, and I just literally
say: "No, no, no, no, no."
- We need to find that, like, unity.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We can't have that weird
vibe anymore, we got to...
I'm gonna be the first
person to jump ship.
I have no desire to do that.
Because of Rocks.
That's why.
All he's focused on is
the shelter and the fire, like,
he's just not playing
the same game
that we are, and
it's really frustrating.
Sorry for writing your name down, Tori.
- No, it's... I mean, it's a game.
- I hope that doesn't come back...
...and bite me in
the friggin' buttocks.
I just want him gone, but
I'm still gonna suck up to him
and be like:
"Absolutely four strong. "
"That sounds like a great idea."
But that's not what
I'm actually going to do.
I'm baller at Mario Kart.
Oh, you have not met me, buddy.
I've been playing Mario Kart
before you were born.
I know this 'cause I'm
baller at Mario Kart.
Yeah, but I hit that acceleration
on "three, two, one, go,"
I always win then.
- Oh, okay.
- I got a trick.
You see, I'm arrogant,
and I know that I'm the best,
so I play as my Mii.
- Oh, you're Mii?
- Ah! Yeah!
How much these girls
talk drives me crazy.
And then I lost it on an
airplane to San Diego
on Friday the 13th, and
I cried so bad, my mom...
I don't know why they always
feel like there can't be silence,
but there isn't five seconds
without one of 'em...
Huge, huge, giant monkey animal.
I was in a musical, right?
Like a school musical.
So I whip out my phone
and call in sick at
work and walk out!
Oh, my God.
That is the Taku
news at 7:00 a.m.
Thank you, guys,
and make sure you tune in.
There you go.
- That's how you end it.
- But, um...
Oh, Jonathan's the
first to explore.
Rain showers in Fiji...
- ....happening from 6:30 to 7:30.
- It's a sun-shower.
Is my canteen in there?
Play hot and cold.
- Warm.
- Warmer.
Warmer.
Hot.
Warm.
That's not how you play.
- Now he's warmer.
- Hot, hot, hot.
- Oh, my God.
- Burning, wait.
It's a very simple concept.
Oh, you go:
"Colder"?
Right, but then he was veering
in the opposite direction,
- ...so then you say: "Colder."
- Then you say: "Colder."
No, because you're
not hot anymore.
- I know, but it's not...
- You're now warm, back to warm.
- No.
- I see what you're saying.
I don't even know what
they're talking about.
And I'm like:
"I'm out of here."
I have to leave
the situation because
arguing about hot and
cold games or anything,
like, so little is just ridiculous.
So thank God we
got fishing equipment,
'cause I'm gonna be
in the water half the time,
and I won't have
to listen to Maryanne
and Lindsay just constantly
going at it about nothing.
That's my escape,
just getting in the water
it helps me a lot.
If I'm alone in the water
for two or three hours,
I can come back to camp
and deal with all this baloney.
I did not hit you.
My foot was under it.
Then you hit it down.
You know I'm doing this.
- Why did you walk over here?
- I was walking...
- ...and then you hit me.
- Okay, back up.
Yeah.
You're so dramatic.
It drives me crazy.
- You hit me, man.
- No, I did not hit you.
Every time something little
happens at camp,
Maryanne makes it
into a ten out of ten.
But I have to control
myself 'cause I can't lose it.
Once I lose it, every... I'm gonna
be labeled as a bad guy.
I'm six-four, I'm 250 pounds,
and I just screamed
at the little girl
that's five-two.
As soon as that happens,
it's over.
I'm swinging a hatchet...
- ...and then you put your toe underneath it...
- But this is my work space.
You came into my work space.
- You're walking back and forth.
- Because it's all my work space.
- Okay, I can't argue with you, Maryanne.
- Look, this is what I'm saying.
- I love you, I don't want to...
- This is what I'm saying.
- Okay.
- Okay?
After we go and
we left the bamboo,
Jonathan immediately went
to the water well with Lindsay,
and I started to get paranoid.
Like, now is he saying:
"Hey, let's go get Maryanne"?
Is it just me, or is Maryanne getting worse?
Yeah.
- She just is so annoying.
- Yeah.
- I think we need to do Maryanne.
- Yes.
- 100%.
I hope he knows
pride's a deadly sin.
This type of stupid fight
that's rifting people apart
is exactly what I don't want.
It's a shame he's too good
of a frickin' shield.
Maryanne is annoying,
but she has a potential
immunity idol,
and she has an extra vote.
Like, we need her.
And I guarantee you,
come the merge time,
if the other tribes see
this sort of behavior,
they'll jump on that right away.
They'll pick her up,
and before you know it,
you're going to be gone because
you couldn't stop being petty.
I'm a little down, I was
hoping we'd merge today.
- You know?
- I know.
The Vati tribe right now it's tense.
- Hi, Hai.
- Hey.
When we're all
around each other,
it's smiles, but I don't
trust these people.
And it took until the first
Tribal for me to realize that.
- So...
- I promise you...
that if we both make merge...
- Bygones be bygones?
- Bygones are bygones.
- We need each other.
- Yeah.
Now, the two games
that really blew up
were Chanelle and Daniel.
I'm gonna have to take...
I have no trust for them.
I know that Daniel's like
the obvious threat to take out,
but he's transparent.
- Chanelle's not transparent.
- Yeah, she's not.
She's harder to read,
and to me that's scary.
They're both scary to me...
- So...
-. ..in a way.
The easy vote,
especially if we want
to make the merge,
is Chanelle.
Mike, do you think you can
get fire going today?
I just don't want to start it
until we have food because...
or we know where
to get food because...
So should we go fishing
first, fire second?
Yeah, 'cause
there's not a lot of...
- There's not a lot of dry wood.
- Okay.
The Vati tribe,
in terms of morale,
I'd give us a "B."
But in terms of actual
survival performance,
I'd give us...
a D-minus.
Don't lose the spear.
We're running off of the fat
that we have on our bodies.
That's pretty much it.
We need to go get fish.
-  Go, Daniel!
- Dan, I believe in you!
Get out there, pal.
- Not.
- You're gonna make it.
All right.
I'm as much a natural fishermen
as an arsonist is
a natural fireman.
But yet it seemed like
the sort of thing
that one must do in Survivor.
Spearfishing is something that's
always highlighted on Survivor.
It always looks cool.
You're using this nifty gadget
to, like, see beautiful coral reefs
and try to catch these
glorious-looking fish.
I think I was more
snorkeling than fishing,
but I was giving fishing
my best shot.
People forget that
fun is important.
They're just so
focused on, like:
"Oh, the next vote is this.
When is the merge?"
It's like: "Calm down.
You're on Survivor."
"Just, like, enjoy yourself."
If he comes out with a limp arm again...
I swear to God.
Wait...
so, he can't compete in physical
challenges but he can go...
spear fishing?
That's what I'm confused about.
Daniel's arm has been
dislocated since day one,
but yet today he's in
the ocean fishing!
What?!
Hey, Mike, Chanelle.
He can't compete
in swimming challenges,
but he can go
swimming for fish?
You can't swim
in a challenge, but
you're gonna go into open
water with a spear, and you're...
Daniel says he
has to stay out of
all the swimming challenges
because he can't swim.
You see how far away
that coral reef is?
It's beautiful out there.
- You guys should go out there.
- Did you see a fish?
Tons of fish.
So you're saying
your aim sucks?
Yes, my aim sucks.
I came close a few times.
You were out there
a long time, too.
- It's really beautiful.
- Was it hard to swim out there?
I find it rather relaxing
and meditating.
We've carried Daniel
from day one,
hiding his shoulder,
putting him out of challenges
so it's not exposed.
How long can you carry a guy
before he becomes
a true liability?
Where'd everyone go?
T went to get water.
Rocks is in the ocean...
...or looking for an idoll.
We should start actually
really doing that.
Yeah, we need to.
We know that there's
an idol out here.
And if there was an idol,
I want myself
or Drea to find it because
she's my number one ally.
What about that one?
The fact that Drea trusts me
enough to go out
and look for a hidden
immunity idol with her proves
how important it is
to have that one person
that you can trust in this game.
And I think that's Drea for me.
I'm gonna keep looking and looking.
We can do this.
Because I work primarily
with women back home
as a pageant coach,
I like working
with strong, independent women.
And I think that's what I saw
in Drea when I first met her.
It was just an instant connection.
One of my role models in
life has always been my mom.
She's just the
strongest woman I know.
She moved to the U.S., and
her entire family was back home
in Central America, so she
sacrificed a lot for me and my sisters.
And that's why I feel like
it's my duty to give back
to strong, independent women.
So I'd like to think that
I'm also coaching Drea
to become an even
better Survivor player
than she already is, and
today we want to find that idol.
"Beware Advantage!"
"If you take it, it's yours and
you must do what it says."
"Otherwise, leave it."
What?
It says "Beware."
I already took a risk
before with the extra vote,
so if it's dangerous,
I'm gonna do it.
"Congratulations, you have found a
three-way shared immunity idol."
This is an idol.
Most women are stuck at camp,
making rice or whatever,
and I just didn't care.
I went out to find an idol.
So kudos.
Women in the new era Survivor 2.0
we can find idols, too.
We're just as good as men.
Probably better, actually.
We're better than men.
Sorry.
"Each tribe beach has one."
"At the next inmunity challenge
you must say a secret phrase..."
"in front of the other players."
"Once all three phrases have been said..."
"at the same immunity challenge,
then all three idols have power."
"But until then, you cannot vote
at any Tribal Council."
- "This is why..."
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
- "Until then, you..."
- "...you cannot vote at any Tribal Council."
Right now, I don't have a vote,
but I have an extra vote.
And if you have a right ally
who can help you,
you can maneuver
around any kind of...
bad juju this thing has.
I have an extra vote, and
I can give you the extra vote.
Okay, so it's like if you're voting
but I'm voting for you..
I have literally
checked every single
Survivor bucket list here.
I have extra vote,
my amulet and my idol.
Currency is everything in Survivor.
And I think I'm Survivor rich.
"Your phrase: Potatoes have skin.
I have skin. Am I a potato?"
"The other two phrases..."
"There's such grace in the game
of soccer it makes me cry."
"It's another classic case of the bunny
rabbit having dinner in the mailbox."
"Rabbit."
She found it.
Maryanne says something
about bunnies.
It kind of reminds
me of the classic tale
of the bunny rabbit eating
its dinner in the mailbox.
Instantly, I know she
has the other one.
Can you tell that
it's in my crotch?
No.
So I am hoping
that some Einstein on Vati
finally finds this and can
say it at the same time
so that we can be done
and over with this.
Are you going to try and activate your idol?
No, if I keep it a secret
until we get to the merge...
- Right, no one will know about the idol.
- ...then no one knows...
Do you get your vote
back at the merge?
- Yep.
- Yeah.
Automatically.
So you have to say the
sentence to activate it early.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Yes, definitely.
So, if we merge tomorrow,
we have an idol,
and I get my vote back
with nobody knowing.
I did find the hidden
immunity idol,
and everybody in our
camp knows about it.
But I don't want nobody
to know I have an idol
from any other tribe because
it puts a target on my back.
If we get to that
merge with that idol,
- and nobody knows...
- And no one knows.
- ...it's a huge weapon for us.
- Yeah.
I'm balancing...
not activating my idol
and not having a vote.
I don't know if
that's balls or stupidity.
Hey, listen, it's a gamble.
I got to be honest with you.
- Right, it's like playing poker.
- Yeah.
And I got to tell you,
we're playing poker pretty good.
So if I go to the immunity
challenge, and I hear
a member of each other
tribe chant their phrase,
I have to make immediate decision.
Do I say my phrase
or not say it?
Come on in.
Taku, Vati, getting your first look
at the new Ika tribe.
Swati voted out at
the last Tribal Council.
And once again,
right on cue, Maryanne
jaw drops,
mouth open, aghast.
It's the classic case
of the bunny rabbit
having dinner at the mailbox.
Like, I always think:
"Okay, this time,
I know what's gonna
happen, this time."
But you never know
in the game of Survivor.
How is everybody
doing 11 days in?
- Hungry.
- What...?
- Agreed.
- Hungry.
- Very hungry.
Okay.
You start going crazy, like,
even when you get food.
Like, we got a potato,
and I was staring at it
for, like, a very,
very long time.
And then we were peeling it,
and I was just all like:
"This potato has skin.
We have skin.
Are we just all potatoes?"
- Oh, my gosh.
- We're tripping.
So it's changing your
relationship with food.
I've always loved food, man,
but, like, now I think
I've got to marry it.
And we're back to love.
The theme for Maryanne.
Jeff, I got to say something.
There's such grace in a game
of soccer that it makes me cry.
Now you wonder
why I'm saying that.
Yeah.
See, I used to coach
youth football,
and soccer season
and football season
were at the same time.
Finally!
Yes!
I've been waiting so long
to just hear something back.
One day, one of my
players jumps up to:
"But, Coach, there is such grace
in soccer that it makes me cry."
Oh, thank God!
I have my vote,
and I have my idol.
So, there is such
grace in soccer
that it makes
me cry, gentlemen.
- Yeah, right.
- Yeah.
I recite my phrase,
which initially wasn't my plan.
But, honestly, it was a
game-time decision.
It was getting later and
later in the tribe game,
and I really thought
my vote was essential.
So this goes from the
non-idol to the active idol.
And guess who has it.
It's a guy with two thumbs.
This guy.
All right, shall we get to
today's immunity challenge?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
All right, first things first.
Got to take back the idols.
Thank you.
- Here you go, Jeff.
- Thank you.
Once again, immunity is
back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're going to race up and over
a tall net ramp.
One player will then
untangle braided ropes
to release a key.
You'll use that key to
unlock a machete,
use the machete to
drop a load of sandbags.
You will then fire those
sandbags, two targets.
First two tribes to
finish win immunity,
safe from the vote.
In addition,
playing for a reward.
Want to know what
you're playing for?
- Yes.
- Please.
- Please be food.
- And sauce.
- Cooked food.
- Food and sauce.
Do it, do it, Jeff.
Just do it, Jeff.
Do you want the bad news?
- Yeah, here it comes.
- It's not food.
We'll take a tarp.
A tarp you got.
That's better than food.
That's much better.
First tribe to finish
a very large tarp.
Smaller tarp for
the second tribe.
Losers Tribal Council where somebody
will be voted out of this
game, and sorry for you.
I will be taking your flint.
Vati, you have one extra person.
Gonna sit somebody out.
- I have very little value to add.
- Who's it gonna be?
Again?
Daniel gonna sit out.
All right, Daniel, take a
spot on the sit-out bench.
Everybody else, give you
a minute to strategize,
and we'll get started.
Here we go.
All right, for immunity
and reward.
Survivors ready?
Go!
Got to get up and over
a very tall net ramp.
- It takes teamwork.
- Go.
Push my feet.
Got it?
- Got it.
- Okay.
- Lindsay's up.
- Go.
All three tribes working
together really well.
- You got it?
- Ika doing a great job.
Drea, wow.
Drea pulling herself up.
That is not easy.
- Roll, roll.
- I'm rolling!
Roll more.
It's Ika in the early
lead right now.
You're good.
Start working it.
- Let's go.
- You're good, start working it.
Gonna be Tori now
untangling the braided rope.
Go, Tori.
And Omar untangling now.
- There you go, baby girl.
- Vati taking a long time...
- ...to get over this.
- Come on.
- Here.
- Nothing is easy on Survivor.
- Come on.
- Every single step...
- You got it?
- ...you got to earn it.
- I'm good, I'm good.
- Come on, Vati!
I'm good, I'm good.
It's now Chanelle in on it.
- Tori doing a great job for Ika.
- You're almost there.
Once that key drops, you can
use it to unlock the machete.
- Tori's got the key.
- You got it, you got it, you got it, get it.
Unclip it.
You're good.
- Unclip.
- She's got the key.
Come on, you guys.
Tori's gonna also
do the machete now.
- Got it. Go, Rocks.
- She's got it now.
- She's got it.
- Go.
There you go, you're good!
Start getting your sandbags!
It is Ika still in the lead.
Go.
Omar and Chanelle
taking a long time
to untangle their braided rope.
It's gonna be Drea coming in
to fire that first slingshot.
Ika with a big lead right now.
Good one, Drea!
Drea, nice fire.
Just misses.
Yes, yes.
- All right.
- Chanelle has the key.
- Gonna give it to Mike.
- Mike, it's right here.
- Mike gonna handle the machete.
- Come on, Mike, just come on.
Guys.
Tap it!
Way to go, Mike!
Vati's back in this now.
Got to get all your
sandbags in the bin.
Drea does it.
One target down for Ika.
- Go, Rocksroy!
- Rocksroy coming in now.
Left one goes up.
Omar still working on the ropes.
The one in, one in your
bottom goes to the left.
This is a big setback, with
Tribal Council on the line.
You can see it in the faces
of the tribe members watching.
- What is wrong?
- Keep going back.
Rocksroy for Ika.
- Just misses.
- Go! Go! Go!
Mike coming in now for Vati.
Mike all the way back,
- and he just misses.
- Great shot!
- Yup, bring down the middle.
- Okay.
Omar really in
trouble right now.
Lindsay trying to walk him
through it, Jonathan frustrated.
Can't even watch anymore.
Yup, and then one to the...
and then the one to the left.
It is hard to describe how
long Omar has been working.
So sorry, guys.
Somebody is going home tonight.
Rocksroy for the win.
There it is!
Ika wins immunity
and a large tarp.
Nobody going home.
Oh, my God.
We're looking for one more.
Immunity on the line.
Mike takes a big fall.
Bring that one
down the middle, yup.
And then we should have it.
Okay.
- All right.
- Now you go.
There you go, Taku.
Let's go!
Jonathan takes the key.
With one chop releases the bags!
Come on, Vati.
You got this!
There goes Chanelle trying
to knock down the first target.
Suddenly,
Taku could be back in this
because Vati has
yet to get any
rhythm going on the slingshot.
- Go, go, go, go!
- Another horrible misfire.
It's going to be Jonathan in.
And right now,
we are back at even.
- It is Jonathan and Mike.
- Yeah, you got this.
All the way back,
all the way back.
Jonathan knocks down
the first target for Tak
Right there.
Taku took forever to get here,
but they are back in it.
Mike knocks down
the first target for Vati.
We are tied now!
One target left.
Here comes Chanelle.
Here comes Jonathan.
So close, babe.
Just misses.
Jonathan for the win.
Here comes Mike.
And he's got it!
Taku wins immunity and tarps.
Sending Vati to Tribal Council,
where somebody will be
voted out of Survivor 42.
- Oh my God.
- Big comeback.
- We were so close.
- So freaking...
It was close.
Ika, nice job.
Immunity is yours.
Nobody going home.
Come grab your big tarp.
This thing is heavy.
Taku, nice comeback.
Immunity is yours again.
Who wants to grab the tarp?
Smaller, but it will get
the job done for sure.
Amen, Mr. Jeff.
- Mr. Jeff.
Still not used to it.
All right, before I send
you on your way,
two players gonna be
taking a journey today.
Ika, pick somebody from
Vati to take the journey.
They cannot have gone
on a journey this season.
- Okay.
- Who you going to send?
Lydia.
All right, Lydia's gonna
go on a journey.
Now, one person's
gonna join her.
It can be from Taku, or it
can be from your tribe.
- Yeah, you can go.
- I'm gonna go.
Go for it.
Who's it gonna be?
- Rocks.
Rocksroy and Lydia,
grab your stuff, head out.
You'll return back to your tribe
before Tribal Council tonight.
Ika, you've got the tarp.
Your flint will be waiting
for you back at camp.
Grab your stuff,
no Tribal tonight.
Taku, grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
- No Tribal Council tonight.
- Thanks, Jeff.
All right, Vati,
Tribal Council tonight.
Somebody will be
voted out of this game.
Before you go,
I need your flint.
- It's for you, Jeff.
- Thanks, Chanelle.
You'll have a
chance to win it back
at the next immunity challenge.
Grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
I'm actually really excited
about losing today
because now I get to
kind of trim the fat.
And Chanelle and Daniel
are the fat of the tribe
because I trust them the least.
They led me on.
When they drew the tribal lines,
I knew the game was on.
So we all know what's coming.
Scramble before Tribal.
Let's make sure
that we just remember
we are still a Vati family
at the end of
all of this, okay?
Yeah.
I had something
to say, actually.
So...
I know that my head is possibly
on the chopping block tonight.
I don't really want to scramble,
but if you're willing
to give it to me,
I'd love just a chance to speak
with each of you, one-on-one.
Dan, I don't think
that's scrambling.
- I think you should...
- Yeah, yeah.
...100% have the right
to talk to everyone.
Play your game, man.
Play your game.
I just want to add to that.
I feel like
my head is also
on the chopping block,
so if I could just talk
to each of you guys,
- I'd appreciate that.
- Okay.
Cool.
Thank you.
Chanelle and I feel
the heat tonight.
And I was ready to go
to the end with Chanelle.
And yet we're here because
when push came to shove
she did not have my back.
So why should I trust her
going forward?
I'm with you to the end.
That's all I have to say.
Out of you and Chanelle...
...I trust you more.
- Chanelle's going home.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Period, I don't trust her.
- Yeah.
I think if I get to
the merge with her,
she's going to flip immediately.
And I'm worried
she wouldn't just flip.
She would kind of drag us.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
I think Chanelle needs to go
because I agree with Hai.
She's likely to
flip at the merge.
So if you know
someone's going to flip,
it's better to get rid
of 'em when you can
than to wait for
them to flip on you.
So, you are a hundred percent
writing down Daniel's name?
He's definitely going.
Yeah.
We have to.
- We have to for so many reasons.
- Yeah.
I think the consensus is,
everyone wants Daniel gone.
Like, you are 100%
writing his name down?
- Absolutely.
- Great.
We're good.
Sold.
- It's a done deal.
- If everything's...
Daniel's go... Look at me.
Daniel's going home.
Got it.
Daniel has one arm, he hasn't
competed in any challenges.
Not only that, I think people seeing
him go swimming yesterday
was also something that kind
of set them over the edge.
I just got to make sure
he feels confident enough...
- ...that he doesn't play...
- ...not to shot-in-the-dark.
Yeah.
What are your thoughts?
Whichever one of them
goes home, I will still be able...
- ...to sleep a little better tonight.
- 100%.
- I don't... honestly?
- Yeah.
As long as me, you
and Lydia don't go home.
We really have to evaluate
which one of these two
will be best for us long-term.
They're two weasels
in a chicken coop.
Both Daniel and Chanelle
have felt as though
they've reintegrated themselves
back into the tribe.
It's just...
not nearly enough.
Mathematically, we're good
because now we have
three votes: me, you and Lydia.
I feel a lot better.
I'll do whatever you want.
Now that Mike has his vote,
we have the majority
of the votes
between Lydia, myself and Mike
that we can split up
just in case
one of them plays a Shot
in the Dark or has an advantage.
The main thing is, Lydia cannot
have taken that shot.
We need her vote.
At this journey, it's extremely
important what Lydia does.
The main thing
that Lydia can't do,
can't do is take a chance
for an advantage.
If she loses her vote,
we are in trouble.
Holy cow.
Wow.
We're here.
- We're really here.
- Wow.
You won't get this anywhere else.
Just put this in a
memory bank and hold.
Wow.
Anytime you get to a
bad place in your life,
- bring this up, holy moly.
- For sure.
Survivor breaks you down, and
everything is stripped away.
I'm learning a lot about myself.
One of those things is just
being comfortable in my own skin.
I've struggled,
as most young women
and just, like,
young people in general,
struggle with body image issues.
And coming on Survivor was
a really big challenge for me,
not only just with
the elements but just, like,
you see people very
open with their bodies.
And a big source of the way
I started dressing was
just 'cause I was
trying to hide.
But you can only
be open out here.
And my body is perfect
just the way it is.
And I feel like I have gotten
more confident in it.
It's not even halfway through
the game, and I'm just, like,
I've already accomplished so much.
There's still more to see.
There's still more to do,
and it's just going
to keep getting more
and more beautiful.
So who do you think
tonight's going to be...
- ...on the chopping block for you guys?
- For us?
I don't know.
I know, and, of course,
like, I'm not there.
So I'm just nervous, of course,
going in, you know,
that it could be me.
Even though I am
in a decent position
going into Tribal now,
I'd mentioned I was, like,
kind of on the bottom.
I'm just meeting Rocksroy,
so I'm trying not to give too
much information about our tribe.
So you feel as
if you're gonna...
you could be a potential?
Definitely, yeah, I was definitely
on the chopping block last time.
- Why?
- Um, no idea.
My first impression of Lydia
was, she seemed more like
someone that's in trouble,
but, of course,
as I didn't, you don't want
to give your opponent
too much information.
Are you guys all tight?
Uh, who is tight?
- You know, it's like...
- Yeah.
I'm trying to just
get a feel for
how camp life is,
who he trusts, and
I got nothing.
"You will now separate
and make a private decision
before returning to camp."
Hey, I'm rooting for you.
- Thank you, I appreciate it.
- All right? I am.
Rocksroy was being very cagey.
And I feel like I was as well.
I think we both wanted
to protect our tribe.
Because we don't know where
we're headed to in this game.
"Protect your vote."
"Risk your vote."
"Here's how it works."
If Lydia and I both pick
"risk your vote,"
then we both lose our vote
at the next Tribal Council.
If Lydia and I say "protect our
vote," then nothing changes
and we're able to vote
at the next Tribal Council.
But if Lydia says
"protect her vote"
and I choose "risk your vote,"
then Lydia remains the same;
me, I receive an extra vote.
I feel like as if
I should risk my vote.
But speaking with Lydia,
seems as if
she's on the bottom of
the totem pole in her tribe.
I think she's gonna risk it
for the biscuit.
An opportunity like this
definitely doesn't come...
very often.
Having an advantage in this
game is just so important.
Coming from Vegas,
don't gamble often,
but when I do, I know that when
I'm up on the house, walk away.
So I'm gonna use my brain...
...and I'm gonna
protect my vote.
It is so hard to get
advantages in the game,
but I think it scares me
more to not have a vote
going into a really
important Tribal.
Lydia!
- Welcome back.
- Welcome home party.
I'm very glad that
I protected my vote.
If circumstances were
different, I definitely think
I might have risked it
for my own personal gain.
The same thing as Jenny said,
you go to a wheel,
risk your vote,
protect your vote.
- I protected my vote.
- Nice.
But we're not in individual yet.
We're going to Tribal
tonight as a tribe,
and I just don't feel
comfortable giving away
the most important thing
I have in this game.
I'm gonna go down to the beach,
and wash my feet off,
if anybody wants
to come with me.
But now I really want to
touch base with everyone
to give me a rundown
of what happened at camp.
How are you feeling
about tonight?
I'm okay.
Yeah, Mike is like, "I'm writing
Daniel's name down."
You know he's got his vote back now?
Yes, I guess.
I feel good.
Like, I was like...
If anything...
I trust you and Hai.
Yeah, no, you absolutely
can trust us.
I'm sorry that I voted for you.
- It was a mistake.
- Yeah.
I'm totally with you
going forward.
To be totally honest, I think
you are the queenmaker.
You and Hai...
...are deciding,
and I think Chanelle and I
are probably on the block.
Daniel and Chanelle,definitely,
they're very nervous,
but they both think it's
the other person going home.
Chanelle, I don't fully trust her,
and Daniel is a liability.
And at our last Tribal Council,
he was trying to get me out.
But clearly, me and Hai
are definitely running this vote.
So here's the recap.
I've talked to everyone.
Mike is 100 on board.
- Daniel is voting Chanelle.
- For sure.
Lydia gets back,
and I have to scramble
to get some alone time with her,
because we are about
to head to Tribal immediately.
I know 100% that
Daniel is comfortable.
It's not you.
It's between Daniel, Chanelle.
So that's where it stands.
- As long as it's not me.
- It's not you.
It's not us, we just have
to stick to the plan.
The merge is coming up
any day now,
so tonight's Tribal
Council is monumental
because not only does it
affect the rest of my game,
it's going to affect how
the merge is going to play out.
I'm just nervous because
whether it be Chanelle or Daniel
that goes into
the merge with me
will determine how
well I do in this game.
All right.
Mike, give me an analogy
from your world
that you come from
that captures where
this tribe is at.
You know, Jeff, once in a while,
when I was a fireman,
somebody on the crew
maybe didn't do something
that they should have did,
but that didn't mean
we didn't stick together.
As with this tribe, tonight
we're gonna lose
a member of our tribe,
but it doesn't mean
that we're not solid.
Daniel, what do you
read into that?
Mike is a straight shooter.
Mike, to his core,
is a team guy.
Some people come
into this game,
and from the get-go, they're
playing an individual game.
And I don't think you can
win Survivor doing that.
And Mike is not
one of those people.
So then, Hai, how do you
vote somebody out
if Mike's story is accurate?
Which is, we're just
one firehouse,
but somebody's got to go.
Yeah, this game is hard.
I see five autonomous
players here
who all have the goal
of getting to the end.
So unfortunately someone
here is being lied to,
or multiple people.
Daniel, let's go with Hai's idea
that somebody's being lied to.
Give me an analogy
from your world...
- Oh, geez.
- ...where lying is fun.
It's part of it.
I should be honest with you, Jeff,
I'm not an analogy guy.
But, sorry, can I jump back
on the Mike thing?
- Yeah.
- When he talks about teams,
he's not talking about
teams just in Survivor.
I think Mike sees this as a team
for, like, the rest of his life.
And by that I mean
the very end.
That's true.
Wait, when you said
"to the very end,"
- ...you mean until you are dying.
- Yeah, I think, I think,
I think, like, hopefully
I live longer than Mike.
- Um...
- It's a very good possibility.
Yeah.
Yeah, but, like, I feel like
Mike and I will probably,
you know, be friends to the
very end of whoever goes first.
Knock on wood it's not me.
Mike's 117, so we don't know
how much longer he has.
- 116.
- Yeah.
Jeff, I actually want to
jump in because I think that,
like, the two different themes
that you're noting.
Friendship and then
the game of Survivor
I think we're seeing it
come to play, like,
right here in front of us.
Because Daniel's comment right
there is him playing the game,
playing to Mike's
soft spot, his heart.
Let me just go and pat
Mike on the back again.
Team, friendship.
And so, like, that's playing
the game right there.
It's almost kind of
milking it a bit.
Daniel, that was pretty clear.
She doesn't buy it.
You might mean it,
but right now
you're saying it
because you're at Tribal.
I didn't mean any game strategy
by that, to be totally honest.
I try to be as
genuine as possible.
Like, there are things
that I could have kept secret.
I mean, I'm a leukemia survivor.
I could have kept that secret,
but I cannot play this game
without being true to who I am.
And, yes, you have to
lie sometimes and stuff,
but I analogize that to, like...
I have an analogy, actually.
Yes.
Okay, I analogize that
to boxing.
You know, like, Muhammad Ali
was one of the best boxers
in the entire world.
He didn't go down the street
punching random people.
He only punched people
when he was boxing.
Right?, so when we're
playing Survivor, we lie,
but in our real lives,
we don't lie.
It's just, like,
part of the game.
So, Lydia, then what
would a vote
be based on tonight
with this tribe?
What are some of the criteria
that might come up?
You know, after tonight,
each tribe is gonna be
four, four and four.
And so no one
has numbers, you know?
And we're speculating a merge,
you know, coming up.
Hopefully soon.
- Please.
- We've been talking about that feast.
Even if it was rice, we're like:
"All right, we'll take it."
So I think one of
the criteria is, like,
who can I trust the most
going forward?
Especially in a game where
the numbers are not obvious.
All right, so, Hai, for Lydia,
she's saying it's trust.
- Yeah.
- How about for you?
100%, trust is the most
valuable currency out here.
If you look back at
the last Tribal we were at...
...there were six blindsides.
And when trust is broken,
it's very hard to win back.
So for me, it's about
establishing trust,
'cause I want to
make it to the end.
- Daniel, you're nodding.
- I mean, unless you're...
one of the greatest
players ever, and I'm not one,
you get burned at least once.
You have to be able
to look past the burn,
and sometimes, when you were
the one who did the burning,
ask for forgiveness.
If you can't do that,
I think you're gonna play
a short Survivor game.
Chanelle, if you're
keeping the people
that are most trustworthy,
then the person
you're getting rid of has
to be the least trustworthy.
Uh, I think that's what
someone reasonable would deduct
from what we're
hearing, so, yes.
Wow, is it hard for you
to answer that question?
No, I mean, the
writing's on the wall.
Like, a reasonable
conclusion would be that
if we are voting based on trust,
the person who is voted out
is ultimately not
high in that category,
the least trustworthy.
And, Mike, you do have
to make those decisions.
It doesn't mean,
to your point earlier,
that you might not like
this person personally,
but in this game it's
just not my best move.
My vote tonight
is strictly gameplay.
Has nothing to do with
how I personally feel at all.
I want to be friends
with whoever gets voted off
here tonight for
the rest of my life.
Sometimes it's hard
to play Survivor
in the way you want to play it.
Tonight I'm playing Survivor.
Okay, it is time to vote.
Mike, you're up.
If anybody has an
advantage or an idol
and you want to play it, now
would be the time to do so.
Okay, I'll read the votes.
First vote...
Chanelle.
Daniel.
Two votes Chanelle.
We're tied.
Two votes Chanelle,
two votes Daniel,
one vote left.
Mike.
We have a tie.
Two votes for Chanelle,
two votes for Daniel.
Here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna revote.
You can only vote
for Daniel or Chanelle.
Daniel and Chanelle,
you can only vote for
each other, so you won't vote.
Mike, if you want
to come grab the urn.
I'll read the votes.
First vote...
Daniel.
Sixth person voted
out of Survivor 42.
Daniel, that's two.
That's enough.
You need to bring me your torch.
Well played, guys.
Love you, Dan.
- Bye, Dan.
All right, it's only
once in a lifetime.
I'm going to enjoy this.
Here we go, Jeff.
Daniel, the tribe has spoken.
The tribe has spoken.
Time for you to go.
Bye, Dan.
Man, that's heartbreaking.
I kept my promise.
Somebody voted for me.
Grab your torches, head back
to camp, good night.
Stay tuned for scenes from our next episode.
Next time on a two-hour episode of Survivor...
Everybody drop your buffs.
Oh, my God!
So, is this called the merge?
Not exactly.
This is the biggest moment
in the game so far.
It is going to be just chaos.
I'm gonna keep fighting
in this game till I'm dead.
I got totally blindsided, I would
have preferred to execute
the blindside, but at least
I got a form of blindside.
That's part of the
Survivor experience.
If I could have
scripted my life,
I probably wouldn't have
given myself leukemia, right?
And if I could
have scripted Survivor,
I probably would
have had myself winning,
but the beauty of life
is that it's unscripted.
That's how we find
meaning in it.