♪ ♪
MIKE:
Congratulations, everybody.
We made the merge.
My friends, what a wild ride.
MIKE:
At Tribal Council,
the majority of the tribe
worked together.
And as hard as it was
to make that decision,
Lydia had to go home.
And it was
the right decision for
my core alliance right now.
MIKE:
Immediately who would be
left on the outs would be Tori,
Chanelle, Romeo and Maryanne.
They were like
how rats get
when you turn on the lights,
and they scurry away
in different places.
That's what they were doing.
They were scurrying away,
looking for places to go,
to hide and talk.
Wow. I'm the only one left out
of it. How did Mike know?
Hai, how did Mike ... know
and not me?
Because Mike was at camp all
day, and we were at the beach.
CHANELLE: Tonight, I was on the
wrong side of the numbers, and
if there's any mistake
not to make,
do not come into the merge
and end up on the wrong side
of the numbers.
CHANELLE: My spot in the game
is really up in the air.
I think tonight is
the first night I realized
that I, in my head,
was playing chess
while everyone else
was playing checkers,
and it was a huge wakeup call
to get my head in the game.
DREA:
Romeo was my closest ally, but
things changed as soon
as we came to the merge.
He's been totally different.
He's just becoming one
of the most paranoid players
I think I've seen.
And, like, it's not helping
my game right now, so,
if Romeo has to go,
then Romeo has to go.
LINDSAY:
I just want you to know
-that I voted for Lydia.
-Mm-hmm.
-That was where my intention
was going.
-Mm-hmm.
And I still truly trust you.
Obviously, it sucks
to be, like, left out.
No one was talking to me.
-Of course, like, I'm with you.
-Mm-hmm.
MARYANNE:
The people in the Taku tribe
are telling me,
"Don't worry. I have your back."
But I know that I'm basically
at the bottom of the tribe,
which honestly sucks so much
because it's like
I flash back all the way back
to elementary school.
And it's like I felt like
I finally found out who I was
and that people would accept me.
And, like, I know it's a game,
and there's reasons
why people are on the bottom,
but it's like
I'm too weird
to be a part of the cool kids.
All you can think of is, like,
I suck.
There's something wrong with me,
and that's why people don't want
to work with me.
MARYANNE:
Ooh!
TORI:
Fancy.
MIKE:
Coming on Survivor,
I'm representing
the over-55 crowd,
the 15% discount
at Denny's crowd.
And the important thing
for me to do at my age is
to be somebody
that they can talk to,
somebody they can trust, and
I'm learning from them.
OMAR:
Yeah.
Allahu Akbar.
MIKE:
So here we got a guy Omar.
He's a completely
different religion than me--
the religion of Islam.
I don't know anything
about it, so,
I'm curious.
Allahu Akbar.
MIKE:
I say, "Omar, would you mind
if I ask you about it?"
And he sits down
and has a conversation
with me for about an hour.
And you know what,
again, you realize?
We all ain't that different.
So I say a little bit more
in Arabic, and then I pray
-in English when I'm like this.
-Okay, cool.
OMAR:
Mike is such an interesting,
lovely human being.
He's an older gentleman,
but when he experiences
new things,
he doesn't run away from it
like a lot of people
of his age may.
He truly embraces it.
Hey, thank you for sharing,
man. I appreciate it.
OMAR:
And I think that's so admirable.
His empathy is so strong,
he could be somebody
that I can align with long-term.
(squeaking)
-Tree mail.
(cheering)
Okay, is the class ready?
-Yes.
"Flying high,
and splashing down,
"a sure shot can seal the deal.
"If a taste of home
is worth playing for,
"then battle for a favorite
-childhood meal."
-ROCKSROY: Oh, wow.
MARYANNE:
It's a reward.
Yeah.
TORI: The reason
I really want this reward
is 'cause I know
that when people are eating,
when they're relaxed,
they talk more.
Last night
I was not in on the vote,
so I see this
as a great opportunity.
In this game, you have
to make bolder moves.
PROBST:
In Survivor 41,
we put an advantage
on this same bench,
almost in this exact same spot
in the water,
and it wasn't found,
which was a little surprising.
You should be looking.
So we're going to do it again,
only this time,
it is a Beware Advantage,
which is much more dangerous
because if you don't do
what it tells you to do,
there is a penalty.
Same spot,
and this time,
if it's not found,
not only will I be surprised.
I'll also be
a little disappointed.
All right, ready to get
to today's reward challenge?
-(all assenting)
-We are.
PROBST:
For today's challenge,
you'll be randomly divided
into two teams.
On my go, you're gonna leap
into the water...
...and maneuver a buoy
through a series of obstacles.
Once you get
all five buoys here,
you'll attempt
to toss them into a basket.
First team
to finish wins reward.
Want to know
what you're playing for?
-Absolutely.
-Yes, sir.
Little taste from home.
-PB and J and potato chips...
-Oh, my...
-MIKE: Oh, my God.
...waiting for you back at camp.
-Ooh la la!
-TORI: Oh.
PROBST:
Worth playing for?
-Sure.
-Yeah. Thanks, Jeff.
-All right.
We're going to divide
into two teams. One person
will not be on a team.
One person will not compete.
You want color.
You don't want gray.
Everybody put your hands out,
and everybody reveal.
JONATHAN:
Thank you, God.
If you are blue,
go down to that end.
If you're orange,
come down to this end.
If you're gray,
go right in the middle.
Maryanne, you drew the gray,
which means
you're not competing.
You will have no shot
at the PB and J.
DREA:
I was going to say,
-can we switch with Maryanne?
-PROBST: So, wait.
So, Drea, you're saying you want
to switch with Maryanne?
Yeah, I don't like
peanut butter and jelly,
so I'm willing to switch
with Maryanne if she wants to.
Then, when I can, on a reward,
if I can do the favor,
I'm gonna do it, okay?
Switch is made.
-Nice job, guys.
-Drea now
sitting out,
Maryanne now in for orange.
All right, I'll give you guys
a minute to strategize.
Drea, you'll take a spot
on the bench. Let's do this!
Here we go, for PB and J
and potato chips back at camp.
Survivors ready.
-Go!
-(cheering)
PROBST:
Gonna be Jonathan up first
-and Lindsay.
-MARYANNE: Nice!
PROBST:
Got to climb up the ladder,
then leap off.
-Whoa! That's how you do it!
-MARYANNE: Whoa.
-(indistinct chatter)
-Beautiful dives
-straight out of the gate.
-MARYANNE: Whoa!
PROBST:
And they are neck and neck.
DREA:
Let's go, guys.
PROBST:
Got to thread that buoy
around the obstacle
and then get over
the obstacle yourself.
Jonathan's gonna get over first,
but Lindsay is right behind.
♪ ♪
(Maryanne whoops)
Jonathan powering
through that water
with one stroke,
just the left arm.
♪ ♪
-DREA: Keep going, Lindsay!
-PROBST: Here comes Lindsay.
Come on, Lindsay!
Jonathan's out
of the obstacle first.
DREA:
Come on, Lindsay.
-Lindsay is right on his tail.
-Good job, Jonathan.
You got to hit that post.
Go, blue!
TORI:
Go, Chanelle!
PROBST:
Chanelle holding the nose.
-Go, orange!
-MARYANNE: Nice!
-Come on!
-PROBST: Now Hai going
-for broke.
-LINDSAY: Whoa!
PROBST:
Hai gets to the platform first.
There's Chanelle.
They're side by side.
We are still very tight
in this challenge.
MARYANNE:
Nice, Hai!
PROBST:
Hai's gonna be over first.
Chanelle right behind here.
-Still very close.
-(indistinct shouting)
DREA:
I start looking around
where I'm sitting,
and I see the same kind
of advantage I saw before.
It says "Beware Advantage."
But if you know me by now,
I'm not gonna beware
of the advantage.
I'm gonna take the advantage
to see what it is.
Hai is up. Go, orange!
-It's Omar into the water
for orange.
-(indistinct shouting)
-Got to get to the post.
Go, blue!
-TORI: Go, Mike!
-Gonna be Mike for blue...
-Let's go, Mike! You can do it!
...with a big leap!
-CHANELLE: There you go!
-TORI: Yes! Yes!
CHANELLE:
There you go!
DREA:
So I take the advantage,
and people were starting
to come my way,
and I put it in my pants.
-(indistinct shouting)
-PROBST: Rocksroy jumps.
-Romeo jumps.
-That's how you do it, Romeo.
Good job, Romeo!
This is crazy.
I didn't do the reward
because I don't like PB and J,
but at the same time,
I feel like I got the reward
by getting the advantage.
Go, blue!
DREA:
So I'm feeling
super excited.
(whooping)
But at the same time,
I know when
it says "Beware," that means
that there's more to the story.
PROBST:
Romeo struggling to get up.
Go, orange!
-Now Maryanne can go.
-(screaming)
-OMAR: Yeah!
Maryanne in the water.
(cheering)
-You got it! Great job!
-There you go!
PROBST:
You're good. Untie the knot.
You can put people in the water.
Two rebounders, one shooter.
Maryanne working
through that second obstacle.
Rocksroy now shooting.
More.
PROBST:
Takes a minute
to figure out that distance.
-Punch it, punch it, punch it.
-PROBST: Maryanne is back.
-Now you can go.
-Can we jump in?
Go in. Two people in the water.
-Rocksroy lines it up.
Thought he had it.
-Oh.
Here goes Omar.
(cheering)
Omar scores the first
for orange.
Orange now in the lead.
-Omar scores the second
for orange!
-(cheering)
Omar, is that in? It is.
-That is three for orange.
-(cheering)
Orange on fire!
PROBST:
Jonathan coming out.
He's going to shoot.
Omar, for the fourth,
launches it.
-And he's got it.
-(cheering)
-Omar single-handedly...
-Last one!
...has put orange within one
buoy of winning this challenge.
Just off the rim.
Jonathan tosses.
Can he get it?
-There's one for blue!
-MIKE: Go.
-TORI: Same thing.
-Omar could win it
right here for orange.
He misses,
and that buoy goes way out.
-There's two for blue.
-Whoa.
Jonathan now got hot.
You got to get
that buoy back fast!
ROCKSROY:
Nail it.
Jonathan hits a third.
We got a challenge.
-Jonathan with the fourth!
-Whoa!
-One more, one more...
-Blue could win it.
What a comeback it would be.
-And they do!
-Yeah!
-Blue pulls it out.
-Come on! Come on!
Unbelievable momentum
-by Jonathan. Five in a row.
-MIKE: Oh, my God.
-Let's go.
-Oh, my God.
-PROBST: Wow.
What a turnaround,
proving once again
why you never, ever
-give up in this game.
-MIKE: Give me a hug.
-Give me a hug.
-♪
♪
All right,
Tori, Chanelle, Rocksroy, Mike,
Jonathan, massive
come-from-behind victory.
PB and J and potato chips
waiting for you back at camp.
Drea, Lindsay, Hai, Maryanne,
Romeo, Omar,
got nothing for you.
Swim out.
Enjoy your afternoon.
♪ ♪
-OMAR: Congrats, guys.
-LINDSAY: Brown bag lunch.
-Yeah.
-(overlapping chatter)
Congrats. Well earned.
JONATHAN:
I walk into camp, and I see
each of us have
an individually-packed sandwich,
just like
your mom made it for you.
And you take it out back
and you eat it.
Look at that.
They were not cheap
with the peanut butter
and the jelly. It's oozing.
JONATHAN:
I'm normally 250 pounds,
and I work out all the time.
I probably eat 4,000
to 5,000 calories a day.
And on an average,
I've probably had 400 calories
a day out here.
So any food I can get,
it's going to help me think
more clear, do better
in the challenges,
even if it's one sandwich.
I'm so thankful
for this right now.
Y'all have no idea.
Listen, guys, I'm licking
the paper. I don't care
-what anybody says.
-No. Do it. You better.
I can't speak for everybody,
but it's okay
that we didn't get the reward.
-I had a great time
on that challenge.
-MARYANNE: Mm-hmm.
-Mm-hmm.
-I'm so proud of everyone.
The fact that we were so close,
I can't even be upset.
-(overlapping chatter)
-Like, I really am
-totally not sour whatsoever.
-OMAR: I know.
You got four in a row. I'm like,
yo, he's hot right now.
DREA:
Yeah.
Oh, I was so mad
at that last one
that dinged off
the back end of it.
-DREA: No problem.
-HAI: It's all good.
-Oh.
OMAR:
Even though we lost,
today's reward challenge
was exhilarating
because I almost won
a challenge,
and I feel like
I'm doing well out here.
OMAR:
Hi.
Right now, my game
is simply
about creating options.
As many options
moving forward as possible.
And I'm not closing any doors
right now.
LINDSAY:
Mm-hmm.
-LINDSAY: Yeah.
-Yeah.
So right now I have alliances
with the bigger group.
Don't tell Tori anything
'cause she's so good
at creating chaos.
-LINDSAY: Yeah.
-She's so good.
OMAR:
And then I have an individual
alliance with each one
of the outliers.
I haven't officially,
like, got a plan from anyone,
but, um, if I had to guess,
I would say
people are gonna split
between Tori and Romeo
-and send Tori home.
-Yeah.
OMAR:
Because I didn't have a vote,
people still think
I'm on the bottom,
and I'm still gonna work
with them,
and they think I was left out,
which is brilliant
because then I have intel coming
from every side of the game.
Information is
the most powerful thing
in the game right now,
so having eyes
and ears on every side
of the island
is invaluable
for my game moving forward.
DREA: At the challenge,
I got an advantage, and
I've been hoping
that there would be a chance
when I get to camp that I'll be
able to read it and actually
see what it is.
Five paces away
from the coconut.
I know that the only chance
I have to do this is now,
because everyone goes
to the water well to talk.
So I go to the water well,
and I'm, like, counting out
five paces one way.
One, two, three, four, five.
I start flipping over coconuts,
and I don't see anything.
So I turn around,
and I see that there's
one coconut that's spread open.
And I'm like,
"If it's close to five paces,
I think that might be it."
So I reach down, open it up.
And it's just, like, this hole.
And I'm like,
"What's in this hole?"
Oh, my God.
(quietly):
What is this?
So I put my hand in,
and I pull out this container
covered in red paint. (laughs)
Why am I red?
I kind of get
the point of the advantage
where it says
"caught red-handed,"
because it's gonna be
all over your hand.
So I instantly go
to the water well
and start throwing water over
my hand and start panicking,
thinking like,
"I have to get it off.
I have to get
this red stuff off."
I felt like I was on CSI,
and, like, I had to cover it up
before, like, the detectives
came and caught me.
The Knowledge Is Power Advantage
is a tremendous advantage
in this game.
I know
two people who have idols--
-Maryanne and Mike.
-(laughs)
DREA:
So this Knowledge Is Power
is an opportunity
to blindside one of them and
take their idol if I have to.
So, right now I have my amulet.
I have my idol.
I have my extra vote.
And I have
my Knowledge Is Power Advantage.
With all this power,
now it's about strategizing
how to utilize the items
so that it best fits my game,
and so that
I don't become a threat.
That's really important to me.
MIKE:
One sandwich and chips.
-DREA: Yeah.
-MIKE: It was a good meal.
And you know what?
It wasn't too much.
It was actually perfect.
TORI: No, on your arm. No, no,
no, yeah, it's on your arm.
Right there.
Tori's like, "Are you bleeding?"
So I tried to
play it off like it was
paint to paint our-our flag.
Oh, gosh.
DREA:
Tori's really good at knowing,
like, when something's off.
She doesn't show it, but she is.
TORI:
Drea comes back to camp,
she has, like, red on her arm.
And I was like,
"Oh, my gosh. Is that blood?"
Genuinely being concerned.
She's like, "No, it was...
I was painting."
And then I look
at our tribal flag.
There's no paint on it.
And then I notice
there's something in her pants,
and she's being very weird.
She's, like,
covering herself
with her backpack.
So, yeah, I'm like,
"What is she up to?"
-I saw paint on her arm.
-Mm-hmm.
And she was like,
"Oh, yeah, I was just
playing around with the paint."
Mm.
Well, there's
nothing on the canvas,
-so where'd you
go paint something?
-Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
DREA:
Right now,
I definitely feel like
Tori suspects something.
And I don't trust Tori
in this game.
Every time I've tried
to trust Tori,
Tori has tried to blindside me
or tried to
get me out of the game.
So she needs to go.
♪ ♪
Okay. In Survivor 41, at this
exact same point in the game,
we gave the players the option
to sit out of the challenge
in exchange for
an individual portion of rice.
It led to a group negotiation
where four players
agreed to sit out
in exchange for enough rice
for everybody for three days.
So we're gonna do
it again this season,
only we're gonna make it
enough rice for four days,
And I'm gonna try
to get six players to sit out--
more than half the tribe.
I'll tell you the truth.
I'll settle again at four
if they push hard enough.
But lest you
future players think,
oh, I'm an easy negotiator,
just remember,
history is merely an indicator
of what might happen
in the future.
Next season,
the monster may have a much,
much bigger appetite.
Come on in!
♪ ♪
Getting leaner.
-Thank you.
-PROBST: Yeah.
Survivor diet.
Clothes are hanging.
Jonathan almost looks human.
(laughter)
All right, shall we get to
today's immunity challenge?
-Yeah.
-PROBST: First things first,
-Tori, got to take it back.
-Okay.
-So weird. Yeah.
-Thank you.
Once again,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna balance
on a narrow perch while holding
a buoy between two handles.
If at any point
you fall off the perch
or your buoy drops,
you're out.
Last person left standing
wins immunity--
guaranteed a spot
in the final ten.
-Wow.
-PROBST: Losers, Tribal Council,
where somebody
will be voted out
and become
the first member of our jury.
The jury phase is
the next stage of the game.
It means
winning is a possibility--
which is why immunity
is so important at Tribal.
And yet, there are times
when you feel
"I actually don't think
I need it tonight."
(sighs)
PROBST:
If that is the case,
and you're willing to give up
your shot at immunity,
you can trade it for
an individual portion of rice.
(oohing)
PROBST:
Or...
if enough of you are willing
to give up immunity as a group,
enough rice for
everybody for four days.
-DREA: Aw.
-PROBST: And if you
ration it properly,
it'll last a lot longer.
How many people have
to step out for the big bag?
Well, this is a negotiation.
What are you putting up?
Two.
Two people
for rice for everybody,
-for four days?
-You said start the negotiation.
You said negotiate.
All right. Nine.
-Nine?
-No.
-CHANELLE: It's a nonstarter.
-It's a nonstarter.
-OMAR: Four.
So is two.
-Two.
-Three.
-Four.
Here's why I think six
is a fair number.
-(sighs)
-PROBST: Just hear me out.
Six is a fair number because
it is more than half the tribe.
(scoffs)
-Who wants to sit out,
first of all?
-I'll sit out.
Nobody wants to, but I will
for rice, 'cause I need to eat.
So there's two--
Lindsay and Drea.
MIKE:
I'm not sitting out.
I came here to play,
and so I want to play.
Why don't we do five?
No, look, five. Let's go four.
-Well, okay, meet us at four.
-MIKE: Meet us at four.
Who are the four?
I know I'm not good
at this challenge,
-and I know there's
a bunch of people here...
-I could be one.
-...who have not eaten.
-MIKE: All right, we got,
-we got three.
-JONATHAN: That's three.
-PROBST: There's three.
-MIKE: One more.
PROBST:
One more, and we got a deal.
-I'll take four.
-JONATHAN: Take four.
(sighs)
-Come on, guys.
-MIKE: Let's h...
Hey, guys, get in the middle
here. Let's get in the middle.
Like, I obviously,
I want to compete.
Like, I want to compete,
but the thing is, like,
we all need food.
And it's like, I know that
there's some people here
who know that they're
in a better position than me.
So, like, it would mean so much,
if you know that you're
in that better position,
to go and, like,
sacrifice, 'cause it's, like,
I could be going home
because of this decision.
But to know that
I'm giving a chance
for you guys to move
forward, like, please.
Just, like, in your heart,
just do it, please.
Like, I'm begging you.
I'll do it.
-JONATHAN: All right, Omar.
-You'll sit out?
-MARYANNE: Thank you, Omar.
-MIKE: That's four.
We have four.
-Are you sure?
-(groaning)
MIKE:
Thank you. Omar.
You got my word.
MARYANNE:
Thanks, Omar.
I decided to go and sit out.
And, you know, I'm an emotional
person, and I'm tearing up,
I'm getting sad, and I'm really
trying to ramp it up--
making people feel bad
about trying to vote me out.
And hopefully,
I'll be able to see another day.
People say you can't
play this game with emotion,
but look at me,
using emotions as a weapon.
(laughs softly)
All right, Lindsay,
Maryanne, Drea, Omar,
-take a spot
on the sit-out bench.
-MIKE: Thank you.
PROBST:
Giving up your shot at immunity
-in exchange
for a big bag of rice...
-TORI: Thanks, guys.
...that will feed everybody
-for at least four days.
-MIKE: Thank you, Drea.
Could be longer
if you handle it well.
JONATHAN:
And I'm thankful for you guys.
Oh.
I'll make it up to you.
-(Drea chuckles)
-PROBST: All right,
everybody else,
we're gonna draw for spots.
We'll get started. Here we go.
Big day on Survivor.
All right, here we go.
Everybody get up on your beam.
That's the first part of this.
You're gonna balance
on that beam,
and I'm gonna count you in.
You're gonna put your handles
into the buoy and lift it off.
Here we go.
In three, two, one...
Everybody lift.
And this challenge is on.
And immediately
Hai is out and frustrated.
Everybody else
gets a good setup,
and we are going.
Hai is first out.
Lasted about a second.
-That happens.
-(Maryanne and Hai chuckle)
Jonathan with a nice recovery.
You have got to
concentrate in this challenge.
It will get you fast,
as it just did Rocksroy.
Mike is out, and we're
down to four very quickly.
-Romeo's out.
We're down to three.
-(groans)
PROBST:
Chanelle and Tori on one end.
Jonathan alone at the other end.
Tori won the first
individual immunity.
She would love it again tonight.
♪ ♪
Been up there ten minutes.
That is a long time
in this challenge.
It feels like hours,
and you are feeling it
right now.
Tori with a nice recovery.
Jonathan with a big,
big recovery.
Huge recovery. That is
tough to do on that beam.
Wow.
Chanelle, Tori, Jonathan,
one of you three
will be safe tonight at Tribal.
And it won't be Chanelle--
she drops.
And we're down to two.
We have a showdown
between Tori and Jonathan.
Jonathan with another nice save.
And he gets it back again.
Wow.
That was close.
Now it's Tori with
a little bit of a wobble.
Tori continues
to adjust those toes.
You got to
get it back in control.
That quivering is
a sign of imminent danger.
Oh.
PROBST:
Jonathan in trouble.
Can he get it back?
-He's trying.
He's still in it.
-DREA: Oh.
PROBST:
Jonathan's gonna drop out.
-Tori wins her second
individual immunity.
-MIKE: Nice job, guys.
-Great job. Oh, my God.
-PROBST: Back-to-back
in Survivor 42.
Well done.
Tori, great job.
Thank you.
Tori, come on over.
-(applause)
-Yes, Tori.
The second time in a row,
-the only person
to wear this necklace.
-(shudders)
-Thank you.
-Tori, safe again tonight
at Tribal Council--
guaranteed a spot
in the final ten.
(exclaims)
PROBST:
For the rest of you,
somebody voted out tonight,
become the first member
of the jury.
And for anybody considering
Shot in the Dark,
there will now be 12 scrolls.
-Two of them will be safe.
Same odds.
-Wow.
-One in six.
You don't have
to worry about that.
-Praise God.
-You are safe tonight.
And you can take
this back to the tribe.
-Yay.
-Great negotiation.
-MIKE: Great job.
PROBST:
You worked me down to four.
Everybody, grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
See you tonight
at Tribal Council.
Thank you, Jeff.
MARYANNE:
Thanks, Jeff.
Tori ends up winning
the challenge.
That pissed me off.
I really wanted Tori gone.
So now we have to figure out
who's going home.
It's between
Maryanne, Chanelle and Romeo.
And I've only known these people
for, like, a handful of days,
and if they've got to go,
they got to go.
(laughs)
♪ ♪
HAI:
I love Maryanne.
Her plea that she was
at the bottom,
and if she was willing
to sit out,
someone else should
take one for the team.
-JONATHAN: Well, who's hungry?
-MIKE: Thank you, guys.
HAI:
Fortunately, we got the rice.
And it was so necessary,
because I was desperate
at this point.
My body was running on fumes
and memories of food.
-Good job, Tori.
-Thank you.
-MIKE: Great job.
HAI:
Good for Tori,
because she was our main target.
And now that Tori is safe,
that leaves our options
for tonight's Tribal
as Chanelle, Romeo, Maryanne.
LINDSAY:
We need to eat. This is...
JONATHAN:
Do you want to go ahead
and start cooking some?
I'll help.
I'm gonna get some wood.
MIKE:
I'm gonna get some wood, too.
HAI:
However, Chanelle has proven
that she's not loyal
to me and Mike.
So Chanelle is our plan
going into Tribal tonight.
MIKE:
Everybody knows the plan, right?
It's Chanelle.
It's personal for me
with Chanelle.
-Chanelle.
-Okay, so then
I'll go with you guys.
You gave me your word. I-I'm...
-Look at me.
-Yeah.
-It's not you.
-Chanelle has been
truly, truly unloyal to me.
(indistinct chatter)
MIKE:
She voted for me
when she didn't have to.
So, bye-bye, Chanelle.
CHANELLE:
Okay.
-(clicks tongue)
-Chanelle is the actual vote.
However,
we told Chanelle to vote Romeo,
because if she has an idol,
or potentially plays
her Shot in the Dark,
our plan is screwed.
CHANELLE:
So I'm a little nervous.
However,
my initial reaction
is just play it cool.
Let targets emerge
on themselves.
I think when you start
pulling a bunch of people,
people notice, people start
to think you're scrambling.
So my plan tonight
is to vote Romeo.
ROCKSROY:
Maryanne, that was
very inspiring, what you said.
OTHERS:
Yeah.
ROMEO:
This new merged Kula Kula tribe
is the kumbaya tribe,
and they want to sit around
the fire
and tell campsite stories.
And usually, when you don't have
an immunity necklace
around your neck,
you are worried.
Chanelle's super calm,
super chill, very quiet.
Me, I'm starting to panic.
I'm seeing what's going on.
I was left out of last vote.
I was blindsided.
I could be blindsided today.
And I thought I had
alliances with Drea and Rocks,
but Drea doesn't
even look at me anymore.
She hasn't even talked to me.
I'm worried because
you and I haven't talked.
You don't even look at me.
DREA:
You are so paranoid right now.
I...
ROMEO:
I don't care how many
people tell me
they haven't heard my name,
or this person's going home.
I have to assume
that I could go home.
Um... Yeah.
So you have to...
-From whom?
-Uh, I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't know who said that,
but it's just...
There's talk going around
the campfire, I guess.
Tori's telling me
that you told her
that you heard
Chanelle, Maryanne and my name.
ROCKSROY:
Tori asked me
whose name have I heard.
And I said Maryanne
and your name.
Rocks told her that
he heard Maryanne, Chanelle,
and the only other name
he had ever heard was mine.
-Rocks told Tori that?
-Yeah.
I heard Maryanne
and, uh, Chanelle.
The outliers
think I'm an outsider,
but I'm well within
the majority group.
And because of that, I acquired
information
that's gonna be invaluable.
Romeo is so paranoid.
At this point, the vote
was supposed to be Chanelle.
Everybody was on the same page.
-We'll figure it out.
-Okay.
OMAR:
But Romeo has now
inserted himself as a target,
and he is gonna
play himself out of the game.
What the...?
What?
'Cause this is ridiculous.
HAI:
Within the last 30 minutes
before heading out to Tribal,
Romeo got a hint that his name
was being thrown around,
and he is stirring up chaos.
And when someone
is creating chaos,
that's hard for me
to control my environment.
And I don't like that.
Okay.
HAI:
I'm very confused
about Romeo's strategy,
because he is just
pulling people left and right,
having personal conversations.
And he was
genuinely safe tonight.
We need to go Romeo, because
I know we want Chanelle...
-No.
-HAI: Romeo is creating chaos.
-Romeo is dangerous.
-I told you.
-We need to get Romeo tonight.
-Yeah, he's been paranoid
like a bitch.
HAI:
We need six on Romeo.
I just told Jonathan, Omar,
you, me, Mike and Lindsay.
-That's six. Done.
-DREA: Okay.
MIKE:
Paranoia's a crazy thing.
Hai panicked
because he heard something
and wanted to change the plan.
But quite frankly,
there's nothing more that I want
is for Chanelle to go home.
I trusted her
the first three days we're here.
She immediately stabbed me back.
She's been playing everybody.
She plays me.
Where I come from,
she's a snake.
I'm sticking with the plan.
I don't care.
-Okay?
-Someone wants to change it?
No, no, no. I'm saying...
No, no.
Nobody's changing it. That's
what I'm trying to tell you.
-Nobody's changing anything.
-All right, because...
MIKE:
I'm not a brain surgeon.
I don't know calculus.
I don't... but I'm street-smart.
Are you voting Romeo now?
I'm asking you.
MIKE:
My social game
is really, really good.
We have... Rocksroy's
not changing his vote.
And it comes natural to me,
just like Jonathan's
strength and athletic ability
-comes natural to him.
-This is gonna mess up
our plans.
Of course.
So I'm gonna convince
my alliance
we can't change the plan
and that it's the right decision
for our core alliance
at this moment.
Because Rocksroy's
not gonna trust us.
It sounds like
he doesn't trust us now.
Chanelle's been calm all day.
Romeo's listening.
If he's willing to do that,
even though we gave him a name,
-I want him gone.
-MIKE: Good.
This is Survivor,
and you can only
go in as comfortable
as people make you feel.
So I'm gonna have butterflies,
I'm gonna be jittery.
Until I see
those first few votes read,
I'm gonna be
closing my eyes, saying,
"Please let it be Chanelle."
♪ ♪
All right.
Little rain at Tribal--
always good.
So, Jonathan,
first question I have,
was there any discussion
that the four people
that volunteered to sit out--
Maryanne, Omar, Lindsay
and Drea-- were off-limits?
Yeah, I made it clear
that I will not vote
any of you guys tonight,
because what they did
helped us a lot.
I already feel better, Mr. Jeff.
I feel like
I got some life back into me.
Wow. Tori, you are safe.
-Nobody can vote you out
with that necklace.
-True.
This is the second time you
could look back a little bit.
Was this different than
the last Tribal Council?
It-it of course is
a little different, but it feels
as people are really
wanting to go with the group.
Like, last Tribal,
I was not part of the group,
and that didn't feel good, and I
had this, and I have this again,
but I still want
to be part of the group.
So that's kind of
what I was feeling.
You just wanted to be in
on the note, whatever it was.
PROBST:
Romeo, how would you describe
what was going on at camp
this afternoon?
I think so far,
since, uh, Kula Kula was formed,
everybody seems to be
a unified group.
And the majority comes up with
"hey, this person,"
and everybody wants to be part
of the majority, like Tori said.
But what's gonna be
interesting is that
this can't last forever,
and it won't.
PROBST:
Hai, Romeo says
it's a unified group
and we all agree on
who to vote for.
-But then it isn't
a unified group.
-HAI: Yeah.
We all think
there's a unified group,
but obviously
someone's out of the group.
Several people
may be out of the group.
And I think it's
all based on perception.
If you're going around
being suspicious
and paranoid and
spreading this information,
you're more than
likely not in the group.
PROBST:
Drea, that's very interesting,
because what Hai is saying is,
"Yeah, we're voting
somebody out,
"but I'm more concerned about
"who I'm going to be
voting with in the future.
"From the standpoint of:
can I rely on you to be calm?
"You're talking too much.
Your tell is obvious."
DREA:
It's really scary because
you align yourself with people,
and what they do
can be detrimental
to your own personal game,
depending on
how they act around others.
And you can try to do
everything you can to save them,
but, you know,
we only met 16 days ago,
when you think about it.
So, it's like, I could
totally hear my mama saying,
"That ain't your family, Drea."
Chanelle, do you think
everybody here is equally good
at reading their own tell
and others?
No.
The answer is no,
because if everyone
was equally as good,
I think everyone would
be on the same page--
which we're not tonight.
And the reason I say
we're not tonight
is because someone's going home,
and someone probably
doesn't know it.
Or maybe
multiple people don't know.
PROBST:
And, Mike,
when you're back home,
is this part of your life,
having to read people?
Or is this something
you're having to sort of learn?
I take pride in reading people,
'cause the truth is,
there are a lot of
good liars in this world.
You don't know
who's lying or not.
To me, it's trust and gut,
and that is what you have to do.
You have to realize
they're giving those tells.
That's what it's all about
on Survivor.
PROBST:
So, Romeo, it sounds like it's
the beginning of a road trip.
And whoever this group is,
they're deciding we've got room
for this many people.
Who do we want
to take this road trip with
over these last days
of Survivor?
Yes, and the next coming days,
I think that will
become more apparent.
But right now
some people don't realize
that some of the other people,
even if they're not constantly
hanging out with someone
or talking to somebody,
doesn't mean that there's
not an alliance there.
PROBST:
So, Chanelle, if we go
with this car analogy,
when you open the car door,
and you decide to get in,
how confident are you
that you're in the right
automobile for tonight?
I hope I'm in the right
automobile for tonight,
but when you're
at Tribal Council,
and you don't have the necklace
that Tori has,
you can't
really ever be certain.
All you can do
is trust your gut.
MARYANNE:
And sometimes you're not even
in the car, right?
So the car has four seats,
and you're, like, the fifth,
and you're, like...
(grunting)
...at the back of the car.
And you don't want that.
You know? 'Cause that means
you chose the wrong car.
PROBST:
Lindsay, if you were
gonna be in this car,
do you want
to be behind the steering wheel?
Do you want to be passenger?
Do you want to be in the back?
Uh, I think that answer changes
throughout the game,
because there's times
that it's, like,
you want to be
in the driver's seat.
And then there's other times
you're like, "You know what?
-Passenger's fine."
We're still gonna get there.
-(Drea laughs)
I don't need to be
the one driving the whole time.
Might want to take a nap.
HAI:
Can I add in?
-Yeah.
-If you're
in the driver position,
you need to know when
to let someone else drive.
And if you don't know
how to let someone else drive,
you better be wearing
a seat belt.
Well, on that note...
(oohing)
PROBST:
I think it is time to vote.
-Wow.
-Hai, you're up.
♪ ♪
If anybody has
an advantage or an idol
and you want to play it, now
would be the time to do so.
♪ ♪
Okay, I'll read the votes.
First vote. Hai.
Romeo.
One vote Hai. One vote Romeo.
Chanelle. One vote Chanelle.
Romeo. That's two votes Romeo.
Chanelle.
Two votes Chanelle.
Two votes Romeo.
One vote Hai.
Romeo. Three votes Romeo.
Two votes Chanelle.
One vote Hai.
Chanelle.
We're tied again.
Three votes Chanelle.
Three votes Romeo.
One vote Hai.
Chanelle.
That's four votes Chanelle.
That's five votes Chanelle.
Eighth person voted out
of Survivor 42
and the first member
of our jury...
Chanelle.
Six. That's enough.
Need to bring me your torch.
♪ ♪
Love you, Chanelle.
-Mm-hmm.
-DREA: Bye, Chanelle.
-Bye, Chanelle.
-Sure.
MIKE:
Bye, Chanelle.
Chanelle, the tribe has spoken.
Time for you to go.
MARYANNE (whispering):
Wow.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp. Good night.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
MIKE:
The guys are coming together.
I'm in.
We're gonna leave
the dead bodies on the road.
Truly, you don't know that.
LINDSAY: He feels like
a top dog, and he's not
listening to me.
Today, two people
-will win immunity.
-Yeah.
Two people going home tonight.
ROMEO:
This is my worst nightmare.
Man, I should
have seen this coming.
I know when a vote is too easy
that that's never the case.
I think my biggest takeaway
was, like, I think I was
playing a little bit too lax,
when clearly the game was
just running full speed.
And so, this game was a lot
harder than-than I thought,
but, I mean,
at least I made jury,
and now I get to decide
who's going to win the game.
(roars)